Welcome to the complete guide to tensor flow for deep learning of Python.
My name is Jose Portsea and I'll be your instructor for this course.
I currently have over a quarter of a million students on me teaching various topics such as Python machine
learning data science finance and more.
I'm also a technical corporate trainer for Fortune 500 companies and this course will teach you how
to use Google's tensor framework to perform the latest cutting edge techniques in machine learning.
This course is based off the same deep learning material I've developed for some of the world's top
tech companies.
Let's give you a quick overview of the course curriculum.
We'll start off a brief crash course in the central Python data science library including some Peiffer
numerical processing Pandurs for data analysis that plotted for visualization utilizing sikat learn
for processing machine learning data sets.
Once we done with the crash course we'll focus on building an intuitive understanding of the basics
of neural that works including trance activation functions back propagation and more after those neural
network basics.
We'll explore how to unlock the full potential of deep learning with tensor flow.
In this course we cover a variety of ways.
We'll begin the course by understanding basic artificial neural networks such as densely connected networks
will learn how to use these for basic classification and regression tests afterwards we'll work on understanding
convolutional here that works eventually using them to solve complex image classification tasks that
will move on to creating recurrent neural networks including the latest topics in the field such as
long or short term memory units and gaitered recurrent recurrent that works you'll be able to analyze
sequences of data such as Time series will also cover other models such as the words of an algorithm
for word and beddings allowing us to map individual words to vectors and explore the relationships between
will cover how to use auto encoders perform unsupervised tasks that works this course even covers advanced
topics such as generative adversarial networks and how to use reinforcement learning algorithms.
The open AI will teach networks how to solve tasks such as playing video games of this course you'll
get clear video explanations for every topic including easy to understand slides to cover theoretical
aspects in an intuitive way and fully coded notebooks to easily reference the code shown in the course.
Not only do you get great technical content but you'll also get access to our online question and answer
forms and or chat room recone go for quick help and talk with thousands of other students.
Upon completion of this course you'll also get a certificate of completion that you can post on your
LinkedIn profile to show off to your colleagues and potential employers all of this comes with a 30
day money back guarantee so you can try the entire course risk free.
Check out the various other preview videos you can get a glimpse of everything we have inside the course.
Enroll today and we'll see you inside.