Hello everyone and welcome to the course overview lecture.
I have a quick favor to ask of you.
Please don't skip this lecture even if you've already taken one of my courses before.
This is just going to be a really useful quick lecture on where to find a lot of important things for
the course.
So welcome to the course.
I'm going to cover the best practices for taking this course where you can find the notes for this course.
How to ask questions to quickly get help and then a little bit of certification and then I'm also going
to talk about the curriculum for the course Ok far first best practices for the course are concerned.
Keep in mind that videos can be sped up up to speed.
They can also be slowed down so I tend to talk at a pretty steady pace.
So me personally I would actually probably speed up the videos the way I consume information.
But maybe if English isn't your first language or you want to slow things down you can also slow the
speed of the videos.
You can also check the video playback quality.
So there's a little gear setting.
If you notice the videos are blurry.
Are you having any trouble with them.
You can always up the quality.
All the videos are uploaded in 10 ADP.
Also you can use the curriculum tab to quickly navigate between lectures and if you have any other problems
with the platform maybe the videos are taking too long or they're buffering.
You can always email a question to support you to me dot com and they they're happy to help you out.
Or you can submit a request directly at the U to me support page.
Again I only make the lectures and the notes and content.
I don't actually control the platform.
So for platform issues please go ahead and send an email to support UMT dot com.
Lot of great folks there and they're happy to help you out.
Two more quick notes.
As far as best practices for taking the course I would recommend you always watch the videos and reference
the notebook's tensor fluid deep learning can be quite a complicated subject.
So I tried my best to really clarify things during the videos and then you can always reference the
notebooks because the code itself is pretty complex.
So you want to make sure that the code you're writing matches the notebooks Exactly.
Also I recommend you always use the Course environment file with the provided notebooks and when I say
with the provided notebooks I don't just mean just copying and paste code from the notebooks.
Try running the notebook files directly.
It's really really easy to make a typo and a lot of this code goes for many lines and it's quite complicated
because it's a pretty complex topic so the notes are there for you so you can always reference them.
OK so speaking of the notes where can you find them.
Well the notebooks and all the data files we use are available as a large zip file and it's a resource
link in this lecture.
It's also available for you in the very next lecture as a resource link.
It's the same file so whichever one you want go ahead and download it.
It's a pretty large zip file because it includes some larger data sets so it may take a little bit of
time to download.
As far as the slides that you're going to see throughout the course these are all Google slides and
they're linked to in the first lecture of their respective section.
So what I mean by that.
If you're looking for the slides for the convolutional in your own networks section you just go to that
sections first lecture and you should see as a resource link the link to the Google slides.
Again why you're watching this video.
You should see like a little blue or some sort of pop up a little link and it should take you to the
resources Okay now how to ask questions and quickly get help.
During the course.
So the first thing you should do is verify that you ran the provided notebook file from that zip file
and you did it inside the provided environment file that we'll talk about during the installation lecture.
All the Knope the code has been checked against this provided environment file so it should all run
if you're running that exact notebook in the environment file with no other edits.
So keep that in mind if you're getting any syntax errors.
It's probably because you copied and pasted something wrong or you have a small typo or you're not running
it in the provided environment.
So always make sure that you're doing that.
All right so let's quickly go over some steps for getting answers to your questions in a quick and reliable
manner.
The first thing I would always suggest is that you check that you actually ran the notebook and that
you also check the videos.
A lot of times the videos I make some comments trying to preemptively answer questions that I may think
arise.
So if you're concerned about a particular section of the notebook go ahead and see if you can find that
in the video.
When I go over that I usually make some comments about it.
If not what I would recommend doing is just a quick Google search of whatever area are getting or whatever
question you have.
There's usually lots of useful pre asked questions on stack overflow that will cover the same topics
or same errors that you're experiencing.
And that way you can answer your questions in just a few seconds through a quick Google search.
So again with such a complex topic Google is your friend and stack overflow is a great resource and
I highly recommend that the first thing you do whenever you have a question is just do a quick Google
search or do a search on stack overflow.
OK let's say you still can't find your answer.
Well you can always search the Frequently Asked Questions lexer.
That's the very next lecture.
Now those are just general questions.
They usually have to do more if the course or getting certified or where you can find the notes that
sort of thing.
Or maybe even the installation process.
If you have a question that's more specific to maybe how a line in the notebook works and you didn't
get your answer either through stack overflow or through the videos that I would recommend the search
previous question and answer post.
We're going to end up having thousands of students in this course and in the getter channel as well.
So you want to search those question answer forums to see if your questions are already answered there.
All right so let's say you tried all that you did a google search.
Try looking on stack overflow.
You search the Frequently Asked Questions lecture you search the Q&amp;A forums and still can't find an
answer.
No problem.
That's the point of the Q&amp;A forms.
So make sure that when you're posting to the Q&amp;A forums you include your main error or your main point
in confusion.
Try to make this as clear as possible.
And also it's really helpful if you link to resources or Stack Overflow links that you've already seen.
That way you don't accidentally just get a reply to a stack overflow link that you've already seen and
maybe they didn't understand.
I would also really recommend that if you're stuck on a particular point in the lecture that you include
a video time stamp.
So let's say minute 12 of lecture 45.
That way we know what you're referencing and if necessary include a screenshot.
If your errors are pretty strange or it's more of a visual thing that's hard to describe screenshots
really help out a lot.
If you have a particular installation issue make sure you include information about your operating system
and the particular procedure you followed OK.
Quick note on certification.
You can check out the resource link for the support page details.
Me has a support page that goes through the full details of how to get certified.
If you take the course and as a quick note if you have any issues with your certificate maybe it's taking
too long or you just want to change the name.
Go get an email support you to me that again they're happy to help you out.
I don't actually control anything about certification.
It's all done automatically through to me.
So support me dot com can always help and they're happy to answer any questions about your certification
OK.
Let's quickly describe the course curriculum right after this.
We're going to talk about the installation and setup of python and flow and your environment.
Then after that we're going to do a very quick overview of machine learning just a little quick refresher
so you can get your mindset ready for the course.
Then we have what we call a crash course section in that section of the course.
We're going to go over things like pi Panchos and sikat learn.
If you've already taken one of my courses such as the Python for data science and machine learning boot
camp you may already be familiar of those libraries so you don't actually need to do the crash course
in which case you can skip it completely.
Or if you want to make sure you understand.
Go ahead and check out the crash course exercises and the solutions.
Just so you can check your understanding.
Again that crash course.
A little bit optional depending on what your prior experiences with those libraries.
OK so you did the crash course then we're going to move on to an introduction to neural networks.
So in that section of the Course we actually don't touch tensor flow.
Well we end up doing as we go through the very basics of neural networks.
We have a very shallow learning curve there.
I don't want to just like rev up the engines and then have you be lost at the very first sight of a
neural network.
So instead what we do is we have a very slow general introduction to neural networks and then what's
really cool is we manually create a neural network framework using python that sort of mimics the tensor
flow framework.
So actually in that intersection we don't touch tensor flow.
Instead we try to build out a little copy of tensor flow manually that way once we actually reach sensor
flow you have a full and complete understanding.
After that section is complete we then have what I refer to as the tensor flow sections.
And these are the sections of the course that really tackle a particular network topic and show you
how you can work with tensor flow.
So they typically include a theory lecture then an implementation example intenser flow and then some
sort of exercise free to follow intenser flow.
So those are all going to be dependent on whatever topic we're discussing so you'll have a tensor flow
section on recurrent and that works convolutional neural networks auto encoders etc..
Everything we talked about in the previous video and last but not least I just want to give a HUGE THANK
YOU to all the students who have rolled not just in this course but all my courses it really means a
lot to me and I'm so grateful to have the opportunity to teach you.
All right.
So without any further ado let's go continue on with the rest of the course.