Welcome everyone to this lecture on the basics of an auto encoder the auto encoder is actually a very
simple neural network and it's going to feel pretty similar to the multi-layer preceptress models we
saw in the very beginning of the course and it's designed to reproduce this input at the output layer.
So that idea of reproducing your input at the output layer causes a key difference between an auto encoder
and a typical multilayer perception model network and that's because the number of input neurons is
equal to the number of output neurons versus previously we were seeing models that had maybe a lot of
input neurons maybe one for every pixel in a picture and then the actual output neurons were just 10
such as a one output neuron for each class.
But in this case for the auto encoder we're actually going to have the number of input neurons equal
to the number of output neurons.
So let's explore what this looks like in a diagram and why we would actually use it.
So this is a diagram of a simple auto encoder and you can see here it's actually stacked so there's
more than one hidden layer.
There's three hidden layers here.
And the important thing to note here is what's happening over on the left hand side with these inputs.
We have five input neurons and then that gets reduced to three neurons in the next hidden layer the
two neurons in that center hit the layer.
Then it gets gradually increased until the output layer again has the same number of neurons as the
input layer.
So we're going to do is we're going to walk through the layers and explain the basic idea of an auto
encoder and to simplify this even further we're just going to have one single hidden layer.
And this is a very simple basic auto encoder.
The other one we just saw with more hidden layers is known as a stacked auto encoder.
And we'll explore that later on in a future lecture.
But now let's just go ahead and try to get the most simple auto encoder possible.
So in order simplify this further we're just going to have this diagram here where we have inputs that
hidden layer and outputs.
And keep in mind when we talk about these layers we're just talking about these actual neurons here.
So we have an input layer of five neurons that goes to a hidden layer which is smaller than the input
layer and then it gets expanded back out to our player which has the exact same number of neurons as
that input layer.
So that's what we're modeling here.
And keep in mind it's just a feedforward network that's trained to reproduce it's input at the output
layer.
So all these auto encoders trying to do is directly mimic its input at the output layer.
So that means the output size is the same as the input layer.
So what does it look like mathematically Well let's say we have inputs X and then that gets fed into
some hidden layer.
So we have that result B H of x so hidden takes an X and then we have a biased term in the hidden layer
along some weights attached to the inputs going into the hidden layer.
And then from that hidden layer we have another set of weights going out and then another set of biased
terms which we can call see.
So the space is just moving along the alphabet.
All right.
So there's two main parts to an auto encoder and that is the first part the encoder and the second part
the decoder.
So let's start from the bottom and work our way to the top.
So at the bottom here we have the inputs.
So we have some input and we'll call that input X and then we're going to do the exact same process
we did back when we're dealing with the very basic neural network models.
We just take her input X we're gonna multiply it by some weights and at a biased term we'll just call
that a linear transformation and then we can pass that through some sort of activation function such
as a sigmoid activation function or many other activation functions that we talked about.
But keep things simple We'll just keep the sigmoid.
And then that results in that hit layer.
So again the hidden layer is just taking in the inputs and applying that linear transformation and then
passing it through an activation function.
And that's the first half of going from the input to that sensor hidden layer that's called the encoder
and then that second half is the decoder.
So what it does is it takes the result of that hidden layer we'll call it a bunch of Acts.
Multiply it by another set of weights w out and then again applies a linear transformation with its
own biased terms that see.
And then we can pass it through an activation function and then we get back what we call X hat or X
bar and that X bar is basically this auto encoders reproduction of the inputs.
Now a really common practice when dealing with auto encoders since you're trying to basically reproduce
your input at the output.
Often you will tire weights.
So all that means is that your weights from the input to the hidden layer are going to be the same as
your weight's coming from out of the Hilarie to your outputs.
So all you end up doing you see your weights coming out is equal to the transpose weights coming in
and we'll show you how to do that later on with their actual code.
It's actually quite easy of tensor flow but keep in mind if you ever reading a paper about encoders
and they say they're using tight weights that's all that means that we're actually not figuring out
another set of weights at the output.
Instead we're just tying that to the set of weights that's being figured out from the input to the hidden
layer.
Now keep in mind you're not going to tie the biased terms together.
Those are going to be separate.
All you're tying are the weights.
So the key idea here is really occurring at that hidden layer so that hidden layer is typically going
to be smaller than the inputs and that's called an under complete auto encoder.
Technically you can also have that hidden layer be larger the inputs but that's called an over complete
autem coder.
And we're not going to focus on that right now.
Instead we'll focus on the typical auto encoder structure which has a smaller number of neurons in that
hidden layer.
So again that's called an under complete auto encoder because we have less neurons in that hidden layer.
And the idea is if you're taking a bunch of inputs and then having to reduce them to that smaller hidden
layer that hidden layer is going to have some sort of internal representation that tries its best to
maintain all the information of the input.
However it has less neurons to do it with.
Now the really interesting aspect of this hidden layer and a big part of using auto encoders is that
we can use this hidden layer to extract meaningful features.
And we'll also explore later on in the next lecture how we can use principal component analysis with
auto encoders.
But the main idea here being that if we have a large number of input neurons and then we essentially
force them to go down into a smaller number of hidden neurons and then ask for the representation back
at the outputs.
Then what we're doing is we're training this hidden layer to try to get some sort of compressed representation
of our input data and you can easily imagine that if you think back to the original diagram you're taking
something like 10 inputs and then feeding it into a hidden layer of only two neurons than those two
neurons are going to have to try their best to figure out how they can essentially compress that information
of ten features into just two using some sort of combination of all those features multiplied by those
weights.
And then with those biased terms.
So again you can kind of think about this almost as a compression capability.
So later on we're going explore stacked auto scooters with more hidden layers so it's not just a quick
jump from the inputs all the way to a small hidden layer so that's known as a stack of encoder and we'll
explore that in a future lecture for now you should understand a very basic auto encoder.
Again the principle is really simple you just have the encoder going from that number of input neurons
to the hidden layer and then you have the decoder go in from the hidden layer that the output where
the input neurons equals the same amount as the output neurons and all the auto code is trying to do
is get some sort of reproduction of its input at its output.
And through that process you end up training that hidden layer to try to compress the information available
from the input.
So up next we're going to discuss a little more about this compression and dimensionality reduction
by exploring how we can use auto encoders to basically mimic principal component analysis.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.