Welcome everyone to this lecture Well we show you how we can perform them and anality reduction with
a linear auto encoder linear auto encoders can be used to perform what's known as a principal component
analysis basically allowing us to reduce the dimensionality of our data.
Dimensionality reduction allows us to get a lower mentioned representation of our data and the encoder.
Half of the auto encoder creates new and fewer features from the input features.
So for example we can take a three dimensional dataset an output a two dimensional representation of
it.
So we have an input layer with three neurons and a hidden layer of just two neurons.
Now keep in mind we're not just simply choosing two of the original three features but instead we're
constructing two new features from combinations of the original three and using those combinations we
can then reduce the actual damage anality of the original data set and we achieve this effect by using
a linear auto encoder and a linear auto encoders perform the linear transformations by only using the
weights and biased terms.
We actually don't use activation function.
So essentially we have an auto encoder that looks like this.
It's the exact same thing that we saw earlier in the previous lecture just know that we're not passing
an activation function anymore.
We're just using the linear transformation of the input and the hidden output.
Now after training what we do is we use the hidden layer to obtain a reduced dimensionality.
So let's go ahead and code this out to see how it works.
If you want more substantial mathematical proof of why the linear auto encoder can perform this principle
component analysis go ahead and check out the resource links.
Some of the geometric notation is a little bit outside the scope of this course but you can go ahead
and check out the link in case you want full mathematical proof of why this works.
But let's not jump to the Jupiter note book and actually implement this.
All right so here I am at a Jupiter notebook and the first thing I want to start off by doing is a couple
of imports will Important them pie and then I also want to do a little bit of visualization.
So we'll import matplotlib that pipeline as Piazzi as.
And then I also need to indicate that live in line since I'm using the Jupiter notebook.
So now I'm going to show you how we can easily create some data sets so you can say from S-K learn dot
datasets import.
And this is a really nice make Blob's functionality and make Blob's what it does is it basically creates
classification data sets for you so you can say data is equal to and then call make Blob's.
And if you do shift type here you can see what it actually does.
It takes in the number of samples you want the number of features you want how many centers basically
how many classes you want and then the cluster standard deviation so the standard deviation between
these actual clusters and then you can also specify other things such as the random state.
So I'm going to create a very simple example will say we'll have 100 samples.
So that is 100 rows of data.
The number of features we want is going to be three features.
So we're basically creating a three dimensional data set.
And this is the data set we're going to try to reduce into to them and Chinse and then we'll say centers.
Just too.
So this is going to be basically two blobs or two classes.
And then here's the important part.
Make sure you have the same random state as me.
Otherwise you'll get different data set.
So that basically sets were in them seed.
OK so now that we have our data if we take a look at what type is actually return it's a tuple.
And if you print all the data you end up seeing something like this.
So you have a large array.
Those are all your values so here's 100 samples with three features.
Those are the columns and then you scroll all the way down you end up seeing the actual classes they
belong to.
Now keep in mind we're not actually performing any sort of classification task right now but the reason
I like having these classes for walking you through PCa or it dimensionality reduction is because it
makes it really clear that you're still able to retain a lot of information.
And so what I mean by that is the following.
So first off let's actually grab some of this data.
So if we say data of 0 then this is just our actual data.
If we say Data 1 then these are our labels.
So we pass this in we're going to need to do some scaling which means we'll say from Escuela and pre-processing
import that min max scaler were already familiar with I will say scaler minimax scaler and then we'll
report back scaled data is equal to scaler transform
and notice here.
I'm going to just transform my entire dataset.
That's because we're doing what is essentially an unsupervised task.
So I don't really care about any sort of train split.
I'm just going to take all my data that's three dimensional and try to convert it into two dimensions.
So do a dimensionality reduction.
But before I do that I need actually scale it sonand I have my data that's scaled and I'm going to basically
plot it out for you.
So let's grab it feature by feature.
We'll say scaled data all the rows in the zero column I will say that's data X and then we'll do this
three more times.
Except for the other two columns.
So what I'm doing here is I'm just grabbing the columns and then set in them as variables data x y and
z so I scaled my data and I grab the three individual columns.
And now what I can do is I can plot them in three dimensions.
So the way we do that with MAP plot lib you say from NPL underscore toolkits dots and plot three the
import axes 3D and this allows you to create some kind of rudimentary three dimensional plot and the
way you do this is if you say fig peel.
See that figure.
So you create a figure object and then you get an access to this.
And the worry about understand this too much because this is really just for the visualization of the
problem it's not a huge part of this course you passing one on one to basically in the case that you're
just doing one plot at the very first grade and then you need to specify a projection is equal to 3D.
So if you run that you get this kind of 3D looking plot.
Keep in mind map plot lib is not specifically designed to be a super great three dimensional visualization
library.
It does have a lot of useful tools for you but if you're really interested in a three dimensional plotting
with Python I was just going for interactive library like Bocca or plot.
Lee again we don't really cover these topics in this course because it's not a visualisation course
but I just want to keep that in mind.
This is not Matt Hotlips greatest strength but it does have the capabilities for it.
So the reason that I want to show you this is because this is what we're going to plot on.
So on this axis I'm then going to say X and call a scatterplot on it just like you would normally say
appeal to scatter.
Except now what's special about it is I can define X Y and Z which means I'll just pasan those columns
of data
OK.
There we have it.
So now I can see my two blobs in three dimensional space.
So clearly when I plotted out in three dimensions they're very separable and you could basically put
in you can imagine like a theoretical piece of paper somewhere here and easily separate those two classes.
And we can actually pass in a third argument or a fourth argument really see and then say this is data
one those labels and then I can color it.
And now we're going to attempt to basically answer is given that we have three dimensions worth of data
and with three dimensions I can clearly see that this data is highly separable.
The two blobs are completely separate.
If I try to use a linear auto encoder to reduce these three dimensions to just two them mentions will
I still have that same level of separation and it should be obvious because I will plot it out just
on two axes and then see if I color them by their specific labels.
If I still get that same separation or if by reducing through them inches into to them inches now I
have quite a bit of.
So to speak cross-contamination.
Let's go ahead and explore this idea and see if we can successfully reduce these three dimensions of
data by using combinations for linear auto encoder into to them engines of data.
Again just to be very clear I'm not just throwing away one column and then having two columns.
I'm going to try to make two new dimensions out of these three old ones and that's where the linear
auto encoder comes into play.
So let's go ahead and do this.
We'll say sensor flow as T.F. and then we're going to be using a higher level a Pine-Sol say from Florida
courtroom the layers in poor.
And if hit tab here was being hit it's because I haven't imported it yet.
You should be able to say fully connected.
What's that.
Oh OK.
Now the tab shows up a little too late.
They can see here there's a bunch of letters that are already created for you.
The one we're going to be using is a very simple fully connected layer just like we saw in our diagrams
and now we're going to do is create a couple of variables we'll see the number of inputs is equal to
3 because we have three dimensions for data.
We'll have our hidden layer be equal to two mentions of data.
And then finally remember because we're using an auto encoder the number of outputs needs to be equal
to the number of inputs.
And while we're at it if we're defining constants we may as well define or learning rate.
Well go ahead and set this to 0.01 we don't have a lot of data so we don't have to learn that slowly.
Up next we're going to create a placeholder so there's only one placeholder because unsupervised hask
we're not dealing with any labels.
So I'll say placeholder to float 32.
And the shape is going to be defined by whatever a batch size we feed so none.
And then by the number of them puts and then let's go ahead and create our layers using this contrib
layers.
So we'll say it in is equal to a fully connected layer and a fully connected layer needs some inputs
number of outputs and activation function and it can take more than that.
But we're going to pass an X as the input the output is going to be the number of hidden units and then
we have our activation function and this is where we're actually going to say none.
Because remember with that linear auto encoder just as we showed in the slides we are actually passing
this with an activation function that we have or outputs layer.
And again this is going to be fully connected layer and that's going to take in that hidden layer.
It's going to have the number of outputs it's going to spit it back out to three and then again no activation
function.
So all this is trying to do is successfully reproduce the input at the output but there's a step in
between where it reduces the number of dimensions OK.
Now we have hidden and outputs.
So let's do the rest of it.
We need the last function here will say loss is equal to T.F. reduce mean.
This is just a mean square air T.F. square and then we'll say let's make sure it's all square right.
And we'll say the outputs minus X because remember X is the actual input and then finally we need an
optimizer will say optimizer is equal to T.F. train and we'll use an atom optimizer and I will specify
some learning rate.
And they will say train is equal to optimizer and we're trying to minimize that loss function
OK.
Almost there except we need to initialize a variable so say if global variables initialiser.
Now it's time to actually run the session and see if we're able to successfully reduce this from three
dimensions into two them mentions and still retain information and we'll say will basically clarify
that we retain the information if we can still see that these two classes are highly separable Let's
go ahead and run this for a thousand steps we'll say with T.F. session.
As s s s say SPSS run that initialiser first and then we're going to do the following.
We'll say for iteration in the number of steps we're taking.
So 1000 steps we're going to run train and then pass in our feet dictionary surfie dictionary is just
going to be X and we're going to pass in the scale data from before.
So that's all three dimensions the features.
And then once that's done training I'm going to do the following.
I'm going to say my to that mentioner output is equal to the hidden layer.
And then I'm going to evaluate the same feed dictionary.
So I'll say feed dictionary X skilled data.
So let's explain what we're actually doing here.
I'm going to train my auto encoder for 1000 steps and I need to keep passing that scale data and this
auto encoder all is trying to do is it takes and the inputs shrinks them down to just two neurons and
then expands them back out to three and then the way it's actually being optimized is by trying to make
sure its outputs match the inputs as closely as possible.
And the challenges this hidden layer has to reduce from three dimensions into two them engines.
Now given this actual data set it's not a very hard task.
You could see that they were highly separable and the stonecutter is going to perform very well as you'll
see in just a second.
But keep in mind we'll still be able to apply the same practice for something with 30 dimensions and
maybe reduce it down to three dimensions but all we're doing is trying to get that input passers through
the hidden them put it through the outputs see how far we are from the outputs the original data source
and then once we've done that through our training we're going to do is after these 1000 training steps.
Notice this is outside the for loop.
I'm going to say hey now taken my skill data and only pass it through that hidden layer.
That way I get to them and output backout.
And if you want to you could perform this in a separate session so it'll show how it looks in just a
second.
So I just ran that for a thousand training steps.
It should be pretty fast.
And now I have output to the end if you take a look at it and it's now the two that mentioned all representation
of our original scale data source.
So let's go ahead and plot this out.
We'll say t scatter and I'm going to plot out the first column of data versus the second column of data.
And we plot that out.
We get two blobs.
Now we still don't know whether we're separating these versus.
Let's go and add a little bit of color in and hopefully these to match up with their respective classes.
And now we can see that we were successfully able to reduce the number of mentions from three mentions
to two that mentions the challenge in this interpretation of the results comes from trying to understand
what these new dimensions actually represent.
And unfortunately you can't just directly say hey this x axis relates to the first feature in our original
dataset.
There is definitely some relationship there but it's hard to interpret because it depends on the actual
weights of that hidden layer in a simple auto encoder.
You could definitely go back and actually look at the weights and see that hey maybe it's 60 percent
a feature 1 30 percent a feature to 20 percent feature three etc..
But as we get larger and larger with our inputs that interpretation is going to become harder and harder
and then especially when we get to stack auto encoders where we don't just have one hidden layer is
that we have multiple hidden layers actually interpreting the combinations is essentially going to be
like a black box.
You're not going to directly interpret that.
Keep in mind that's also a challenge which is normal principal component analysis.
So you're not really sacrificing interpretability in that sense by using a linear auto encoder.
So keep that in mind.
That's a normal principal component and also still suffers from that same interpretation problem that
it's hard to just get an intuitive sense of what access won here and access to represents.
However the most important part is we can clearly see even on a visual stance it still works.
We were able to successfully reduce the number of dimensions in this dataset and still retain information
or we're finding information as the separation of classes here.
OK.
So up next you're going to be running this same exercise except you're going to be doing it on a set
of data that has 30 dimensions or features and hopefully you'll be able to see that even with 30 dimensions
you'll be able to successfully reduce it back down to just two them engines and retain that super ability
of data.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture where we'll cover over the exercise.