Welcome everyone to this lecture we're going to go over the exercise we're going to perform them and
anality reduction with a linear audio encoder.
Let's walk through Jupiter notebook and see if we have to do.
All right so here we are at the linear auto encoder for PC exercise and for this what you're going to
end up doing is basically very similar to what we just did in the lecture where you going to do just
follow along here get the data and the data is this anonymize data.
C s v file and it's included underneath the auto encoder folder.
And then notice that it's basically just a bunch of columns that have anonymised column names so just
for letters and then there are some values and each of the columns and if you go all the way to the
right you also have a label column.
Now remember we're not doing any sort of classification task we're just using that label to see if we
can maintain that class separation even if we reduced down to just two mentions.
Believe it or not you're going to take this 30 of them internal data set and you're going to reduce
down to two that mentions and you'll be able to clearly see that the cluster are still separated.
So you'll scroll down here you'll skil the data and then build that the linear auto encoder and a lot
of these steps match very closely to what we did in the lectures.
You can always check the lecture for more details of the placeholder layers loss function optimizer
then you'll go ahead and run your session and hopefully at the end you still see that even with just
to them mentions this theory then mentionable original data set will reduce down to two mentions with
the linear auto encoder.
The auto encoders hidden layer has learned enough of the real combination of features to create two
new feature planes that allow it to still maintain class severability with just two mentions worth of
data.
OK.
Best of luck on this and I'll see you at the next lecture where we go through the solutions.