Welcome back everyone.
The solutions lecture for the dimensionality reduction exercise for linear audio and encoders.
Let's go to the Jupiter notebook and walk through the solutions.
OK so here we are at the notebook.
We'll start off with our imports will the numb pie and then we're also going to use pandas to read and
to see as we file.
And then finally we're going to import map plot lived that pipe plot as PLDT and then we'll say map
plot live in line OK.
First things first we need to actually get our data will say DMF or whatever you want to call your data
frame is equal to read CXXVIII.
And since I'm already located in the auto encoder folder there's going to tab autocomplete for that
CSP dataset.
And if you take a look at the head of it it's going to look something like this.
Basically you have these 30 columns of data and if you go all the way to the right you have that label
column and the hope here that's just the result of calling info.
It's another way of seeing general information but your data frame specifically about each of the columns
so we can see here they're all basically the same thing just five hundred entries of numbers and all
the way down and we have that label column.
Now we want to scale the data.
An important thing to note here when we're scaling data is we're not doing any sort of train test but
because this is unsupervised learning.
We just really care about the features we'll say from a scalar and pre-processing import and will improve
the minimax scaler will create an instance of a min max scaler and then we'll finally say our scale
data is equal to scaler.
And again we'll just call it transform on our entire features dataset.
So we'll say the drop the label and say x is equal to 1 OK.
Now we have our scale data.
So those are just the features.
Up next we want to actually begin to build out a real linear auto encoder which means we're going to
import sensor flow as T.F. then the next thing we're going to import is that fully connected layer will
say from tensor flow contrib layers and poor fully connected OK then we're going to fill out the number
of inputs to fit them mentions the data set.
So we have 30 features so that means we're going to have 30 inputs the number of hidden units in this
case we're going to reduce it down to two then mentions So we'll have that out there.
And then it is already set for us the learning rate you can kind of play around of this but we shouldn't
need a very high learning rate.
The fact of the matter is the state is highly separable even in 30 dimensions.
So we should be able to learn on it pretty fast.
Next we have the placeholder.
So we're just passing in our data will say x is equal to T.F. placeholder and then we'll say flow 32
and shape it's going to basically be defined by that batch size.
And then the number of inputs which is 30 features But next we're going to create some layers hidden
layer is equal to a fully connected layer.
So pass an X than the number of hidden units and then for this case we'll say activation function is
done.
And then the outputs are just going to be a fully connected layer.
And also a hidden number of outputs and then finally no activation function Let's go ahead and create
our last function that's going to be T.F. reduce mean use mean.
And then we're going to take the square.
So basically I mean square there
of the outputs minus X OK we ever mean squared error.
Let's create our optimizer will use an Adam Adam optimizer T.F. train call atom optimized for this person
the learning rate that we defined earlier and then say or trainer operation is just the optimizer trying
to minimize the loss.
Next we're going to create an instance of that global variable initialiser.
So we'll say it is equal to T.F. global variables initializer.
And then we actually create instance of it so we'll make sure we run that and then we actually want
to run the session.
So we're going to create a tensor for session that runs the optimizer for at least a thousand steps.
So you can use ebox if you prefer one ypocras just defined by one single run through the entire dataset.
Well St number of steps is equal to 1000.
Again you could have said something like just run it for two epochs.
Let's make sure that's not connected.
So we'll say it with a session as SPSS session run and it's and then it is safe for every iteration
in the range.
The number of steps we defined earlier thousand steps we're going to say session run train and then
our feed dictionary here is just going to be our scale data.
So we'll go ahead and run that should be pretty fast.
And now we want to create a session that calculates the scaled data going through that hidden layer.
So with T.F. session as SPSS and this is one of those instances where you might want to run a interactive
session with initialiser variables again and then say that the two the output is equal to that hidden
layer and then it evaluates given a dictionary X and then the scale data OK.
So we're going to confirm now that our output is actually the output we expected some to them actual
output.
So we'll check out the shape.
So now it has 500 entries but there's only two features so let's plot it out and see how well we did.
So we'll say Pulte scatter and we want to get output to the I will take.
Well let's just show you output to the it looks like.
So you can kind of get an idea I now have just two columns worth of data from the 30 columns.
So then in going I say grab all the rows in the first column and plot them against all the rows in the
second column.
Now if you just run that and you get something that looks like this where there's not very clear separation
and you can determine that by asking for the color will say color is just defined by that previous label
column.
So we see here they're not really well separated still.
What we can do is we'll come back up here and train it for a couple of more steps.
Let's go ahead and just say 2000 steps.
So we'll run these cells again evaluate again if that new model run the output and then let's run this
again.
So you can see we're getting better or better separation.
So let's run that for just let's say two overkilled or 5000 steps.
Hopefully it doesn't run forever.
Ok it looks like it ran pretty good.
And here we can see.
So now we going getting clear separation.
So if you don't get clear separation at the very beginning you may just have to run it for some more
steps.
Now if we scroll back up here at the instructions that call for a thousand steps that may again not
be enough for you.
So go ahead and just you know change it to some higher number Fermanagh and again at 1000 this time
you can see I kind of get lucky here and I do get that full separation.
So again the more steps you do the more likely you get a higher separation there.
If after many many thousands of steps you're still not getting separation.
Go ahead and run the solution is no book and double check that your all your codes actually matching
the solutions and the solutions.
No but those have a thousand steps as a number of steps there.
Go ahead and amp that up and then check again.
OK.
If you have any questions on this feel free to post that on the forums.
But hopefully it was pretty straightforward.
Thanks everyone and I will see at the next lecture.