Welcome everyone to this stacked couter lecture Let's go ahead and take a look at a stack of couter
operating on the digits dataset that will give us a really good opportunity to visualize how well the
reconstructions are coming out at the output layer.
Let's open a particular notebook and get started.
Okay right off the bat as always we start off with a couple of imports here.
We will be doing some plotting in order to visualize those numbers.
So I need to import that plot lib in line.
And of course we're gonna be using pi.
And then finally let me import tensor flow as T.F. and let's grab our digits data set.
So we'll say from tensor flow examples tutorials.
Just import the input data function that's input data.
So don't run that then the next thing I'm going to do is say this is equal to and we'll make sure this
doesn't work.
OK good.
And this data is equal to input data.
We're going to call read data sets.
And right now I'm located underneath the auto encoders folder.
So I need to grab the convolutional neural networks folder.
So I just have autocomplete that and then I also want to grab the data and I want it to be one high
end code.
So we'll say one hot equals true OK.
And you should only see extracting here if you did this properly.
If you begin to see that it's downloading.
That's totally OK if you want to wait for it to download.
But remember you already have the data set ready for you underneath the convolutional neural networks.
Up next we want to reset the default graph just in case to have some other notebooks running.
And let's get started.
OK so let's start creating the parameters for our stacked auto encoder.
We'll go ahead and design a pretty simple stacked auto encoder.
We're going to say we start off 784 inputs which is the result of 28 times 28.
Remember we have 28 28 pixels in the digits dataset.
Then for the next layer I'm going to go ahead and divide it by half.
Is kind of an arbitrary choice for my stack stonecutter but I kind of want to make it clear that we're
continually decreasing the number of neurons available and then for that sensor hidden layer I'll go
ahead and divide that in half again we'll say 186.
Now of course you could keep going to smaller and smaller encoding but instead we're going to begin
to expand that back out.
So we'll see 392 here again.
And then finally 784 remember we need to have the output match the input.
So let's set this up in terms of some variable names missing number of inputs is equal to 784 will say
neurons.
In fact lushest but the solid and useful that we don't get this kind of Misi commenting.
OK we're going to have number of inputs at 784.
I will say neurons in that first hidden layer.
So your odds underscore here in one is equal to 392 going to see neurons.
And the second hidden layer is equal to 186 than the number of neurons.
In my third hit in Alair.
Well that's going to be equal to the number of neurons in my first hit.
So that's where we begin to expand backout 392.
And then finally I will say the number of outputs is equal to the number of inputs.
Now keep in mind as you begin to reduce the number of neurons available in the hidden layer later on
when you visualize your reconstructions you may not get a clear reconstruction because you may have
sacrificed too much information by decreasing number of neurons too quickly or by too much.
And these are numbers you can definitely play around with and see how it affects your actual stack quarter
because you're actually built to visualize this at the very end.
We see the results.
So kind of a fun project here.
Finally a scribe are learning right because it's another constant we have to provide.
So we'll see 0.01 and I'm going to say that my activation function is equal to T.F. But again rectified
linear unit.
And the reason I find the right now is a variable is that way I can just call this shorter variable
name instead of having haven't call this all the time.
All right.
Now it's time to actually begin setting up everything we need for our session and our Grath.
The first thing we need is a placeholder and we don't need a placeholder for our relabelled since this
is unsupervised learning.
So now that I'm just having a placeholder for X that's going to be to float 32 and the shape is going
to be pretty simple just none which is going to be based off the bat size.
And then the number of inputs which is the number of pixels OK so repassing and 784 pixels for each
image in that batch.
And then let's go ahead and set up our weights so I can say initialiser is equal to.
And I can tell you something we haven't seen before which is T.F. variance scaling initialiser and I'm
going to run that and then talk a little bit about it.
If we scroll back up here we realize that we're going to have to build the weights for our inputs are
hidden layer 1 in our hidden layer 2 and then back out again.
And when you're constructing and initializing these weights typically will be done in the past just
grab from some sort of Renn distribution or maybe even set them all to start off it's ones or zeros.
But there's going to be a problem that occurs in the fact that the scale of these weight tensors is
quite different because we're dividing it in half each time.
And what T.F. variance scaling initialiser allows us to do is basically as a name says it's an initialiser
that's capable of adapting its scale to the shape of the weight sensors and there are parameters you
can do here.
But basically it's going to if you do shift help here have some basic scaling.
So at one point zero and it's going to scale it's the size of the tensors.
So because here it's going to adapt its initialization based on the distribution that it chooses.
Distribution normal to the shape of the weight tensors and that's going to allow us to have much better
training because we're going to initialize it based off a distribution that's based off the size of
these hidden layers.
So that's going to create a much better training than if you just initialized it with random weights
across the board because of the size difference in these weight sensors.
So that's usually a necessity when you're dealing with auto encoders especially if you start to do a
really quick shift in the size of the hidden layers.
So let's show you how we can use this guy to actually quite easy and then create some weights variables.
So just as we then in the past we're going to say T.F. variable and then we're going to initialize it.
Previously we did things like T.F. zeros or T.F. ones or T.F. you know truncated normal those kind of
things.
But what I'm going to do now is just call the initialiser object they just created and then passed in
the shape so it's expecting Here's the shape.
So it's going to be not quite simple.
The first weight needs to be the number of inputs and then the output is going to be neurons hit one
and then when you can also tell it what data type is going to be for the variable and the data type.
So the type is equal to T.F. flute 32.
OK so let's copy and paste this because we need a couple of more sets of weights and then let's change
and edit what we need to.
So we have the first set of weights for the input layer.
Second set of weights for that first layer.
Third set of weights for that next hidden layer and force that awaits there.
So let's see what happens here.
We have a number of inputs two neurons hit and one that means neurons hit and one is going to be the
next set and the weights are which means you're get into coming up next they're And then that means
you're on hit into is coming over here.
And then you're on student 3 coming over there which means you're on student 3 going to come here.
And then finally we're going to have our outputs.
So outputs.
All right.
Let's make sure I didn't actually have a typo.
So neurons hit three not define.
Make sure I find that appear neurons high theory.
OK.
Let's run that again.
Okay perfect.
So save that and now we're going to do the same thing but offer our biased terms now are biases.
Those still have to be as strict as the weights we can just start those off as ones or zeroes.
Basically up to you.
Well go ahead.
Because when I was running earlier that tended to give a little bit of some cleaner results.
So I'll say T.F. zeros and that's going to be defined here by the output.
So neurons hit one going to copy this and then paste it four more times for each of those weights.
So we have to be three before zeros menow now need to say it and Lerer to hit only three in the last
decade is going to be the output tools and numb outputs.
OK so we have our weights our biases and we have our activation function defined appear as a CTF.
So we'll keep that and in the notes actually redefined as LCT underscore phunk just to make it a little
more readable.
So I'll go ahead to do the same thing here.
We match exactly the notes but again serving the same purposes like that up there.
Except now I think it's a little more readable than actif.
OK so our activation phunk Let's go ahead and create our hidden layers.
So our hidden layer one is going to be equal to the activation function we chose and then we're going
to say just T.F. matrix multiplication of our placeholder by those weights and then we add in our bias
term Sofala is feels really familiar from the very first lectures covering tensor flow basically doing
the classic neural network design of multiplying your input your weights adding some biased term and
then passing it through an activation function.
We're going to need to do this a couple of more times though let's copy paste here.
So after a hit or one as you may have guessed is hidden there too.
Same deal we're going to say T.F. Mitchell to cation except instead of passing x now we're passing and
the result of Hitler 1 times waits to plus Bice's do and similar thing for that next it.
Doodler 3.
Instead of saying Hit it layer 1 we're going to see him later to
and then this is going to be the third way Tobias's.
And this is actually the upper layers let's call it up layer and this is going to be hidden layer 3
Hitler 3 hopefully and how it's PayPal's there and then for Byass for OK.
And now it's time to find the last function.
We'll just go ahead and say T.F. reduce mean T.F. square of the output layer basically the predictions
minus the results.
OK.
And this is not really in essence a prediction it's more like how good of a representation are we able
to create based off the original data.
So just the mean square error here.
And then we're going to pick an optimizer.
We're going to use the atom optimizer for this.
Say T.F. train atom optimizer and then going to pass in the learning rate that we decided earlier on
which was I believe 0.01 find my training operation as just the optimizer attempting to minimize our
loss function.
Let's go ahead and initialize the variables.
Hopefully this all feels pretty familiar right now.
There's a T.F. global variables initialiser and run that.
OK.
So we basically have everything ready to go.
All we have next is to actually run our session and then test out the output.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
We're almost done here actually.
I'm going to be saving this in order to get on the train data or testator's Well we'll say T.F. train
Savir.
OK so let's actually start constructing our session.
We'll go ahead and run it through five e POCs and we'll fit in in batch sizes of 150 where each IPAC
is going to be an entire run through all your training data and the batch sizes just how large of batches
you're feeding in.
So 15 in and 150 images at a time.
And I say with T.F. session as SPSS we're going to say session ront in
and then we'll do the following.
So I'm going to say for every epoch in the range of the number of the POCs chosen we'll do the following.
The first thing to decide well how many batches is that actually going to be.
Well luckily for us that's quite simple the way this dataset works for us.
We know the number of batches is just going to be this train number of examples divided by the batch
size.
And the reason I'm doing this two forward slashes is in order to not get a small point now.
This basically does a kind of classic division sort of truth division here.
So we know the number of batches we need to go through now just the number of examples of about the
size that equals the number of batches to go through.
So say for every iteration in range of the number of batches we need to go through that are going to
say X batch y batch is equal to this train.
The next batch pests and the batch size again kind of uses convenience methods from him.
They were frightened to say session run that training Optum or training operation we define earlier
and that our dictionary just expects one placeholder value that's going to be X as the next batch.
So once we train that entire number of batches we'll go head and print out our training loss which is
just going to be evaluating our loss.
And again we'll pass it in the dictionary next ex-pats.
Whoops make sure it'll have strings there right.
And we'll go ahead and print out something like Poch
the Los Angeles pitance of formatting there will pass in the pocket number and then that training loss.
Finally once we're done with all the pox I'm going to save this so we'll pasand and save session and
then we'll say example Stex auto encoder checkpoint auto Khutor checkpoint S.K. OK run that and fast
forward in time for this to finish running.
Then we're going to test our auto encoder output on the test data and then we're going to visualize
it.
OK so I just finished running a fiver POCs.
This may take a little bit of time depending on how good your machine is.
Let's go ahead and test that 10 images.
So we're going to say run now 10 test images or images that the auto hasn't seen before.
And let's see how they come out on the other end.
Hopefully they still represent numbers more or less.
They should look like the numbers the past then they may be a little blurry or a little skewed a little
noisy but we should be able to tell that they are fairly similar.
So I'm going to restore that model I just credence let me copy and paste this here.
Examples that out and couter.
And again if you don't actually want to run this there is an example of checkpoint file free to load
up that we don't wait for all this training OK.
So those are examples that Uttam couter I'm going to say that the results are equal to the output layer.
And then I will evaluate it same as we did last time based off the feed dictionary of X..
But in this case of pasand test images.
So the in my test images and then we're just going to passen the number of test images we actually want
to test which in this case are tentes images.
All right so right now I have my results.
So if I take a look at my results they're just basically 10 arrays and I'm going to copy and paste a
plotting function that's in your notebook.
I'll briefly walk through it to tell you what it's kind of actually doing here.
But this is from the notebook that goes along this lecture.
Basically what this does is it creates that polyps subplots.
So it's going to create two rows by 10 collops and the figure size is something you can adjust.
And what it's going to do is for every thing for every test image basically it's going to show the original
test image shown just reshaping it to a 28 by 20 then passing it to show.
And what this represents is the axes of the subplot.
So it's going to plot it at the very top that first rose zero.
So at the very first row we'll see all the real test images.
So those should look really clean.
And then on that second row we're going to see what happens when we pass those test images through the
actual stacked auto encoder.
So let's run this.
And here we go.
OK so this is actually basically we should expect depending on how you actually ran this.
It may be a little noisier.
That is to say you may see a little more coloring around these numbers but you should be able to basically
tell especially for really obvious ones like the ones that it did OK.
Now you'll notice there is definitely some noise here.
For example if you look at the two it's kind of drawing as if it was a 3.
So that's not really good.
And you can see for the four it's kind of getting a piece of a 7 and this one that's kind of like a
really bad five.
It's starting to really get some blurry here.
But for really obvious ones like zeros and ones and even the input 7 it performed pretty well.
So keep that in mind you can definitely kind of begin to tell what features that's learning here.
As a quick note something that's really common for people to do that.
Otto coder's is that instead of the valuating at the output layer with the end up doing is to see what
features the stack auto Khutor is kind of learning.
They end up coming up here and grabbing one of the hidden layers and evaluating at that.
So this actually isn't very useful for the way we designed our stack out in coater.
Basically just nothing or noise.
But if you're interested to see kind of what neurons are highlighting at certain inputs what you could
do theoretically is grab this second hidden layer rummer or second hand and layers one of the smaller
ones.
The one that D6 come all the way down and evaluate at the second hidden layer is sort of the outer layer.
So we're going to pass in these images and then here you're going to see kind of what pixels light up
essentially in this model second hidden layer.
As I mentioned in our case it's going to be almost nothing or kind of noisy.
And if you actually want to run this so now it's evaluating at the hidden layer that's two that's actually
just 196 pixels which means the second one is to be 14 by 14 because 14:10 14 is 186.
So if you're on that you should be able to just kind of see some noise here so you can kind of see maybe
some trends.
In this case it's not super clear.
Maybe you can added some more neurons that kind of play around with that.
But the more important part is actually evaluating at the output layer where you do get to see basically
that the stacked couter is trying its best to represent the numbers at the output.
All right I hope you found this lecture interesting.
I will see you at the next section of course.
Thanks everyone.