Welcome everyone to the machine learning overview lecture we're not going to take a little bit of time
to discuss some basic machine learning concepts and principles to set a foundation for future lecturers.
We're going to talk about the basics of supervised learning unsupervised learning reinforcement learning
some evaluation methods and more unlike typical computer programs machine learning techniques will literally
learn from data that is the same machine learning algorithms can actually find insights and data even
if they are specifically instructed what to look for in that data.
And that's what separates a machine learning algorithm from a typical computer program.
You're just giving the machine learning algorithm a set of rules to follow instead of actually telling
it what to look for it will find the insights on its own.
Now in this course we're going to be discussing how to use tensor flow for three major types of machine
learning algorithms or machine learning topics and that is supervised learning unsupervised learning
and reinforcement learning will also touch on other topics that we can use tensor flow for such as Word
embeddings with words like.
So let's first discuss supervised learning.
Supervised learning uses labelled data to predict the label given some features and that's the really
important part.
The fact that the data is labeled so whenever you think of supervised learning think label if the labels
continuous It's called the regression problem and if it's categorical It's called a classification problem.
So let's go ahead and give an example of a classification problem which would fall under supervised
learning for your data.
You'll have some features such as height and weights and the label could be something like gender.
So then your task could be given a person's height and weight predict their gender.
So what does this actually look like.
Well for instance we could just plot out a couple of points here.
Remember since this is supervised learning and classification we already know the labels in this case
our labels are male and female genders and we have height in weight as our features.
So for a classification task our model ends up being trained on some training data here then in the
future we'll get a new point who features we do know such as we know the weight and the height but we
don't know what class it belongs to then our machine learning algorithm will predict according to what
it's been trained on what class it should be.
And in that case it predict that male then there's also regression problems.
This is again a supervised learning technique because of a Russian problem does have a given label based
off historical values.
Now the only difference here is that the label is sort of being categorical such as male and female.
It's continuous such as the house price.
So in this case we'll have a dataset with features such as the square footage of a house how many rooms
it has etc. and we need to predict some continuous values such as house price so that when the task
is given a house size and the number of rooms predict the selling price of the house so when we plot
out this data it looks like this.
We have a price and let's say square feet.
So here only using one feature.
So on the x axis we have our feature the square feet of the house indicating how big the house is and
then on the y axis we have the actual label that we're trying to predict.
And in this case the label is continuous because it can't be split up into categorical units instead
of it's continuous Preissing value.
So your model will end up creating some sort of fit to the data.
In this case it kind of has a trend here that the larger the houses the higher in price.
So then when you get a new house whose price you don't know but you do know it's features such as the
square footage of the house you end up checking out your model and it returns back it's predicted price.
So that's how we regression supervised learning algorithm works.
And again this is a very basic example of this so supervised learning has the model train on historical
data that is already labeled such as those previous house sales.
Once the model is trained on that historical data it can then be used on new data or only the features
are known to attempt prediction.
So that can be really useful if you're a real estate agent.
You can look up all the features of previous houses that have sold and then match them up to their prices.
Train your model and then when the new house comes onto the market base of its features you can predict
what price it should sell for.
Now the question arises What if you don't have historical labels for your data you only have features
since you technically have no rights or correct answer to fit on that is you have no label.
You actually need to look for patterns in the data and find the structure.
And this is known as an unsupervised learning problem because you don't actually have the labels.
So let's walk through an example of an unsupervised learning problem.
It really common unsupervised learning task is called clustering where you're given data with just the
features no labels and your task is to cluster into similar groups.
So for example Mavin you're given data that has as a feature heights and weights for breeds of dogs
and however this is unsupervised learning you actually don't have the label you don't know what actual
breeds these are so you have no label for the breeds you just have the actual features the heights and
weights of these thugs.
So your task is to cluster together the data into similar groups.
It is then up to the data scientist or whoever is performing this machine learning task to interpret
what the clusters actually means and that usually indicates that unsupervised learning has a lot to
do with domain knowledge.
As far as interpreting the results so what does this look like as a really basic example.
Here plot out all our data points for these various heights and the weights of these dogs.
And then after computing your clustering algorithm you end up deciding that you have these two clusters
you're machine learning model says hey I think these two clusters are pretty similar to each other but
you should note that clustering isn't actually able to tell you what the group labels should be.
It can't report back what actual breeds of dogs these are.
All I can tell you is that these points in each cluster are similar to each other based off the features.
So it's a really important thing to know especially when it comes to evaluating unsupervised learning
models.
Now you might be wondering what about machine learning tasks that I've heard about or read about like
a computer learning to play a video game or drive a car etc. and that sort of reinforcement learning
comes into play.
And it's not quite like supervised learning or unsupervised learning.
Reinforcement learning works through trial and error which actions yield the greatest rewards.
So when it comes to reinforcement learning there are three major components.
That is the agent the environment and the actions and we'll cover this all more in depth when we actually
show you how to do reinforcement learning of Python.
But to start off the first major component is the agent and that is the learning or decision maker than
the agent has the environment.
And that's what the agent interacts with.
So for reinforcement learning trying to learn how to drive a car or self-driving car the environment
may be what it's reading in from the camera Thiede such as the street signs etc..
Or if you're training the agent to learn how to play a video game that would be the actual pixels on
the screen that can read then you have actions.
And that is what the agent can actually do in response to the environment.
For example self-driving car you could say break or hit the accelerator turn etc. for a videogame reinforcement
learning it would be what button to press based off the environment.
Than for the actual process of reinforcement learning what occurs is that the agent will choose the
actions that maximize some specified reward metric over a given amount of time.
Maybe if you're training an agent to play a video game that actual Ward is your high score then what
you're going to do is have the agent learn the best policy with the environment and it's going to respond
with the best actions.
So let's go ahead and walk through the basic machine learning process for a supervised learning problem.
Then afterwards we're going to discuss some key differences for unsupervised learning as well as discuss
holdout datasets at the very beginning of this course.
Most of what we're going to cover falls under supervised learning are unsupervised learning.
So it's important that we basically discuss what that whole process actually looks like because we're
going to be using tent's flow and you're own that's to actually solve these problems later on much later
in the course we'll discuss reinforcement learning which kind of has its own particular machine learning
process.
It doesn't really fall quite into this general machine learning process.
OK so let's go ahead and go step by step.
What a M-L process looks like.
First thing you have to do is actually acquire the data.
Now this really depends on what task you're trying to solve.
If it's something like a regression problem you need to acquire a previous house sales and you maybe
get that from something like Zill dot com or if you're trying to classify images into dogs versus cats
you somehow acquire the various data of images of dogs and cats.
Then the next step is to clean and organize the data.
So again maybe you got those actual images but they have too many pixels so it's too much information
and it's going to take a really long time to train your model.
So maybe you clean it down or take away edges or just try to get the faces of the dogs and the cats
instead of the whole body etc. or maybe try to do things like normalize the data.
So you do some sort of standard scaling on your data and unfortunately a lot of your time is actually
spent on cleaning the data and not so much on making the cool models.
So again most of your time is going to spent here on data cleaning.
So once you do that you do what's called a train test split and so you going to split your data into
a training set and a testing set.
Now there's lots of split ratios you can use a really common split ratio is to have 30 percent of your
data be test and then 70 percent the data be training.
But it really depends on the situation how clean your data is how much do you have access to.
And then we'll also discuss hold up data sets later on once you perform that train to split it's time
to actually train or fit your model on the training data.
So you'll have some sort of model.
And in this case we're going to use tensor flow and neural networks as our model and train that model
solely on that training set.
Then once you've trained that model it becomes time to evaluate that model.
And this is where that test set comes in.
Now the reason we use that separate test set is so we don't basically cheat since the model has already
been trained on the training set.
We want to evaluate it fairly against data that it has never seen before just like it would in the real
world.
Once it becomes time to deploy that model and that's the main idea behind that test train split.
So you train your model on that training data and evaluate your model on data it hasn't seen before
such as that test set.
Once you've done that you go ahead and adjust model parameters to try to get a better fit onto that
test set.
So again train your model on the training data evaluate how it performs on that test data set and then
you can make adjustments and cycle back and forth.
Once you're satisfied if your model you can then deploy it onto new incoming data.
So that's a very basic approach to machine learning acquire the data clean data split it into a test
and a train set train your model on that training set evaluated against a test set adjust the model
parameters.
Repeat that process until you're ready and set aside to deploy the model.
Now let's go ahead and discuss unsupervised learning remember unsupervised learning.
Those are data sets that had no labels.
So for unsupervised learning problems most of the time you're not actually going to do some sort of
test train split because it doesn't really make sense to evaluate your model against some test because
you don't know the correct labels to evaluate against.
So are we going gonna end up doing and said we're going to use all the data as training data and then
you're going to evaluate against the training data based off some sort of unsupervised learning metric
and we'll discuss those evaluation metrics in just a little bit.
But unsurprised unsupervised learning typically not going to have that test train split because it doesn't
really make sense because you don't actually know the correct answer to evaluate against then finally
let's go ahead and discuss a holdout set or an evaluation set.
Sometimes it's also called that and does a really similar process to a test train split.
Except we actually after we clean the data split it into three groups a training set a testing set and
what we call a holdout set.
And again the ratios between train test and hold out really different depending on how much study you
have and what that particular situation is.
So there's no real right or wrong answer on what the ratio should be between those three sets as far
as their sizes are.
But the actual process is really similar to what we saw before we take our data in we clean it we split
it into those three sets.
We train our model on the training data and then we test our model against the test data and the base
of those results we can adjust the model parameters test again etc. go through that little loop and
then once we're ready to deploy our model we have our holdout data set.
Now the purpose of the hold out data set is to try to get some sort of final metric or idea of how well
your model is going to perform.
The pond deployment you can think of it as not trying to cheat again with the test data because technically
we've also been adjusting model parameters against the test data.
We still don't have a true sense of how well the model performs against data that it's truly never seen
before and truly never been adjusted for.
And that's what we have that hold that data set.
Now the main idea here is that once you evaluate your model against the whole dataset you're not really
allowed to go back and adjust the model parameters.
The purpose of that holdout dataset is to get some sort of final report some sort of final metric to
let you know hey when we deploy this to the real world this is the sort of metrics that we're going
to expect because the model has truly never seen this data before and it's never had the parameters
adjusted for that data.
So that's the purpose of that whole that data set so we've been discussing a lot about model evaluation.
That last step has a lot to do with evaluating it against either the test data or the evaluation data
that hold out data.
So let's quickly dive into more details for certain problems later on in the course so supervised learning
for classification evaluation metrics you have things such as accuracy recall and precision and which
metric is the most important really depends on the specific situation.
But a lot of times in this course we're just going to be using accuracy because it's the easiest to
understand.
Basically all accuracy is is the number of correctly classified samples divided by the total number
of samples given to the actual model.
So again pretty straightforward for regression evaluation tests.
Again that falls under supervised learning.
There is lots of evaluation metrics things like mean UPS error mean squared error root mean squared
error.
Essentially all these are just measurements of on average how far off are you in your prediction from
the correct continuous value.
So mean absolute error means square root mean squared error to some manner or degree.
They're all trying to say the same thing on average your model predicts about this far off numerically.
So we'll be using these metrics when we do regression tests for unsupervised learning as far as evaluating
that model that becomes actually much harder to evaluate.
And it really depends on the overall goal of the task.
Again remember for unsupervised learning you never really had the correct labels to compare it to.
However you can use things like cluster homogeneity or something called the Ranh index to evaluate your
unsupervised learning model and we'll discuss those later on in the auto encoders section of the course.
Now remember for unsupervised learning even if you have good metrics your model may not have performed
well and you can see here especially kind of on that second row from the top that for humanised it's
really easy to see look correct clusters should be for those kind of moon shapes but depending on your
evaluation metrics you may get bad splits or bad clustering on your data where the metrics turn out
really well but the actual groupings don't look correct.
So again unsupervised learning clustering is just a really hard problem and evaluating it is also a
really hard problem.
So kind of keep that in mind as you encounter those problems in your own work.
Now for reinforcement learning evaluation is usually a lot more obvious since that evaluation or reward
metric is actually built into the actual training of the model.
So it's typically just how well the model performs against the task it's assigned.
So that particular score in the video game etc. and again we'll discuss this a lot more when we actually
show you how to perform reinforcement learning OK.
As a quick review we discussed machine learning the types of machine learning the general machine learning
process just the basic overview and basic overview of evaluation metrics.
Hopefully that gives you a nice little foundation to work off as we continue the rest of the course.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.