Welcome everyone to the series of lectures we're going to be discussing how to build deep networks with
tensor abstractions.
Now tensor flow has many abstractions and what I mean by the word abstraction is just some sort of higher
level API which allows you to simplify your code in order to still call the same sort of tensor flow
commands.
And that usually allows you to skip things like having to find a feed dictionary variables and placeholders
instead have a much simpler to use interface.
Now typically that's simpler to use interface comes at the cost of control.
Now often you won't need that sort of control.
That if you're dealing with a simple network such as a deep fancily connected network while you're concerned
about is really just stacking layers on top of each other and making sure all the neurons are connected
and that sort of use case is perfect for abstractions.
Now as I just mentioned senseful has many abstraction options.
There's T.F. learn Cristy of slim layers the estimator API that we've covered before and even more than
that and many of these abstractions reside intenser flows.
T.F. contrib section and basically the way the contrib section works is that typically libraries or
extra features get developed and people contribute to tensor flow so they eventually accept them under
the subsection of T.F. but contrib.
And then it becomes very popular or very useful they will quote unquote graduate to be included as part
of standard sense of flow.
And in fact one of these abstractions the layers abstraction is kind of half way some of it's in contrib
and some of it is directly accessible as part of T.F. the layers in issue with abstractions in general
is one there are in my opinion probably too many at this point in time for tensor flow.
They should probably all be consolidated into one more general abstraction and the other difficulty
is that it's really hard to tell which abstractions are worth learning and which are not.
And that's because the speed of development of tensor flow has caused abstractions to come and go quickly.
So some abstractions have really risen in popularity only to be abandoned a few months later when something
like Cara's comes out and Cure's gets included intenser flow.
So keep that in mind.
We're going to focus this series of lectures on presenting the most common abstractions used and the
ones that basically I personally believe will have the most longevity as far as tensor for development
is concerned.
And those are the estimator API that we first learned about so we'll do a quick review of that as well
as cares and Cure's was actually its own abstraction over sensor flow and another deep learning framework
called S.A. and it was this higher level API that eventually with one of the newer releases of tense
flow got accepted to be part of tensor flow through T.F. contrib.
And there's also this layer's API which is kind of halfway on contrib and Half-Way and T.F. layers.
So we'll talk about that later on.
So we're going to focus on understanding how to use these abstractions to build deep densely connected
neural networks basically focusing on how do we stack these layers on top of each other.
So that makes it really easy to use these abstractions for these simpler tasks all the code that I'm
about to show is available in deep nets with T.F. attraction's Python notebook file.
And keep in mind all the code is actually in there in one giant notebook if you're following along.
I would actually recommend creating one notebook per abstraction.
That way you don't get any sort of interference between them.
OK.
Let's start by exploring the dataset we're going to be using and open up a fresh Jupiter notebook and
then walk you through that dataset.
We're actually going to grab it using sikat learn.
So let's jump over to the notebook.
All right.
So as I just mentioned we're going to focus on grabbing that data right now.
We'll say from Eski learn datasets import and we're going to load this wind data set.
So the way S-K learned data sets works is that you basically import this function that allows you to
download this wind data set feel say wind data equals load wine run that and that loads up what is known
as a bunch file of S-K learn which is kind of its own special type of dictionary file which if you call
wind data keys it kind of behaves like a dictionary.
You see a couple of things here.
There are the feature names the target or label the target names the data and then the description attribute.
So what we can do here is we can say prints wind data and you can call here the description attribute
absolute mixtures that way.
And yes there we go.
And this is the wind data database.
So there's 170 instances there's 13 attributes and I have all these attributes things like the I don't
know chemical properties of the swine Plus the alcohol content things of that nature.
It's separated into three classes.
And if I remember correctly the three classes represent something like red white and ros but I'm not
a wine expert so you may have to look at the actual link to this wine data base.
So that gives you a bunch of summaries of mystics as well as the resource of where you can grab this.
So pretty small data set but it's perfect for us.
And luckily the classes are pretty well balanced there's a little more of class one than the other two.
But for our purposes that's fine.
OK.
So here's more information about the data set but we're going to do is continue on and we're going to
scroll down here and just grab the featured data as well as the labels.
So we're essentially going to attempt to do a classification task on this data will say feature data
is wind data and then we're going to grab the actual data key off that bunch object and then we'll say
labels is equal to wind data and then grab target.
So sikat learn tends to call that label as a target because it's the target you're trying to predict
then we will go ahead and perform a train test split as well as scale or data from S-K learn model selection.
I will import train split Coltrane to split and then pass that feature data as well as the labels.
And let me do shift enter here so I can grab the actual output.
So scrolling down like we've done before and then I will grab this line of code here.
Copy and paste that up and then it will say that the test size is equal to 30 percent of the data.
And so you get the same random split I do go ahead and say random state is equal to 101.
Again not necessary just an arbitrary number choice but that way your split can be the same as mine.
And lastly we are going to scale this data in order to pass into our neural network abstractions so
we'll use the minimax scalar.
I'll create an instance of the minimax scalar and I say scaled X train is equal to scalar and it will
fit transform on my training features.
And then I will say scaled X steps is scalar.
In this case I'm not going to do it I will just transform because remember we don't want to assume that
we're going to know future test data.
All right.
Perfect.
So we have our data set up coming up next in the next lecture or we're going to do is discuss our first
abstraction which is essentially going to be a review of the estimator API we saw at the beginning of
the course.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at that lecture.