Welcome back everyone in this lecture we're going to show you how to use the estimator API in order
to solve the classification problem for that wind data set.
Let's go back to Jupiter notebook.
OK so we have our wind data set.
The next thing I will do in order to start using the estimator API is they will import sensor flow as
T.F. and then I also say from sensor flow in poor estimator and then I will go ahead and run that.
OK so as a reminder if we take a look at our X train shape that 70 percent of the data.
So we have 124 rows with 13 columns have the features.
And then we have the additional label column.
So to use the S-meter API which gives them before I need to create feature columns and if they're all
numeric columns which if we take a look at x train that's actually the case here.
So take a look at x train.
These are all just numeric feature columns.
What I can do to quickly create a list of just a bunch of numeric columns is say C-f feature column
numeric column and then I going to pass in the string x to represent the actual features and then a
pass a shape attribute to represent the actual 13 data features.
So that's a really quick way to create feature columns if all your columns happen to be numeric.
We've shown you before how to deal with category calls with the estimator API.
So you can check back on those videos in case you need a refresher.
Up next is actually straight to the model so create a variable called Deep underscore model and then
off the estimator API if you do that here and then hit tab you can see the various functions that are
available to us.
We're going to do then Cely connected or a deep neural network classifier and then we have this hidden
units argument which is just the list.
And you basically say how many neurons you want in each layer.
So in our case we're just going to say 13:13 13 if you start doing more than that you'll probably be
overfitting especially for such a small data set.
But if you're looking for really large dataset maybe you'll need more than you can adjust as you see
fit.
And the next one is to find the actual feature columns will say feature columns is equal to that feat
calls variable we just made and then we also need to say the number of classes we're predicting.
So by default it's binary classification.
But in our case we have three different types.
So we'll go ahead and say there's three different classes there and then we can also pass in an optimizer.
So we'll pass A.F. train and we'll do a gradient optimizer with the learning rates equal to 0.01 OK
so run that and you should be able to see your model created and then it's actually really easy to train
your model.
The only thing left we need to build out is our input function.
Again we've shown you before how to create these input functions you just call estimator inputs and
then you have two options one for an umpire function one for panderers murthering of just not pi.
So we'll say x is equal to the x variable.
We said earlier is kind of almost like a fit dictionary here.
Scaled X train then the y component is equal to y train.
And since we're training all this will say shuffle is equal to true.
And then we can define a batch size.
I'll go ahead and say 10 for this level data and then we can find the number of POCs how many times
you want to run through this entire training set and we'll go on to say five run that and then let's
go ahead and trayner deep model on that input function.
So I will say input function here and let's run this and we can also if we want to or we can say steps
here if necessary.
So I could say something like subscales 500.
So go ahead and run that.
It's going to create that and then it will train it should be pretty straightforward.
And then we're also going to create an evaluation function which is going to look really similar to
our previous function again estimator inputs from PI input function.
But in this case we're just going to be passing in our test data.
So this will be scaled X test scale x test and then I also want to make sure that shuffle is equal to
false.
So don't shuffle my testate around run that and then all say predictions is equal to.
And if you say deep model you can call the Predict method off of this.
Keep in mind it also has if you'll remember and evaluate method.
So I could pass in the actual test labels.
But in this case we're going to do that manually which it predicts and the input function is going to
be equal to input function evil evil remember and recall that this is actually a generator so if you
want to get the actual results you know cast this something or loop through it later on.
So we'll cast this into a list.
So now if I take a look at Pretz it's this list of dictionary objects.
So I will use some list comprehension to just grab what I'm looking for which is this array value the
class ID so that predictions is equal to an say P class ID.
So that's the dictionary inside there.
And then I also want to grab the actual results here so that 0.
So will say X off of that 0 and say for P and Pretz.
So run that.
And that's just a simple list comprehension that eventually just gets you back that list the actual
classes predicted zeros ones or twos.
And in order to evaluate this we're going to do is say from S-K learn the metrics import and you can
do either confusion matrix.
You can also do it classification report.
Let's go in and just do a classification report here and we'll pass in our test and our predictions
and let's print this up.
OK so running that you should have some pretty good results for that.
Hovering around above 85.
So in this case I performed pretty well in 95 94 94 but that's the estimator API.
You've already used that before in the beginning of the course.
Hopefully that was basically all of you for you.
Let's quickly do a quick rundown of everything we did.
First things first you have to get your data in the right shape.
Once you've done that you can go ahead and create your feature columns feature columns can be a little
more complicated if you have categorical data but again recall that you can just call tab here and there's
different versions of categorical data.
We covered those in the beginning of the course using the estimator API.
But if you have all numeric columns this is a nice little feature with the shape then we create a classifier
defining the hidden units.
You can easily add more layers just by making this larger.
You have the feature columns and the Reclast to predict the specific optimizer with your learning right
then you create these input functions which you like to basically act like a feed dictionary inputting
that data.
And if you're training you also want to make sure you pass and your training labels you want to shuffle
this and you can find your batch size number of pocks you train your model all the data and then you
can evaluate it and use predict or evaluation the Pennine what your estimate or input function looks
like.
OK.
That's really all there is to it.
Coming up next we're going to discuss the keris abstraction off of Tancer flow.
I'll see it there.