Welcome everyone in this lecture we're going to be showing you how to use the Keres API as a T.F. abstraction
and carious is actually now included within tensor flow.
So we'll show you how you can use it from tensor flow.
Let's jump to Jupiter notebook and discuss a few things about cars.
OK.
Here I am in the Jupiter notebook and as a quick note I've gone ahead and reran all the data code and
i deleted from the previous lecture video all our stuff about the S-meter pay.
So we're going to start fresh with carrots and if you go to the carrots documentation page here.
It's a python deep learning library.
And basically what it is it's a high level neural network API.
It's written in Python and it doesn't just run on top of tensor flow it can actually run on top of C.A.
Kate or C.A..
And if you want to use it in that manner you'll need to download keras as a separate library.
With the release of some newer versions of course what happened was cars eventually became part of tensor
flow.
And as I mentioned earlier in the beginning of the abstractions lecture series the contrib portion of
tensor flow has that section of things that are contributed to tensor flow.
So that's where Carse's.
So if we come back here after imports says T.F. I can also show you this from tensor flow dot contrib.
If you hit tab here you'll eventually see a list of all the options.
So here they are we see there's Android based flow Bouzid trees distribution's factorization framework
etc. layers which we'll discuss later on.
There's also a legacy code in here that will probably not be updated in the future metrics losses predictor.
And one of them you can eventually see is curse.
So basically the entire library is now with intenser full here.
So now you can import anything that's available in cars and there's activations applications etc..
So the first single import is models.
Keep in mind what we're going to show here is a really small part.
It's just building a very simple deep densely connected neural network curiousest can actually do things
like convolutional or one that works for current near.
That works all the higher level API.
Again you're sacrificing control for that.
But if you're more Istomin cares go ahead and check out the current documentation.
Right now we're showing how you can use it as a basic setup for a high level API.
OK.
So important models.
So I go ahead and with carriers we end up doing is you first create a model.
So I'll say my deep neural network care model is equal to models dots.
And here you can and that doing various models but the ones are mainly going to call his sequential
model and it's sequential because you basically just have a sequence of layers.
So in order to add layers of the model what you need to do is call from tensor flow contrib keris and
we're going to import layers from Keres and curious layers.
If you take a look at it do layers tab you realize that there's actually a bunch of layers already created
for you and Cara's There's the average pooling layer convolutional layers to the 3D.
All this stuff but we're really going to be focusing on the simplest layer which is just a dense layer
that's connected.
There's also drop layers et cetera.
So you can explore that later on but will first create a layer and what you end up doing is you take
your model.
That model we just define densely or near that work Cara's model and you call ad and then you end up
adding layers to it these layer objects.
So for dense network what you need end up defining is the number of units in this particular layer.
So we have 13 units in this layer and you also need to fine if it's the first one the input dimensions
and the input dimensions for us is going to be 13 features.
And then you can also define an activation.
So we'll go ahead and pass in the street code for activation as our E-L you are rectified linear unit
and later on we'll show you how you can discover the string codes for that.
You could just go to the doc documentation but you can actually see it quickly.
But we'll talk about that later on.
Forget the last prince who's there.
OK.
So let's basically mimic what we did before and added a couple more layers here.
Well again say Kurus model.
I'm going to add and here you know you could technically add whatever kind of players you want if you
for whatever reason needed a convolutional ere you do that as well.
But keeping things simple We'll have another dance layer.
We just say units is 13 because it's no longer the first input layer we don't need to find the dimensions
or we need to say again is the activation function which will pass in the street code there.
So I'm going to copy this and paste this.
So then we essentially add two more layers there and then finally when we get to our last layer we'll
say model and I'm going to add in other dense layer but the number of units is going to have is just
equal to three.
And the reason for that is because we're going to be using the activation function of a soft Max activation.
Remember back to the digits data lecture we had the one hot encoded classes.
So we're essentially going to be doing a very similar thing here except carious is going to take care
of all that in the background.
So we'll explain that in a little bit.
But essentially we just have three units one for each class using a soft mass Max activation there and
that's going to be our last layer.
OK.
Next we want to compile the model.
So the next thing I'm going to do is say from tensor flow contrib thuck Harris and going to import losses
optimizers metrics and activations.
So previously I said there's a quick way to figure out what activations are available.
So you don't just have to memorize these particular string codes and the quick way to do that is once
you've imported these you can just say activations dots that tab here and we'll show you all the activations
that are available for you.
And basically all the ones that you would expect are here for you their sigmoid activation and soft
Max rectifies linear unit etc..
Hyperbolic tangent all the basic ones are here for you.
So keep that in mind.
And if you're looking for whatever optimizers are available free you can do optimizers thought and then
hit tab.
Adam itemizes is available armis prop.
Gradient descent.
Cetera.
So we're going to do here is the following.
We are going to say grab our model.
So the final step after he added the layers is to compile it which basically sets up all the layers
as they should be.
So the compiling step needs an optimizer and it's a loss function.
And if you're doing classification you can pasand some metrics to classify by say optimizer and we're
going to pass that string code Adam which we saw right now how we can get it we just say optimizers
dot and then see the list of itemizes available.
And that for a.
We're going to do is the following will say sparse underscore categorical underscore cross entropy.
And for this one I would suggest looking into the documentation as far as which ones are appropriate.
It kind of depends on what format your data is in.
If your data is not one hot encoded coming in in order for Caris understand that we need to do is say
sparse categorical cross entropy if your data is already hot and coded then you can just do categorical
cross entropy.
So keep that in mind.
There's a lot more detail in the current documentation about this.
You won't really find this sort of detail in the text for the documentation.
Instead they would expect you to go to Paris and read about it because essentially everything that's
included in this is already here for you contrib that cares.
So we're using sparse Ketek we'll cross entropy because we're using categories as we have three of them.
Number those three classes and we're using sparse here because coming in they're not one high end code
already where you could do is one high end code them and then just have categorical entropy if you wanted
to.
So all the same metrics is going to be accuracy in case you ever want to do some sort of evaluation
so you compile that model AUPs that should just be single.
Yes.
That you run that and now it's ready to be trained.
So again the steps here was just to import your model create an instance of that sequential model and
you just add layers to it.
Pretty straightforward once you out of the layers.
You compile it with whatever optimize you want the last function you want and then if it's classification
you can add things like metrics.
So let's go ahead and train this model will say the end of this model and we're going to fit it to our
scaled data.
So scale x train.
And then our right train and then go in and train this for I don't know 50 parks or something so run
that you should see some output like this.
It probably won't run as fast as that here but mine is already done.
You'll see the loss and the accuracy metric kind of go up.
So that's basically what we were asked for right here as far as the metrics.
So if you scroll all the way down hopefully you started reaching close to 95.
So if you want to get predictions off of this it's actually quite easy you just say predictions as equal
to whatever your model name was.
And you can call predict.
And if you just can't predict that's going to return back the actual like soft Max the output layer.
So we won't predict classes here and there we're going to pass our scaled X test data and then let's
print out our classification report.
So let me actually import that from S-K learn dot metrics import classification report and let's run
that classification report.
In our predictions and then pass an the test values.
So if you're in that you should get somewhere around 80s or 90s percent.
I believe you ran this enough you should be able to get up to 95 percent maybe even higher.
OK so let's quickly review what we just did here of course.
It's a really great library especially just starting out learning of machine learning and you're not
sure what actual framework you want to use because you can basically put this on top of C A.K. or thanto.
But again you just tent's food that contribute Cara's import models create a sequential model instance
and then whatever layers you want you just add those layers on.
Once you've done that you go ahead and compile it using whatever optimized you want the loss and the
metrics and then you can fit this.
Now keep in mind this is a really simple example because we're just doing a densely connected neural
network and it's pretty straightforward.
But this sometimes gets a little more complicated as you add in more complex layers like recurrent neural
network layers or convolutional layers.
It's still intended to be much simpler than just doing it straight in pure tensor flow.
But keep that in mind.
All right so that's if you're interested in learning more about care since this course is mainly focused
on tensor flow I would recommend you check out the curiousest documentation is actually quite good and
they even have things like getting started guys for like a sequential model.
So you click here and it will tell you how to do a specific sequential model so specify an input shape
the compilation of it training etc..
So lots and lots of examples even has a full example folder.
If you go to that page it has lots of examples here on how to do various models.
It's a really great library.
And in my opinion it's the future of abstractions for tensor flow.
I believe this is probably the number one abstraction in the future.
Granted I may be totally wrong about that but Keres is probably the strongest one and that's especially
noted because it was an entirely separate library that got contributed into tensor flow again.
Don't forget about the estimator API and coming up next we're going to show you the layers API which
is also really popular.
So we'll cover the layers API in the very next lecture.