Welcome back everyone.
Finally PIII we're going to talk about is the layers API abstraction.
Let's over with the Jupiter notebook and show you how to use it.
All right before we get started with the layers API I want to make a quick point here that currently
the layers API is kind of separated between the layers contrib portion and the TFT layers portion.
If you come over here to the documentation of the general API docs you can see the python API guides.
So if you keep scrolling down eventually you'll find layers contrib and if you click on that you'll
see layer's contrib So there's T.F. contrib and then there's various layers and basically we end up
doing is you just stack layers on top of each other and then pass them in with placeholders variables
and a T.F. session.
You can remember from our lecture on convolutional neural networks we basically created our own layer
type objects.
That is what this T.F. trip contrib is for.
Now as I mentioned there's T.F. contrib layers and you can use those.
And there's a lot more layers here but if he keeps scrolling down past T.F. left contrib layers you'll
eventually realize that there's already a T.F. layers for us.
So right here there's T.F. layers.
And this is what's been able to essentially graduate from contrib over to layers.
So there's an overview here and it will tell you more about the actual layers.
So this is the layers module and you can see here has various functions.
And keep in mind some of these functions got changed as far as their naming convention when it got passed
from contrib to the TFA layers.
So for example A.F. duck and contrib that layer's the fully connected layer for dense neural network
is called fully underscore connected A.F. thought layers.
It's just called dense.
If you want to find that more information about how to use T.F. layers for more complex tasks like convolutional
all that work you can click over here there's a link in your notebook but just go to Florida the org
slash tutorial slash layers and it has a full guy to basically solving the data set task with the layers
API so you can see here.
If you scroll down they basically import convolutional layers pulling layers etc. and again.
Main idea here of the abstractions is you kind of just take care of the layers with one or two lines
of code.
Let's go ahead and solve the problem of the wind classification with the layers API in order to do this.
We are going to need to one in code our data.
The easiest way to do that is with Panas basically pantless has a really quick method to do this.
So we're going to say one hot underscore why train is equal to PD and the get dummys method quickly
creates one high encoding for anything you pasan.
So if you say P-T that dummys on this y train and then check out that one hot train you can see here
now are classes 0 1 and 2 are encoded throughout this entire white train.
Now if I want this as a Panas data frame but instead as a matrix I can say as matrix here and then run
that and then I have the same thing.
But now it's as a PI matrix which is the format that the layers API is going to need this in.
So let's do this one more time for the test data.
We'll say one ha y test is equal to PD get dummies and then we'll pass y test as the matrix gets.
OK so we have our one hot encoded training and testing labels.
Now it's time to find some parameters for our actual layer's API the way we're going to do this is the
following method.
We're going to say the number of features is 13 and then we're going to say the number of neurons in
the first layer is 13.
The number of neurons in the second hidden layer is 13 and then the number of outputs is equal to three.
And let's also find now a learning rate for our optimizer will go ahead and just say 0.01 and then we'll
be using the contrib layer's API because it has slightly more options.
So because of that we're going to be using the fully connected
and wups mixture.
That's okay.
OK.
So now I have a fully connected.
And what's interesting about this layer's API is it kind of is a halfway point between a simple abstraction
and full tensor flow.
It really connects nicely with sessions last functions and optimizers.
So it has that half of control of using pure tensor flow but it basically takes care of building out
common layers for you.
So it's a pretty useful API which is why I think it might have some more lasting power.
So the first thing to do is create or placeholders will say to float 32.
And then the shape of this is going to be based on the batch size and then the number of features which
in our case was 13.
And then we also need a placeholder for the actual labels so placeholder 32 and then the shape here
is going to be equal to that size and then three on that output because it's coded.
Next we're going to need the activation function in order so I don't keep rewriting this for every single
layer.
I'm just going to call TFT and N for Ariail you as my X F or activation function.
Next we're going to find hidden one layer.
So these are the actual layers.
Keep in mind appear this numb head in one hand and two.
Those are the neurons for these layers.
So when I find hit in one I call the fully connected function and then this just needs the inputs the
number of outputs and then the activation function.
So you passen the input which is going to be that X placeholder for that first layer.
And if you want you could call this input layer to maybe a more appropriate there was a hidden one and
also the activation function actif it into fully connected it in one.
And then it's going to need number hit into 13 year olds there and the activation function is again
going to be act f and then finally we'll have our output layer.
It's also going to be a fully connected layer that takes in that hidden to layer and then whatever number
of outputs you want.
In our case it's going to be three outputs.
OK so let's go ahead and define the last function.
So this kind of feels like a blend between pure tensor flow and the layers API.
Basically the layers API already done using it.
It was just these three lines right here.
Hopefully I'll say this a little bit of time but we're going to use our soft Max cross entropy when
I say our one hot labels is equal to that y true placeholder.
And then the logic is essentially our prediction is going to be the output K so that's our last function
we need to of course build an optimizer that attempts to minimize it.
So I will say optimizers T.F. train and we'll choose an atom optimizer with the learning rate that we
find earlier.
And we're going to hear training up operation is just minimizing that optimizer.
So we see optimizer and we call it to minimise our loss function just as we've done before.
Then finally we say in its T.F. global variables initialiser and now we're going to run the session
just like we would any other time well to find some number of training steps I'll go ahead and say a
thousand training steps and then I will say with T.F. session as SPSS
run that global variables initialiser and then see for I in range the number of training steps you want
to do here is just run that trainer so run that trainer and then pass in that feat dictionary.
So very typical of tensor flow basically.
Now you're just back to the classic tensor flow.
Having used that layer's API to quickly create in your own that worked for you and then will pass and
why train here.
So there's our feed dictionary.
So what we're doing that we're going to go ahead and grab the predictions so say logic is equal to the
output layer and we're going to evaluate that output later and we'll give it a feed dictionary of the
test data which is just going to be the scaled X test that our predictions is going to be RMX of logic
here along x is equal to 1.
So what does that actually mean.
Remember we're going to be basically asking what value has the highest probability for the class.
That's what the output layer is going to give back.
So we're going to use that RMX along access equal to one in order to actually grab that.
So that's going return that index position which luckily for us we just have 0 1 and 2.
That correlates exactly with the predicted class.
So the result is just going to be the evaluation of that.
And let's make sure that it actually have a typo there can't feed can't feed this wups.
Looks like we forgot to actually pass the one hot uncoated.
So I mean take a look up here with that we actually call the one hot coated one hot white train.
So let's grab that
and pass that in.
OK.
Now that train trained fine.
Remember we had a pass and the one hot forgot about that and let's test this out.
We'll say from S-K learn metrics.
I'm going to import the classification report.
And let's see how we did will say Prince classification report.
Passen those results.
And then the actual test run that.
And luckily for us we got 100 percent accuracy with this.
Now we did run it for a thousand training steps.
So we performed really well as a quick precaution.
If you ever get perfect results like this they're not completely unknown when you're dealing with really
complex models like neural networks.
We should be suspicious of them.
So something I like to do if I ever get this kind of perfect result is maybe skew the parameters to
make sure that I would not get a good result if I did this wrong.
So what I'm going to do here now is just reduce this to just two training steps.
So I get to run this all again and hopefully now when I run this I can see worse performance and that's
exactly what I get.
So of just two training steps I'm not getting a good performance.
So I know here that it is a result of my actual model and not some sort of air.
So just a quick precaution if you ever get perfect results always have some sort of healthy suspicion
for them and confirm that it is actually your model.
All right.
Hope you enjoy that series of lectures.
I will see you at the next one.