Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture where we're going to be showing you an awesome visualization
tool that already comes built into tensor flow.
And that is tensor board and it really allows you to visualize complex graphs and a very organized manner.
Keep in mind that we will be using the command prompt as well as the Jupiter notebook.
So go ahead and open up either your terminal or your command prompt and make sure you have your environment
file ready to be activated.
Let's open up a Jupiter notebook create a simple graph and then visualize it ok here and at my Jupiter
notebook I've already imported tensor flow and what I'm going to do is just build out a really simple
graph session.
I'm going to say T.F. is equal to T.F. and I'm going to add two numbers together.
They wanted to that I'm going to say B is equal to T.F. and three and four together and then I will
say C is equal to T.F..
And then I will multiply A and B together.
So a very simple graph and then what I will do now is run the sessional say with t f session as SPSS
like and say session run.
And then I just actually need to run C and in fact I can print out the output of this so I can see it
and I get 21 which makes sense because I basically have one plus two here which is three and then three
times three plus four to seven.
So if through them.
21.
Now if I have a really complex graph I'm not going to be able to directly interpret it just using these
lines of code if I have more than just these three entries.
It's going to be really hard to basically trace back where all these variables come from.
So it'd be really nice if I could visualize that graph.
And that's actually really easy with tensor board.
So let's show you how you can do that will you end up doing is within your session where you're going
to do is the very first thing of your session.
You're going to say T.F. or excuse me writer is equal to see summary and then you going to call file
writer and you're going to create an output file location.
So I'll say it Dopp forward slash output and then of this we're going to save our session graph.
And then once you're finished running your operations you're going to make sure to close your writer.
So let's run that.
And right now we see the same result but if we take a look at where this trooper notebook is located
for my case it's located under miscellaneous topics.
If I come back to the miscellaneous topics folder click on the output folder I can now see this T.F.
events file.
And that basically has all the information about that graph.
So we're going to do now is open up our command prompt and show you how you can run tensor board.
So I will open up my command prompt and inside the command prompt the first thing I want to do is make
sure that I activate my deep learning environment.
The reason for that is because I need to make sure that I have tensor flow available in this environment.
That way I can call sensor board at the command line.
Otherwise you get some sort of error saying something like tensor board not recognized the next loops.
The next they're going to do is call a tensor board and then the following command.
Dash dash.
Well make sure there's a space there.
So it's a little harder to tell my screen but I'm typing tensor board and then typing a space and then
I will say dash dash log directory is equal to.
And then if you're on Windows you may need to use double quotes here.
And if you get an error of double quotes go ahead and try.
No quotes that kind of depends on what operating system whether you use single quotes double quotes
or no quotes at all.
So just keep that in mind and you're going Pathans pass in the same path that you created earlier.
So let me make sure I call the output.
So there it is support slash output.
And I can just do that because I'm located in the miscellaneous topics folder.
If you want to you can write the full path out here but since I'm located in the same folder I just
need to run that and I see centerboard running at this HTP.
So I will go ahead and copy this.
Make sure you don't copy of control c otherwise you're going to end up putting.
So in my case I just did it right click that and then I will go back to my browser and paste that in
and here.
Now we see this awesome visualization of my graphs.
So I have adding X and Y here add 1 x and y these two scalars and then they get multiplied and I can
click on one of these nodes and I can see the various operations the data types expects.
And then I can actually remove it from the main graph etc. and if you come over here to tensor flow
there's things like downloading it to a PNB file thing to a screen if you have a very large plot or
a graph you may need to do that.
You can see the various runs in case you randomly fill sessions of this.
You can upload graph files you can highlight this thing that says trace inputs.
In this case we actually have no placeholder input so we'll just turn that off and then you can also
see the graph essentially a legend telling you what the name spaces are.
The operation nodes constants etc..
Now as you can imagine if we have a ton of operations here this sort of automatic naming of add add
1 add to multiply and multiply 3 etc. isn't actually going to be very helpful.
So you can actually add names to your notes.
So let me come back here and show you how you can do that.
Basically every tensor flow operation has the ability of a parameter called name and you'll see this
often throughout a different storyline on line where they just assign names and if they never use centerboard
you might be wondering well why are they assigning the names.
If we never actually use them well they're for centerboard.
So let's go ahead and say this was our first ad operation and keep in mind you can't have spaces in
the string.
Otherwise we'll have an error there.
This name we'll say is our seconds at operation and then this multiply we'll give it the name of final
results.
So I'm going to run these again and let's refresh our Tencent board.
So when I refreshed tensor board if you take a look at what happens I end up getting my original graph
here as well as this new named graph.
So if you want you can edit that if we come back to our output folder you can see now I have T.F. events.
So I have my old one and the one I just created.
And also if you open up your command prompt it will basically report to you.
Hey I found a more than one Medak Raffy wants to run.
I move right in that graph with the newest event and what it means by overwrite is that it's overwriting
with a new graph here.
So it's adding that on top.
So it's technically showing two graphs if you wanted to edit that.
You could just kind of delete your old plot file or overwrite it cetera.
But again pretty good news here that we don't accidentally overwrite a graph because notice you're still
giving it the same output.
But luckily for us censor board and sensor flow is smart enough to know that you may not want to accidentally
overwrite your old stuff.
So basically just keeps adding to those crafty events.
All right.
So you can name stuff in your graph.
Well you can also do is add scope's.
So to do that we're going to add in a couple of more variables here.
I'm going to say 8 is equal to T.F..
And let's go ahead and add one hundred and 200 together and it will give us the name
a add the names aren't really important here is just for demonstration purposes we'll make another variable.
Well another operation really not really a central variable and this one's going to be called at 300
and 400 will name this be at.
And then we have this final result of C..
So what we'll do is we'll do the following.
We're going to add a two or multiply and B to.
So let's add those and we'll say A2 is T.F. and I'm going to multiply the result of an 8 1 and they
will say BE2 is equal to T.F..
Multiply the results of B and B one.
OK so we can so far follow along with the general logic because we kind of wrote this from the start.
But if you begin to just see this as code you kind of have no idea what's going on just at a quick glance
but luckily if tensor board will be able to see that now what we're going to do is we can see here that
our code is organized in blocks and we can actually project that organization with the use of scopes
in tensor board.
So what we end up doing is wow are the finance operations we can do the following we'll say with T.F.
name scope and then you pass in the name or what you want the scope to be called so we can say like
Operation a.
And then we have a colon here and then you write in as a block.
So just tab and dance all the operations you want to find within that scope and what that scope is going
to look like with intenser board is basically a big grey box that it can expand.
So then the next thing to do here is say if name scope and this will be all be called Operation be
inlets in that this is now all go within the scope and you can actually have some scopes.
So if you have like another set of operations inside the scope you could have also had with T.F. name
scope operation you know Delta A or something like that.
OK so now we have these two scopes.
So let's go ahead and check this out.
So we'll run these again.
And now I'm getting a much larger number which kind of makes sense.
And if I refresh my tensor board what's going to happen now is this third graph looks a little different.
It now has these operations and those that are actually kind of named and what you can do is you can
expand these operations so you can double click on that plus sign and then see the graph that is within
that operation.
So there was my first that my 8 and I multiplied it and that's operation.
I can expand on this.
Click on that and then you can see operation B.
So now this allows you to organize really large graphs.
So when you see these really awesome pictures of tensor board running in action they're usually using
these operations so you can see here the really nice flow.
So we start off really simple graph that we named our nodes and then we group them together in operations.
And like I mentioned before we can have subgroups here.
So if you wanted a scope within a scope you could have done that as well.
All right.
Now so I want to know that there's actually a lot more to censor board than just visualizing graphs.
If you click here where it says interactive you can also see options for visualizing things like distribution's
histograms teks profile images and sensorial actually has really great documentation on this.
It basically has a censor board tutorial walkthrough for visualizing learning grafters ization histogram
dashboards.
But I also just want to walk you through not just graphs but also histograms.
So let's try to do that going to come back here to censor board.
And what I'm want to do is copy and paste some code this code directly from the documentation so you
can always reference it there or just copy and paste from the actual notebook for this lecture.
So I will copy and paste this but all I'm doing here is we're creating a placeholder k just like you
would.
And then we're making a normal distribution.
But what's interesting about this distribution is it has a shifting mean so it has the shape 1000 different
than normal but the mean is defined by this placeholder.
So basically have some sort of distribution that's slowly moving depending on this.
And then I'm going to record the histogram.
Now this T.F. summary histogram is a way that you can actually record things like variables or weights.
So if you recall back we're creating our own models we have T.F. variable you could pass that T.F. variable
here and then give it some sort of name or file path and then we're going to do is we'll create a session
here.
So let's actually say this.
Say with C-f session
as SPSS so it follows the same path we've been doing.
We're going to say that we have a writer it's equal to a summary writer and we're actually going to
follow this into another directory.
We'll say it goes to this temporary folder histogram example and then we'll say summaries and we're
going to say summary merge all.
And what this does is going to merge all your T.F. summaries into a single node.
So in this case we actually just have one T.F. that some recall but a lot of times you'll have lots
of histogram calls and you'll be able to see them all.
So we say T.F. that summary that merge all and then we're going to set up a loop.
So let's go ahead and do this.
Inside the session we're going to say Ed is equal to 400.
And we'll say for step in range and what we're going to do is say our current k value and make sure
my invitation is correct.
What's our current value.
Is it called Step divided by the flow then then we have this summary which is going to be some is equal
to session run you're going to run our summaries and we're going to feed it some feed dictionary of
those values which in this case is just that 400.
Are those values to 400.
And then we're also going to be calling our writer to add that summary.
And then at the very end of all this we're going to say writer and we're going to close that off.
OK let's go in and run this maternal on typos here.
And it looks like it ran correctly.
So what we're going to do is recall tensor board actually pointed to this histogram example because
right now it's just pointed at the output.
So we'll come back to our command prompt.
I'm going to say control see here and then we'll say tensor board space dash dash log directory is equal
to.
And then we're going to pass that file so's I believe Tim and make sure I get the name correct.
It was his Gramp underscore example histogram underscore example.
So let's run that make sure we don't get any errors.
Ok looks like it's running.
So I'm going to now refresh this page.
So I'll come over here refreshed that you are ill.
And now I can see I have my distributions.
Next we see that distribution.
Let me zoom in here so you guys can see it as well.
And I can see here the distribution as it moves throughout the various values from where we have those
400 different values.
And then you click here on histograms and I can see what's really cool is this moving histogram.
And this is a really cool way to visualize your weights as they move and kind of center on some particular
values.
But again this is T.F. summary for histograms.
So essentially summarize them just to review that you call T.F. but some read the histogram you pass
and the name of what you want.
This particular one to be called in this case we called it moving mean.
And so if you come over here it relates as moving mean.
And then we can end up doing is merging all of them.
So you can have several histograms one for your biases one for your weights and you can check out all
those examples in the documentation.
All right so those are the basics of using tensor board.
Definitely check out the documentation.
There's lots of useful links there for you.
I'm going to just bring it in real quick so you can see it over here at my browser so you'll notice
that if you go to tensor flowed or slash get started.
Slash Well if you just go to get started here you'll notice there's lots of Tauriel.
But at the very end there's three full tensor board tutorial so visualizing learning of tensor board
there's also this great video here that's kind of really popular on YouTube where they discuss how tensor
board works.
They can come over here.
It'll give you more information.
There's also T.F. That's somebody that's scaler so you can do things like plot out your last throughout
time.
Summary operations etc..
It has tons of example code and it's relatively easy to understand now that you understand how to work
with tensor flow.
It's essentially just calling a summary scalar or summary histogram or summary file writer to whatever
you want to save.
So you can check out that visually like visualizing learning to Tauriel that's the main one.
And then there's also things like Graph visualization which you've actually basically already covered
so you can have those operations those nodes and then there's also the histogram dashboard which you
also basically cover it already for you.
All right.
So check that out.
It's a lot of fun to play with.
You won't use it too much throughout this course because we're really focused on learning tensor flow.
This is a really cool way to visualize and makes us feel look really pretty but it won't be the actual
main focus of a lot of our projects throughout the course.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.