Welcome everyone to the section on generative adversarial networks or Gannes Ga.
So it's time to learn about the Ganor generative adversarial network and they were first reported in
2014 from Ian Goodfellow as well as his other co-authors working the same lab.
So as you can tell this is a really new technology and it's a really exciting technology in the space
of deep learning.
Gannes basically have the capability to generate new samples similar to the data they were trained on.
So for example they can create new faces after being trained on a large data set of real faces so they
will actually generate faces that mimic a real person's face.
So they've been able to achieve some incredible results here we can see that just after a few training
a pox the network is actually able to after being trained on images of faces begin to generate its own
faces.
Now the pocks and even after one of the POCs you can definitely tell here that these aren't real people
they're kind of distorted images but some of the latest results from Invidia.
And this is from basically late October 2017 so very very recent results as far as the filming of this
presentation.
These are fake celebrities that a network has generated.
So none of these people are actually real.
The network itself generated these images and they look very convincing.
If you start looking closely you can tell that certain things are off.
But this is really incredible work from the latest results of Invidia.
So let's go over the general idea of how Gannes work we're going to end up to create again build two
networks a generator and a discriminator.
And these networks basically compete against each other.
So the classic analogy for Ganns is the forger versus the detective.
So you have a forger trying to forge paintings and make them real enough that the detective won't notice
and you can think of the forger as a generator and the detective as the discriminator.
So you have these two networks a generator which we have here in that little blue box and the discriminating
network in that little like pink orange box and they're competing against each other.
And basically what happens is the generator makes fake data to pass discriminator So the discriminator
also sees real data that is real images.
So for example real images of paintings or real images of faces.
And it predicts if the data received is real or fake and the generator is being trained to try to fool
the discriminator it wants the output data to look as close as possible to real data and the discriminator
is trained to figure out which data is real and which data is fake and what ends up happening is that
the generator learns to make data that's indistinguishable from your old data to this cremator.
So if we follow this kind of example here starting from the top we have some real data and we take in
some sample data from the real ceps in this case like a real painting and we show that the discriminator
criminal choses side whether it's real or fake that's been trained on real data.
Then we have latent data.
So that can start off as random noise that we feed into the generator and the generator is then trying
to fool the discriminator.
So Ill slowly generate pretty poor examples trying to mimic the real data.
And as it gets tradeoff off to trying to basically fool discriminator it gets better and better.
So the latest sample is basically a random vector that the generator is using to construct fake images.
And as the generator learns through training it can figure out how to map these random vectors to recognizable
images that can fool the discriminator.
And it doesn't actually have to be just images images or the most famous example of Ganns.
They can also do things like using gas to try to generate for instance audio data.
So eventually after a lot of training and usually a lot of tuning of hyper parameters that generator
will hopefully be able to generate examples that are indistinguishable from the real data.
Now putting out again can actually be relatively simple you're just essentially making two networks
that we've done a lot in the past and we're going to use the T.F. layers API to make that even simpler
for us.
So it's just a discriminator network and then a generator network well isn't really simple is the tuning
of the hyper parameters and the training time involved so let's briefly discuss some potential problems
that occur with Gannes one potential problem is the discriminator over powering the generator.
So sometimes the discriminator.
Remember that's the network that's trying to tell whether or not something's real or fake from the generator.
It can sometimes begin to classify every single generated example as fake.
So what you may want to do to fix that is have a discriminator output be unskilled instead of a sigmoid.
Because remember the sigmoid function returns something that's always 0 and 1 are between 0 and 1.
And that may cause discriminator to just shut everything down to zero and have it all be called fake
or false examples.
There's also another problem that's known as moed collapse and that's where the generator discover some
sort of weakness in the discriminator.
Maybe if a certain section of an image has red pixels on it that discriminator automatically says it's
real.
And what ends up happening is the general just keeps sending the same image over and over again because
it basically found this little trick to fool discriminators some sort of weird potential weakness and
the generator is basically continually producing a similar example regardless of whatever variation
you provide it.
And it's let latent sample input.
So the one way you can know if that's happening is if your generator as you check it keeps producing
the same data over and over again.
One way to fix this is you can try to adjust the training rate maybe slow it down a little bit.
Or you can even change the layers of the discriminator in an attempt to make the discriminator better
at detecting a real sample versus fake sample to avoid that potential weakness.
Now keep in mind this technology is extremely new.
It was just published in 2014 and the latest techniques are constantly being published like we just
saw that invidia paper was just published as far as the time of this filming.
Less than a few weeks ago now realistically if you're serious about Gannes only a GP power computer
is going to be able to handle the training of again in a reasonable amount of time.
That's not to say for simple problems a CPA you won't be able to handle it.
A CPA can't handle it.
It's just going to take a really long time we'll have to probably wait hours or days for a really simple
problem.
If you're just running it on C.P. you now with more complicated problems such as generating those faces
we just saw really good news.
The only realistic way to do it.
And even then if you have a really strong GPU for some problems it can take a really long time like
days two weeks for certain data types.
So keep that in mind.
This is really going to be limited by your hardware as far as what problems you can tackle.
So if your locally limited to kind of mediocre hardware you may want to look for a service online that
allows you to access higher power GPS use.
So we're going to do now is code out the most famous example of again and that is creating again that
generates numbers based off the data set.
So we're going to hop straight into that in the very next lecture.
Thanks and I'll see you there.