Welcome everyone to part one of our code along we're going to create a generative adversarial network
to generate this data digits.
Let's go ahead and open up a notebook and get started.
All right let's start of our imports will do tensor flow of course as T.F. and then we're also going
to be using pi and we'll be plotting out just a little bit just see what the numbers look like.
So let's go ahead and import pipeline and we'll say map lib in line.
OK.
So let's go and grab our data.
Remember senseful has a really nice function that allows you to quickly grab the data as you say from
examples tutorials and just import input data
and then we're going to say this is equal to input underscored data and we're going to say read data
sets and I'm going to pass in the exact file path from the notebook.
That way I don't accidently read download all the data.
So I'm just going to copy and paste this to make sure I don't mess it up here.
There we go.
So I'm gonna grab it again from the convolutional neural networks and this dataset.
When you run this you should only see extracting if you're running this in the same folder as the notebook
expect.
So keep that in mind though you don't need to download everything again.
So a quick review remember if we want to show the data you can say this just training.
And then there's images here and you can grab just a summary in the image here so whatever is the 12th
index the image and then you need to reshape it to a 28 by 28 pixel run that and that should show you
whatever image it is in this case it's a 1.
So if we took out another image then this one looks like a 2 or 9.
This one's a 7.
Clearly.
OK.
And then remember that we can also say See map so it can say grace here just to see the actual white
background.
All right.
Now it's time to actually build out the networks the first network we're going to start with is the
generator network and then we're going to create the discriminated network for both these networks we're
going to create what's called a variable scope.
So let's first start with some functions.
So we're going to create a generator function that we can easily call it.
It takes Z as an input as he is going to be that random noise that we start the generator with and then
it's going to have this redos variable that will explain later on when we talk about the variable scope.
So we'll say with T.F. variable underscore scope we're going to pass in a string code here.
If you shift tab you can see that there's a name or scope piercing and passenger string code will say
GM for generator.
And they're going to say reuse is equal to reuse.
So you can either set this reuse as one or later on you're going to see is all set it as true.
So you might be wondering well what is this variable scope for.
Well the goal of variable scopes in general is to allow you to basically have modular sections or subsets
of parameters so those belonging to certain layers that way when an architecture of a layer is repeated.
So when you call this generator function again the same names of those variables can be used within
each layer scope.
That's going to make a little more sense when we actually see how we use this function because we're
going to be using it over and over again.
So keep that in mind that we're going to be using this variable's scope and this reuse.
We're going to pass in later to be true.
So what kind of touch on that later on right now will set the hidden layer for society of.
And it's going to be a dense layer so densely connected.
The inputs here is just going to be that random noise Z that will create later on and the number of
units will just say 128 as we did before.
When dealing with the state digits data set and then what we're going to do here is for our hidden layer
the activation function we're going to be using is a leaky rectified linear unit So remember we talked
about leaky rectified linear units we're talking about various activation functions.
Unfortunately tensor flow in 1.3 still doesn't actually have a leaky rectified linear unit.
And if you look this up on Stack Overflow let me bring in the link real quick.
You'll get something like this where someone's asking well how can you use a leaky rectified linear
unit.
And there's a couple of good answers here.
Let me zoom in so you can see this.
If you take a look one of them actually just defines the full function here.
And then another person has a really clever solution where you just use T.F. that maximum X or versus
Alpha times X where you choose that Alpha basically essentially the leak rate of that leaky rectified
linear unit.
And this is a lot more efficient to use so we're going to be using that.
And you'll notice at the very last post answered pretty recently is that there's going to be a leaky
rectified linear unit upon the release of 1.4 which at the time of this filming isn't out yet and the
environment we provide is not using 1.4.
So eventually in the future you'll just be able to pasan TFA and that leaky rectified linear unit as
the activation function here.
Because remember for these layers if you do shift tab here there's going to be an activation option.
OK so let's go ahead and do the maximum method.
If we come back here we're going to be using this maximum Athen to simulate the activation function.
So let's come over here and start typing that out.
So we're going to choose an alpha of 0.01 for Aliki rectified linear unit and then we're going to do
that kind of maximun logic here so I'll say T.F. maximum and we get to say Alpha times hit in one or
hit and one says it's just going to choose the maximum out of that.
And then we're going to do another hit and we'll say hit and Larry to again that's going to be T.F.
layers that really connected the inputs for this one is going to be the up or hit in one and we'll have
this be 120 units again and again something being play around of how many units you want.
He wanted to you could have a really really large network if you wanted very good generation results
but 128 should be more than fine.
In fact you can kind of play around with if you only want one hidden layer but let's say hit insue now
is going to be the same thing T.F. maximum and it will be Alpha times it into or hit into whichever
one's maximum there.
OK finally we're going to have our output and that's going to be T.F. layer's that's connected will
take in it and layer 2.
And then the units here.
Because as the output.
And we're actually generating a new picture.
We're going to have the full 28 by 28.
So we expect 784 to be our output here because we're actually trying to generate that vector image.
And then the activation function when kind of playing around with this I notice that the hyperbolic
tangent tended to work better than a sigmoid.
So we'll go ahead and set up our network to use that.
So say 10 H there.
And later on you'll see that we're passing in random noise instead of going from zero to 1.
We're going to go from negative 1 to 1.
Just like the hyperbolic tangent does.
And then finally we're going to return the output.
OK so that is our generator function.
We're going to do something really similar for our discriminator murmured the discriminator is going
to try to tell whether something is real or fake from the generator.
So let's go ahead and make this a discriminator and this is not going to take in Z.
Instead it's going to take in data X but we'll have this for use.
And instead of Jeon here we'll go ahead and say yes for the discriminator hit and one that's going to
be the same thing except the inputs here is going to be X we'll go ahead and do the leaky rectified
linear unit using this method of Alpha.
So this is going to be the same.
This is again going to be the same we'll have to hit in later here and at the very end the set of this
activation function being a hyperbolic tangent we just want to know.
True or false.
Is it a real data point or not.
So we're going to do is separate this out into two steps to say logic's themselves see a Flair's thence
pass and head into and say units is equal to just 1 because we basically want the probability of it
being real or fake.
And then also the output is T.F. sigmoid of the logic's.
OK so that's our scrimmage there.
So now we have these two functions that we're going to be able to quickly call upon when we want to
build out our generators and discriminators.
OK.
So in the very next lecture we're going to do is begin to actually use these functions along with some
placeholders and then define a loss function as well as the optimizer.
I'll see at the next lecture.