OK here we are where we left off last time.
Last time we created our generator function and our discriminator function.
Now it's time to do a little bit of setup as far as placeholders losses and optimizers.
So let's start off with the placeholders.
So we're going to create two placeholders one for the real images that we're going to be passing into
the discriminator and then one for z are basically the noise that we're going to pass into the generator.
So we'll say really images is a placeholder.
So it's a placeholder and it's just floating point 32 and the shape it's going to be none because that's
defined by how large that batches.
And then there's 784 pixels.
Hopefully this feels pretty familiar given that you have used this dataset before in the convolutional
neural networks section then for Z we're going to do as well say T.F. placeholder will say to float
32.
And the shape here again none for the batch size and we'll go ahead and feed our generator a vector
of 100 random points.
So once we have that we're going to go ahead and create an instance of regenerator so we'll say gee
is generator not really an instance more like calling the function and then we pasan placeholder there.
So we have a generator we're passing in this Z which eventually we're going to pass in a feed function
because remember generator if we look up here.
It's just a bunch of layers that eventually returns the output are passing in that placeholder for the
actual noise.
And later on we'll pass in a feed dictionary that feeds in that noise.
So generators pretty straightforward.
Now it's time for the discriminator and for discriminator where we're going to do here is we're going
to edit this function a little bit so that we don't just return the output but we also return these
long bits here.
So let's go and do that run that again make sure you ran that and we're going to need to have two discriminators
because remember we want to run the discriminator first on the real images so that the discriminator
is actually trained on real images and understands what the real data set looks like that way once you
start feeding it the generated images that are generators actually trying to fool discriminator with
it's been trained on real data and understands what it should look like.
So we're going to say the output real.
So this is the real output and then we'll say the logic is real and we're calling them real because
we're going to call that discriminator function and pasand the real images placeholder.
OK so we have the output and the logic for the discriminator pasand the real images.
So it's going to learn on the real images then we're going to do is say output fake.
So we're going to call these Lodge's fake as well because this is going to be the discriminator except
you're passing in the results of that generator.
So say Gee and because of this we need to say reuse equals.
True because if I just do this you end up getting a value error.
So if you scroll down here if you try to run this all again what's going to happen it says hey this
variable kernel already exists and that's disallowed.
Did you mean to set re-uses equal to true in the variable scope.
And that's why when we came up here we had to say re-uses equal to true.
So that's where we had a set that variable scope because since we're running a discriminator essentially
twice we need to be able to reuse those same variable names that we've been kind of assigning here.
So when we need to say here is reuse is equal to true and that's going to take care of that issue.
So that was kind of the main point of creating these scopes in order to be able to reuse a lot of the
variable names and that the string is also going to come in handy later when we create a list of all
the variables or building out our graph OK.
So that's a discriminator notice has returning returning the output in the logic's because we're going
to use buffer those for the losses.
So let's go ahead and get some losses here.
So I'll say losses and I'm going to define a basic loss function.
So I'll say the loss function takes some logic and some labels in and it's going to return we'll say
T.F. reduce mean and we're going to say sigmoid crossed entropy the floor is that he used before and
then we'll just say here Blodgett's equals largest and labels equals
labels in.
OK so this is almost like a helper function that just basically wrote this function.
So I don't have to constantly write reduce mean and sigmoid cross entropy.
All right.
So let's actually start calculating the losses of the use of this last function.
The first one will do is the discriminator loss when it's trained on the real data.
So that's going to be called the underscore real loss.
So the calculated loss when it's being trained on the real data.
So we'll call her last function and then we need to passen the logic and the labels.
So we already know the lodge's here.
Remember that's just right here at the lodge It's also can it pass that in.
And then the second one or the actual labels.
So recall that the discriminator here is not trying to be a neural network trained to the tech what
number it's being presented.
It's not trying to tell whether that number is 7 3 or 2 all discriminator is trying to really understand
is is the image being presented to the discriminator network something that a real human being wrote.
Or is it something that someone like a computer is trying to pass off as a handwritten digit.
So when we train on the real data we want all the labels to be true.
So what we can do is say T.F. ones and if we take a look at the documentation for T.F. ones by doing
shift tab here and scroll down.
This creates a sensor with all the elements set to one.
However it takes an A shape argument.
There's a more convenience and for our case here.
T.F. ones like which again creates a tensor of all elements set to one.
But you can pass in a straight tensor so you don't need to worry about the shape.
So that's a little more flexible.
So we'll go ahead and use that will say T.F. ones like.
And we know the shape it needs is the same as tensor right here.
So we'll just copy and paste that in.
So that is the labels.
Now there's one thing we're going to do here that's called smoothing.
Right now this discriminator is passing in ones as the labels which makes sense we're going to pass
that one through a sigmoid function that's going to stay as one.
And then basically everything stays true what we want to do here is so that discriminator isn't so well
to make the discriminator a little more generalized.
What we can do is apply smoothing.
So this helps discriminate generalize better.
And basically it just means that you reduce the labels a bit from being perfect 1.0 to being something
like 0.9.
So you can just easily multiply by 0.9 to apply that smoothing factor.
OK.
So we'll go ahead and do that.
And let's continue on to do something similar for the fake data we'll say fake loss is equal to the
last function that we find earlier and will passen the lot it's fake copy and paste that in.
And now it's that of ones we're just going to say these are zeros because we know these are all fake.
So now we're going to say the loss for training on fake data is this.
The logic's and this can actually be real as well.
It can be fake it doesn't really matter here.
So run those two and then we'll say the loss is equal to here.
Lips The real loss plus the fake Clauss right.
So that's a total discriminator loss.
And then the generally the loss is pretty straightforward you're just going to call the loss function.
And we can pass an lips the logic of the fake and then I will say T.F. ones like because we know wants
to be true.
So I'll say T.F. this can be Lodge's fake.
Ok so now we have both our discriminator discriminated a loss by both the real loss and the loss and
then the generator loss.
Now let's go ahead and define the optimizers.
We'll go ahead and give this a learning rate of Precilla learning right.
0.00 one if you start going too fast.
Basically just get a bunch of noise out from the generator.
Keep in mind as we always say a slower learning rate means training time is going to take longer.
So we're going to have to optimizers here.
One for the discriminator trainer and one for the generator trainer.
And in order to do that we need to basically create a list of the variable names.
So I'm going to copy and paste some lines of code here.
And you typically really only do this sort of thing when you're dealing with multiple networks that
are going to be interacting to each other.
But you're right to call trainable variables from tensor or flow.
And this just returns all the variables that were created and by default when you create these variables
they say trainable is equal to true.
So we have all these variables that were created and then inside their names some of them are going
to have details and some of them will how g n.
And that's because of the variable scope we passed in that string code here that if your member for
variable scope is the name.
So we'll come back down here and the using list comprehension we're gonna grab every variable for every
variable in these trainable variables.
If either D.S. for discriminators name or GDNF generator is in that name and then we have two separate
lists of the variables.
So now that we have that we can go ahead and create our two optimizers.
So say the trainer is equal to T.F. train I will use an atom optimizer here use the learning rate and
then we'll just call the minimize function here.
So we want to minimize the discriminator loss and the variable list that we're going to pasan is only
the discriminator variables.
Whoops.
Learning rates.
OK so that's our discriminator trainer.
We're going to do a very similar thing for the generator trainer.
So we'll see CEF train Adam optimizer pass are learning right.
And then again minimize and now we're going to minimize the generator loss and the variable list is
going to be equal to those generator variables.
And if you want to explore those lists look like you can just do this and I'll tell you that it's a
list of the variables you can see here.
Kernel zero bias colonel by bias Colonel.
Now we didn't have to do a lot of this work because this is essentially all done by the layers API.
So just keep that in mind.
All right so now we successfully have created our losses and then our optimizers.
So we're all ready to go the next step is to just essentially train the session.
So let's go ahead and do that in the next lecture.