Welcome back everyone.
Now it's time to continue our project here by actually creating the training session.
So we're going to create a few variables that the training session is going to use.
We can say that size will say that's equal to 100.
And then it POCs That's how many fool runs it does through the training data.
Now definitely more POCs means you're going to get better results from that generator.
But keep in mind that Gannes in general take a really long time to train.
So we've actually already ran on a very high powered GPS view.
This same session or graph that we're actually going to construct right now for 500 epochs and you can
grab that saved model and play around with it and see what results it's generating.
So right now we'll kind of keep things light we'll do 30 POCs although to really get good results you
should be doing plus 100 you.
So we'll do 30 full runs through training data and then we'll see in it is equal to say T.F. global
variables initialiser so we initialize all the variables and then we can also create a saver function
if we want to save it.
I won't do any saving right now.
So last thing I do is say samples is equal to an empty list and I'm going to save it.
An example sample of what the generators actually producing per epoch.
So at the end there's going to be 30 example images in this list.
OK so let's create the session will say with T.F. session as SPSS we first need to initialize those
variables will say run and it then we're going to say for every epoch and range of POCs that we just
defined we'll do the following.
First we're going to use classic division not true division to figure out how many rounds do I need
to do batches to actually go through all the training data.
So the number of batches are going to be using is going to be equal to this train.
The total number of examples two forward slashes for classic division not true division divided by the
batch size.
That's basically going to give us a whole number indicating how many batches for if you have each batch
be 100 images.
How many of those batches does it take to go through all the training examples which is as we know one
IPAC.
So then we're going to say for I in arr. of the number of batches we need to perform We're going to
grab a batch of data.
So say this training data grab the next batch and it's going to be defined by the size that we're going
to get the images and we're going to reshape and rescale them to pass them into the discriminator.
So we'll say the batch images is equal to batch index that 0.
And then we're going to reshape it and we'll reshape it to be batch size by 784
and then we're going to take that same things or say batch images is that images.
And then we're going to multiply by 2 and subtract one from that
an operation that's linear transformation basically allows us to rescale everything so that it makes
sense for the hyperbolic tangent activation function that discriminator network is going to be using.
So speaking of that we're going to create some noise will say batch Z is equal to and that's where we're
going to use some PI.
We're going to create some random uniform noise that goes from negative 1 to 1 just like the hyperbolic
tangent function and the sizes that will be defined by the batch size.
So in our case 100 and we'll go ahead and say 100 by 100 here.
OK so now we're going to run the optimizers and we're not actually going to save any of their outputs.
Really we're just going to run them and then the output that we really care about is the generator output.
So we'll go ahead and do that later on.
So we're going to say a session run and we're just using an underscore here because we're not really
saving any of their outputs to any variables because we don't really care about them.
We're going to have the scrimmaging your trainer and then we're going to have a feed dictionary here
in the dictionary it's going to be two things are passing in number we have the placeholders for the
real images.
Now we're going to pass and Bachche images that we just defined earlier and then we also have the Z
placeholder here.
So we'll see that Z and then we're going to do a very similar thing session run and this is going to
be for a trainer feed dictionary and this is just going to take in some noise that Z.
OK so that's running the optimizers.
And then we're going to line it up with the IPAC for a loop.
Well Line it up really of this for loop.
But make sure it's on this level.
So with this indentation we're then going to say go ahead and prints on e Poch and then we'll just say
format IPAC.
Make sure this is not in this for loop otherwise you'll see this printed.
Well way too many times OK.
Then we're going to do is we're going to get a sample from the generator as retraining so of say sample
Z is equal to the random uniform.
So we're going to pass on some noise here.
The size we're just going to say one by 100 because of the batch size is 100 in one because I just want
one sample basically just one piece of data so that ran the noise and then we're going to grab a generated
sample from our generator.
So we'll say a session run by that generator function passen Z here.
Because that's the placeholder.
And then we're going to do is say reuse is equal to true.
And then finally we will define the feed dictionary and the feed dictionary.
Z is just going to be that samples Z that we just created.
All right so we have samples out there and then we're going to append that generated sample to the list
of samples.
OK.
And then here if you wanted to you could save the model with you down to the note book you'll notice
that's commented out so you don't risk XLE overwriting the model that we have for you.
We don't need to read anything.
OK.
So pretty simple session.
All we're doing here is we're going to be running through this.
We have our batch images.
We're training those Herminator training in the generator as well.
And then every single epoch we're just going to run 30 of them we're going to save an example image
so hopefully they start off pretty noisy and they get better and better.
So the generator should at the very end the 30 POCs do something that sort of looks like a number 30
really isn't enough yet.
Definitely check out that 500 IPAC model that we provide for you if you really want to see good samples.
Let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure we have no typos here.
We should eventually see something like it says on the zero name.
Size is not defined so let's check what the alignment is on a size Sirico will say size equals run that
again.
And hopefully you have no typos.
Let's make sure on IPAC zero.
You know what we should eventually see on IPAC one.
OK so this is running now.
This will take a while to run.
Keep in mind I'm still running this on a very powerful GPU right here on a Nvidia type next.
So it's running very fast and even with that it's going to take a while.
So I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done training for 30 bucks.
All right so it's finished training.
So let's go ahead and see how it performs.
If we take a look at those samples it's going to be a list of pictures at least present as an array.
So let's go ahead and take one of those.
So the very first one right here we can check out its shape.
It's one by 784 So we want to reshape this to be an actual image so we'll say 28 by 28 and then we'll
say peel t show and we see what is essentially just noise.
So you can keep going further and further into time see see it it's a little less noisy and second or
30 Poch really if you're coming 0 indexing and you can keep going.
So let's go in and jump to 10 and see how it performs still pretty noisy will jump to 20.
See that performs still kind of noisy.
Can see trying to get some shape.
So let's see 30 prox the very 29.
I mean because we're starting indexing zero and see how that one is performing.
So you can see here that it's actually starting to perform a little better starting to look like a number
maybe twenty eight you can see here a little less noise because if we compare this to what the very
first one looked like at 0 you can see here it's a lot noisier.
All right so we could see with 30 epochs we were getting some improvement but we still haven't actually
seen that generator create something that looks like a real human hand written digit.
But luckily we've already ran a model for you on a powerful GPU for 500 pocks.
So let's go ahead and load that up first.
We're going to do here is a saver is equal to T.F. train saver.
Now we can pass any variable list parameter that allows us to link it to the generator variable list
that we had earlier.
So now we have the Savir Let's go ahead and create a session C-f session as SPSS and then we'll say
saver and we're going to restore the session and then the file path leps is going to be from the notes.
Let me grab that real quick.
Should be the models folder as a checkpoint file.
So I get that passed in there so we're going to restore that.
And then we're going to run the same code that we ran up here.
As far as changing a sample something to copy this sample sample copy that bring that down here.
Let's go ahead and generate five of these samples.
So we'll say new samples is an empty list LC for x in range 5.
We're going to do here is create these two samples are really just one sample.
So we'll create five random samples with this 500 IPAC model and then we will see new samples and we're
going to append that generated sample.
OK so let's run this and see how it performs and let's check out those new samples.
We'll grab those new samples and we'll grab one of them here.
We're going to need to reshape it to be 20 by 20 and let's say peel t show this and you can see here
at the really looks way more like a number.
So you can see here this looks like nine.
So check out what else was able to generate that kind of looks like a number seven.
You can see here it's maybe a little less clear to this one.
Obviously trying to create something that looks like a 9 3 0 here that one is not too bad.
And then four also kind of looking like a 9.
So you can see it's not just learning a particular number it's able to generate a lot of them.
All right.
So that's how you can use the model that we provided for you.
You can just run the note book theorically and then that way you don't need to kind of spend a lot of
time training your models.
OK.
Hope you enjoy this project.
Thanks everyone.