Welcome everyone to an introduction to neural networks in this section of the course we're going to
have a series of lectures that will cover key theoretical topics and aspects surrounding the neural
network model that is things like neurons percept trons activation functions as well as cost functions.
Gradient descent and back propagation once we build a general very high level understanding we're going
to code out all of these topics manually with Python without the use of a deep learning library.
Basically we're actually going to try to do is manually create a very simple version of tensor flow.
Once you've actually built this by hand manually with Python we're going to move on to using the deep
library for this course tensor flow understanding a high level overview of these key elements is really
going to make it much easier to understand what's happening.
Once we begin to use tensor flow and tensor flow has direct connections to these concepts in its syntax.
All right let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.