Welcome everyone to this lecture on an introduction to the precept Tron before we launch straight into
neural networks we understand the individual components first such as a single neuron artificial neural
networks or Amen's actually have a basis in biology.
So we're going to see how we can attempt to mimic biological neurons with an artificial neuron otherwise
known as a perception.
And then once we go through the process of how a simple perception works we'll go ahead and show you
how you can represent that mathematically.
But let's start off of a biological neuron such as a brain cell.
So the biological neuron works as in a simplified way through the following manner.
Basically you have dendrites that feed into the body of this cell.
And you can have many rights and what happens is an electrical signal gets passed through the dendrites
to the body of the cell and then later on a single output or a single electrical signal is passed on
through an axon to later on Connect to some other neuron.
And that's the basic idea we have kind of these many input Erlick of electro signals through the dendrites
goes through the body and then a single actual signal output through the axon So the artificial neuron
also has inputs and outputs so we can attempt to mimic the biological neuron.
So this simple model again is just known as a perception.
In this case we have two inputs.
So let's go ahead and see a simple example of how it can work.
So we have two inputs and a single output and we start indexing at zero so we have input of zero input
one.
So the inputs can have values of features.
So when you have your data set you're going to have various features and these features can be anything
from how many rooms a house has or how dark an image is represented by some sort of pixel amount or
some sort of Darkness number etc. So essentially Don't worry right now about what these numbers actually
represent.
Later on we're dealing with real data sets will have something more tangible.
For right now these are just arbitrary number choices.
But again we have input zero and Input 1.
So again indexing starts at zero here and we're going to assign them values of let's say 12 and 4 then
the next step is to have these inputs multiplied by some sort of way.
So we have weight zero for input zero and weight one for Input 1 and typically the weights are actually
initialized through some sort of random generation.
So you just choose a random number for these weights.
In this case we'll just go ahead and pretend that the random numbers chosen was 0.5 and negative 1.
Again the numbers here are pretty much arbitrary.
Really focus on the general process.
So now these inputs are going to be multiplied by the weights.
So that ends up looking like this.
We have 12 times 0.5 or 1 1/2 and that equals six.
And then we say four times that if one is equal to negative four the next step is to take these results
of the inputs multiplied by their respective weights and pass them into an activation function.
There's many activation functions to choose from.
Now we're going to cover this in a lot more detail later on.
For now our activation function is actually going to be very simple.
We're going to say the following.
If the some of the inputs is positive return one or output one if the sum of the inputs is negative
then output zero.
So in our case if we say six plus negative four that's the same thing as saying six minus four.
So then we get to as a result.
So since the sum of the inputs was positive the activation function returns 1 or outputs 1.
So there's a possible issue here and the issue is the following.
What is the original inputs started off as zero that any way you chose even if it was randomly chosen
multiply it by the input would still result in zero.
So if input 0 happened to be zero and if it happened to be zero as well instead of 12 and 4 then you
could have a problem.
You essentially always get out zero because zero multiplied by the way is still going to be zero.
So we can actually fix this by adding in a biased term.
And in this case we choose one.
So we're going to go ahead and add in our own biased term here plus one.
So what does this actually look like.
Mathematically Now let's quickly think about how we can represent this perception model mathematically
and it's actually quite simple.
Basically we just say the following from equals zero to n that is the number of inputs we're gonna say.
W If I were that specific wait for that input multiplied by XVI which is the input itself plus the bias
term.
And that's essentially it.
So once we have many preset trons in a network we'll see how we can easily extend this to a matrix form.
So as a quick review in this pretty simple lecture we just covered briefly the following.
We discussed in the very basic terms how biological neuron works then how that can reflect to a perception
model which is the artificial neuron and then the mathematical representation of that perception model.
Coming up next we're going to continue discussing how we can build off this perception model to build
a neural network.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.