Welcome back everyone to an introduction to neural networks.
We've seen how a single percept Trump behaves.
Now let's expand on this concept to get the idea of a neural network.
Let's see how to connect many perceptive thoughts together and how to represent this mathematically.
So what does a multiple perceptions that work actually look like.
Well essentially looks like this.
Here we can see that we have various layers of single percept trons connected to each other through
their inputs and outputs.
In this case we have an input layer all the way on the left which is purple.
We have two hidden layers and hidden layers are the layers that are in-between the input layer and all
the way on the right that output layer essentially hidden layers are layers that don't get to see the
outside.
That is all the way the inputs on the left or all the way the outputs on the right so input layers those
are real values from the data so they take in the actual data as their input.
Then you have hidden layers and those layers between the input output layers.
And if you have three or more hidden layers that's considered a deep network and then an output layer
where you have some sort of final estimate of whatever the output that you're trying to estimate is.
So as you go forwards through more layers the level of abstraction increases.
Let's not discuss the activation function in a little more detail.
Previously our activation function was just a really simple function the output 0 or 1.
Remember we were just taking the some of the inputs in that simple percept Tron model and then had an
activation function that just had an output of either or 1 based off whether that number was positive
or negative.
And if we plotted out that looks like this we can say the output is either 0 or 1 on the y axis and
then the x axis we see our marking at zero.
And if we have a negative value we output 0 and if we have a positive value we output 1 and we did this
by having the x axis B W X plus B.
That is the wait times the inputs plus that bias and it's really common to just set that equal to Z.
So you can refer to Z instead of having to constantly for two W X plus B.
So whenever I say Z I'm essentially referring to those wait times those inputs plus that buys So unfortunately
this is actually a pretty dramatic function since small changes aren't really reflected.
So you can have kind of really small changes in Z for instance the change from 0.5 and Z to 0.6.
Doesn't really matter it's still going to output one as long as it's positive or the changes that are
really dramatic from negative one to negative thousand doesn't really matter.
It's going to be zero.
So it'd be nice if we could have a more dynamic function.
For example this red line here you can see here that our outputs now are no longer just 0 or 1.
We have a little more detail to it.
There's a little more nuance here.
So lucky for us this is actually the sigmoid function.
This red line function already exists and it's known as the sigmoid function.
And they say my function is just f of x is equal to 1 over 1 plus E to the negative x and we can replace
X here with Z.
So we have Z is equal to W X plus be.
So we just take the whole thing that Z and plug it into the sigmoid function.
So we'd have f of Z is equal to 1 over 1 plus it's the negative Z.
And that would be our sieve function for the activation function so changing the activation function
used can actually be really beneficial depending on the particular task we're trying to complete.
Now we'll get into more detail on that later on when we actually implement our own that works.
Let's discuss a few more activation of functions that we're going to encounter throughout this course.
So a really common function that's used is an activation function.
Besides just one function is the hyperbolic tinge of function or 10 H or tannish of Z or Z remembers
just W X plus B and that looks really similar to the sigmoid function except note that the output can
then be from negative 1 to 1.
Unlike Previously we had zero to 1.
So if we look at the Sigma function again that went from 0 to 1 and that was equal to 1 over 1 plus
it's a negative x or negative Z whatever the input is.
And now for the Tench or hyperbolic tangent function it goes from negative 1 to 1 but still has it sort
of same behavior shape.
And if you're interested in how to express the hyperbolic tangent mathematically over here on the right
hand side or the actual equations for then there's also the rectified linear unit or r e l u.
And this is a really common activation function but it's actually relatively simple.
And the way it works is the following method you basically passing your z value into this Max equation.
So you say max of 0 or Z.
So what does that actually mean.
Well the rectified linear unit that actual activation function works the following manner.
It says based off your z value and zero.
Just return the maximum value and that actually means that if your value of z is negative then the max
between zero and any negative number is always going to be zero.
So we can see here that is z.
If it's negative the function always returns 0 and then between Max 0 comma's Z if z is positive it's
always going to return the value of z.
So essentially of just y is equal to Z here.
So on the right hand side that's where you get that sort of straight linear line.
So again relatively simple function but this is kind of considered at certain points in time state of
the art.
So we're going to definitely be seeing this activation function a lot throughout our lecturers so that
rectified linear unit and hyperbolic tangent tend to have the best performance so we're going to really
focus on these two throughout the course but deep libraries in general have these built in force.
So we don't really need to worry about having to implement these activation functions manually.
We'll essentially be able to select them from our deep learning library.
As we continue on we'll also talk about some more State of the activation functions.
But up next we're going to do is discuss cost functions which will allow us to measure how well these
neurons are actually performing.
So right now we've understood two major concepts the perception and then the activation function inside
that particular neuron.
Up next we'll discuss cost functions.
Thanks and I'll see it there.