Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to discuss cost functions we'll now explore how can we evaluate the performance of a neuron
we can use a cost function to measure how far off we are from the expected value.
So we're going to use the following variables and notation.
Let's quickly review this so you don't get confused when we actually see the cost functions we'll use
the variable y to represent the true value and we'll use the variable A to represent the neurons prediction.
So what does this actually mean in terms of weights and biases.
Well remember that we said W times x that is the wait times the input plus the bias is equal to Z.
And remember that we pass Z into the activation function.
So for example if we're using the sigmoid function we could say that sigma of Z is equal to A.
So that neurons prediction when we actually put in the some of those weights times the inputs plus those
biased terms we get the Z and then we can pass that in to the activation function sigma of Z and that
is equal to A.
Which at the end of represents the neurons prediction.
So the first cost function we're going to discuss is the quadratic cost function and that is equal to
the sum of y minus a squared divided by.
And you can if you want pull out one over.
And so what do we actually see here.
Well we can see that larger errors are more prominent due to squaring because remember why is that true
value and A's are predictive value.
So if there's a big difference there when we square it's going to really be prominent now.
Unfortunately when you actually implement this quadratic costs function this coloration could cause
a slowdown in our learning speed to the way that formulaically it actually works.
So instead we're going to be using cross entropy as our cost function.
And this is defined in the following manner we say negative 1 over and and then we take the sum of Y
times the log a plus one minus Y times the log of 1 minus a.
And this actual cost function allows for faster learning.
And the reason for that is the following.
The larger the difference between y and a D faster than your on ends up actually learning due to this
cross and should be cost function.
So that means that if we end up at the beginning for really large difference between our predicted value
and the true value we can essentially quickly jump forward using this cost function because the larger
the difference the faster Nero is going to learn.
So now that we have these two key aspects of learning of general networks the neurons of their activation
function and the cost function.
We're still missing a key step and that's the actual learning process.
So we need to figure out how we can use our neurons and the measurements of our air our cost function
basically a measurement of how wrong we are and then attempt to correct our prediction.
In other words actually learn.
So again so far we understand the neurons the precept trons how we can link them together to get a neural
net and then we also understand now that we have these cost functions that are essentially measurements
of how off we are how wrong we are what our error in general is.
So now that we have these two components we need to understand well how to actually fix that error and
we're going to do in the next lecture we're going to briefly cover how we can do this with gradient
descent which is probably a term you've heard before.
If you've ever read anything on machine learning.
OK let's go ahead and discuss gradient descent in the next lecture.
I'll see it there.