Welcome back everyone to this lecture on gradient descent and back propagation.
If you've dabbled in machine learning before or if you've even looked at some online articles you've
probably already heard of the term grading the sense.
Let's quickly go over a high level overview and then discuss back propagation gradient descent is an
optimization algorithm for finding the minimum of a function which is useful to us because we want to
minimize that cost function.
So to find a local minimum we take steps proportional to the negative of the gradient.
Let's go ahead and go through a very simple example in just one dimension.
So basically what we have here is our cost on the y axis so the result of that cost function and then
on the x axis we have a particular way that we're trying to choose.
So remember we end up choosing a random weight in the beginning.
So let's say that Bluepoint initiate that ran the weight that we chose and we want to somehow choose
a weight that's going to minimize that cost and we can see here just visually when they mention.
That's basically at the bottom of that parabola so the weight gradient descent works in just a high
level overview is that you end up taking the gradient which we know is a derivative of the function
at that point and then seeing which way it goes in the negative direction and then we end up taking
step by step.
A The sense along that gradient until we finally see that we get that minimum cost.
So we see here just visually what the parameter values to choose to minimize our cost is.
So finally this minimum is really simple for one dimension but our cases are going to have a lot more
parameters.
So we're not going to do that visually or with such a simple diagram.
Meaning we're going to need to use built in linear algebra libraries that are deep learning library
will provide using greened the sense we can figure out the best parameters for minimizing our cost.
So for example find the best values for the weights of the neuron inputs and we're going to go a lot
more into the mathematics hungry in the sense when we actually go through the math example.
So now we just have one issue to solve and that is how can we quickly adjust the optimal parameters
or weights across our entire network.
In that one example we just showed for a single weight.
But what if we want to actually go and then fix all the weights or adjust all the weights for the entire
network.
And that's we're back propagation comes in basically back propagation is used to calculate the air contribution
of each year on after a batch of data is processed and it relies heavily on the chain rule from calculus
to go back through the network and calculate these errors.
And the way back propagation works it calculates the air at the output and then distributes back through
the network layers and it requires a known desired output for each input value.
Remember that supervised learning needs some sort of comparison to actually get that error.
So the implementation of back propagation is going to be further clarified when we dive into the math
example because it really relies heavily on the chain rule and the river lives.
And it's not something that really works of sleights.
So instead what kind of show you by hand how this entire process works.
But now that we finished off our very high level overview of the theory behind your own that works let's
go ahead and get a quick discussion of tensor Flo's playground which is a really fun Web site that allows
you to kind of visually see a lot of the aspects we've been talking about through the last previous
lectures.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.