Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the tensor flow playground.
So we're going to be able to actually visualize and play around a lot of the topics we've been discussing.
Go ahead and open your browser and go to playground tensor float dot org and hop over to my browser
and explain what we're looking at.
OK.
Here in that playground that sensor float.
And it's this really awesome site that allows you to really visualize a lot of the topics we've been
discussing about neural networks.
Let me explain a couple of the aspects that are on this Web site.
So you start off over here on the left hand side with the data you want to use.
You have various data sets in right now.
If you go over here you can select classification or regression.
We'll go ahead and just do classification for now.
You'll notice that you have various datasets you can choose or you're trying to classify between orange
points and blue points so you can click here to get it that it looks like this or more complicated spiral
dataset or just two clusters etc..
So let's go ahead and choose this default dataset which is kind of a rim or a ring of orange points.
And then in the center we have these blue points.
You can also affect the ratio training to test data.
We're going to keep a 50/50.
And you can also make the test data or training data and noisier.
So you can add some noise to this.
You can see there are more mixed up but I'll go ahead and bring this down to zero.
Basically what it was and you can also play out the batch size.
So the actual batches that are going to fit in then once you've done it the data you can move on to
the features that you want to actually fit in.
They see the properties they want to fit into your neural network.
Here we can just see that we have the X1 which is kind of this horizontal separation between Orange
and Blue.
And if you hover over it you can see it on the right hand side towards the output and then X2 kind of
this vertical separation etc..
Just trying to use these two features and let the neurons learn how to use those features on your dataset
to separate out into two classes.
Let's go ahead and make this just a really simple neural network it's going to have one hidden layer
and we're going to have this be just one simple neuron.
In fact let's go ahead or just feet in one feature.
So refeeding and one feature this kind of horizontal separator and then it goes into one neuron so let's
go ahead and train on the simple singular feature into just a single neuron to see or output.
And as you may likely predict that this isn't going to be such a great classifier because we have a
single neuron and a single input but we can see a lot of the stuff that we've been discussing over here
on the output.
You can see in black you have the test lost so lost is kind of just another word for that cost or costs
function that we discussed zero Test loss and then you can also see a loss on the training data in great
can kind of see how they compared to each other.
And then over here on the top let's go it imposes epoxies just the number of times we kind of feed in
this data through on your own network.
You can see our learning rate or activation functions you can kind of play around these.
So we have different activation functions that we've discussed.
Right now we're using hyperbolic tangent.
Then we also have regularization we haven't really talked about that yet so I kind of leave them as
none and zero.
And you can also clarify the problem type.
So let's go ahead and play around with this and try to make a more complicated neural network.
Well go ahead and take in two features and then let's say we'll go from three neurons and then two neurons
and see how this performs.
So we're going to then run this and hopefully now we're going to see a much better performance.
And you can see here we are just visually almost getting to the point where we're correctly classifying
and of all these blue points and those orange points.
So in order to fix this well we can do is try adding some more neurons or play around the hidden layers.
But let me go out and posit here to show you what these lines represent.
So right here these lines represent the outputs from either the features or a neuron into the next year
on.
So here we have a kind of dense network because every neuron is connected to every other neuron the
next layer.
And if you hover over these you can see that they have weights to them.
So you can actually click on this and then adjust the weights yourself.
You can play around with that.
It is here I can adjust weights to maybe like 0.8 one and see how that performs etc..
But also remember we discuss bias.
And if you click on a neuron here there's a little tiny square and that's actually the biased term.
So everything that we've been discussing so far is actually visualised here we can see the weights these
inputs from one you're on to another.
The biases and the thicker the line that means the higher the weight.
So really great visualization a really fun tool to work with.
Let's go in and see if we can improve on this.
I'm going to add in one more hidden layer and let's add in kind of three neurons on these guys.
Let's see if we run this if we get better results.
Slimmy reset this.
And let's run this again.
OK.
We can kind of begin to see that.
Yeah really fitting the data well in our test losses essentially zero and are trading losses 0.
So essentially now we have kind of this perfect classifier.
And what's really cool is if we pause this we can kind of see individually each of the neurons are doing
and notice as we continue on through our network we get higher and higher levels of abstraction until
the final.
And you can see here that essentially one of these neurons is doing all the work and we really get the
shape of the Heisler abstraction which are essentially that circle in the middle versus kind of that
spiral on the outside.
So let's go ahead and test this on a much more complicated dataset such as this spiral data set.
So if we run this notice here that even though we performed really well on that previous dataset with
this much more complicated dataset it's not able to really classify it that well you can see here it's
kind of struggling to get in that spiral shape.
So it's trying to really learn and test it against the training data.
But notice here we're still really not there.
So let's go ahead and see what we can do to improve this.
So I will pause this is something we may need to do is just add and more hidden layers.
Remember we can also change or activation function.
So we're going to change this to kind of that rectified linear unit and let's go ahead and just kind
of go crazy here at a bunch of more neurons.
This something can really play around with.
So let's get in five hidden layers.
Why not.
I'm really kind of choosing these arbitrarily to see how this works.
I remember the more nuance more layers.
The longest is going to take so I'm going to add in kind of four Sogo 6 6 6 6 4 you can really play
around with this however you want but let's go ahead and run this now.
Again more hidden layers.
It's going to take a lot more as far as training time.
You can kind of see here Test loss is slowly decreasing.
Seems like it's plateauing.
And then we kind of get a breakthrough here and it's kind of struggling but you can see here it's really
trying its best to make out that spiral shape.
So even with the rectified linear unit activation and all these hidden layers we can sell that still
a really hard problem to solve but is trying its best to get into that spiral shape.
So I'm going to kind of go to the max here.
So let me pause this and let me add in it neurons.
Each of these layers can see how that kind of affects performance.
You know when even at six hit in layers maximum.
So let's go kind of all out on this and see how this works.
So that's not to say as a general problem solving strategy you should just go crazy if neurons and hit
players.
But I kind of want you to see the effects of adding a lot of stuff here.
So again rectified linear you get tons of neurons 6 hit in layer so we have a deep network here.
Let's go ahead and run this and see how it performs.
So again the more neurons more players the more time it's going to take to actually learn on this data
and what's really cool is you can see the higher level abstractions as you kind of visit these neurons
see see the visualizations here and kind of towards the end you can see spiral shape really begin to
come out.
So I jump forward in time a bit but you can see here that we have kind of a much lower test loss than
what we initially started with and then a training loss we can see that we're definitely making out
the spiral shape a lot more clearly than our first neural network.
So I encourage you to really play around with this we can go in and pause this.
Now a player of the learning rate.
So obviously the lower the learning rate that means the longer this is going to take to train.
But you may get more accurate results.
I can kind of refresh this and see here that it's going to take a lot longer to train this.
If you have a much slower learning rate or if you refresh this and go to a much higher learning rate
this is going to learn kind of a lot faster.
You can see here really high learning rate.
Kind of ruins the whole thing and says OK I'm going to classify everything as blue.
So lots of things to play around with here.
Hopefully you can now have a really good visualization of all the topics we've been learning about.
So again playground that senseful the or really fun web site really awesome Web site to play around
with.
I really encourage you to check it out and visualize everything we've been talking about.
Coming up next we're going to discuss in full detail the mathematics behind the neural network theory
that we've been talking about and then show you how to manually compute all that in Python.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.