Welcome back everyone.
To finish off this section of the course we're going to manually create in your own network and what
I mean by the word manual is we won't be using it frameworks such as tents or flow instead of we're
going to be doing is trying to mimic sensor flow ourselves by manually coding out the classes and functions
needed doing this before we actually use the tense flow of framework is really going to help build a
nice foundation for your understanding.
We're not going to build out something very complex here it's going to be a very primitive neural network
but it should really help you for the future section when we actually show a lot of the same class names
and functions used with tensor flow.
Let's go ahead and get started.
We're going to start off a really brief overview of object oriented programming and the super keyword
in Python.
Let's open up a new Jupiter notebook.
All right so let's start off of a really quick overview of object oriented programming.
Nothing too crazy here.
And then we'll also show the super keywords and we're going to be using it later on.
So to create your own objects in Python you just have the class keyword and then you can create something
like a simple class and then inside of this when you have functions here instead of a closter called
methods and you always start off this method which kind of initializes the class and then Ill always
take in a soft keyword.
So it's code to make a really simple one that just says Prince Hello.
OK.
So those are simple class.
So if I say S is equal to the string let's say world.
I can see hey the type of s it says some sort of string object.
And if I do s dot and then hit tab here I can see the various methods and attributes that are available
for that object.
So let's try this for an object that we created will say x is equal to a simple class.
And if you don't have any princes there and then you type in X it's going to say hey it's a simple class.
If you actually want to create an instance of a simple class you have these princes right here.
So let's run this again and then I see hello because this method executes upon a creation of an instance
of this class.
So it says hello and then if I check x that says hey simple class at.
And it points to a specific point in your computer's memory saying hey this is actually an instance
of this class simple class because it's not just me it's simple class it's living at this part in your
computer's memory.
So very basics of creating a class there let's go in and delete these cells.
All right let's go ahead and add another method to our simple class.
We'll say the IF and we'll just have it be called Yele and yell isn't really going to do anything except
printouts yelling so again and when I say x is equal to a new instance of simple class and it's going
to say hello and then went to X dot tab it will autocomplete yell and then it will say yelling.
So now I have my method here of this simple class.
Ok now that I have that simple class working.
Let's go ahead and create in other class and we'll call this extended class.
You can really call it whatever you want but the reason I'm calling extend that class is because I'm
going to essentially extend or inherit from the simple class so have simple class.
There and then I'm going to say the F underscore underscore in it or underscore pasand sulfur again
in here it's just going to print out extend.
So let's go ahead and say why is equal to an instance of this extended class.
And now we see extend.
Now notice what happened here is that we only saw extend but even if we inherited from simple class
we didn't see.
Hello.
Now this inheritance does allow us to use methods from simple class.
So even though I don't have a Yale method inside of this extended class it's only inside a simple class
this variable y if I say y dots tab it still has yellow attached to it.
Then it will still say yelling.
So now the question arises How can I make this in a special method also execute inside of the success
of the class.
And the way you do that is through the super keyword.
So when I call super Here it basically tells Python hey go grab whatever class I'm inheriting from and
then I can say Dot underscore underscore in its underscore underscore close parentheses and then run
this out and run.
Extend that class again and going to see how low an extent because I basically said hey go ahead and
run the init method of this simple class and then it prints out Hello.
And if this hello took in arguments for example it says take an argument name and we go ahead and concatenate
that name Runcible simple class again to make sure those changes are saved.
Now if I run it here I can provide a name to run that again and they will say hello Jose.
OK.
So that's the very basics.
Just very quick overview of object oriented programming.
Hopefully I've already encountered object oriented programming before.
This is really more an overview of this super keyword and O.P..
If you're totally unfamiliar O.P. you may want to go back and check that out in a more normal Python
course instead of a steep learning course.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to do is discuss operations and we're going to basically make our own operation
which is a node in a graph and senseful is also going to use this concept of a graph.
So once we have that operation class that we create We're going to create couple of example operations
such as additional placation and matrix multiplication.
Afterwards we'll create placeholders variables in our own graph class and then we'll be able to actually
create a very very simple neural network.
All right.
So we'll do all of that in the next lecture.
Thanks and I'll see you there.