Welcome back everyone to part two of this manual neural network lecture series where we're going to
focus on the operation plus we'll be building so the operation class we create.
It's going to have two main attributes that is input nodes and output nodes so the input notes as you
may have guessed is just the list of input notes that are going into this operation and output nodes
is a list of nodes that are consuming this particular operations output.
Then inside this operation class will also have a global default graph variable which will explain in
a second and then we'll have a compute method and this compute method is going to be essentially overwritten
by an extended class that inherits this operation class.
So let's discuss a little bit about what a graph looks like and then what's going to happen with this
compute method.
So a graph is essentially going to be a global variable.
And the reason we were using this term graph is because tensor flow runs off graphs and we'll kind of
reiterate this when we learn about the tensor flow basics in the next section.
You can imagine a graph as kind of this list of nodes.
And in this case we have this sort of really simple graph where we have two constants are two nodes
and one and two and each of those is a constant one and two respectively.
And then those are feeding into some sort of operation.
And three.
So in our case we have kind of this skeleton operation class and then this operation class is going
to be inherited by other classes.
So for example we can have an add a class that inherits operation class and in that case it takes in
those two inputs 1 and 2 and then outputs 3 because one plus two is three.
Or maybe we have a multiply operation so that multiply operation is this going to say 1 times 2 and
output 2 etc..
So that's the very basics of what a graph would look like.
Obviously when we work in a tensor flow we'll have to deal with this so manually but there will be a
really complex graph in the background that tense flows kind of constructing everything.
So now that we understand the very basics of what we're going to create Let's jump the printer notebook
create this operation class and then also create a couple of operations such as addition multiplication
and matrix multiplication.
What's up over to the notebook Okay here I am at the notebook.
Previously we kind of discussed this really basic O.P. and then the superfunction.
Let's go ahead and put in our operation class.
So our first class going to be operations is just a mark down so we'll start with class and we'll say
Operation we'll start a fire in that method.
What's going to happen when we actually create an operation that takes himself by default.
And then we'll have input notes as a parameter and we'll initialize it with no input nodes by default.
But then we can also pass and whoops self and say input nodes is equal to input nodes and then we're
also going to have output nodes will say output nodes is equal to.
And in this case we'll just have an empty list so that list about Panos is later going to be overwritten
by the actual class.
That is the operation that inherits from it.
OK so we have our input nodes and our output nodes are going to do is we're going to say for every node
in the input we're going to append this particular operation this self operation to the list of the
consumers of the notes that is the output nodes.
So that's a little for loop so inside of this in its method I say for every node in my input nodes What
are you going to do is say grab that node grab the output nodes for that particular node and then append
self which is essentially just a reference to this current operation.
So again for every node in the input notes that are going into the operation I'm going to append this
operation to the output nodes for that node since saying hey once you dump this operation you're going
to output it to whatever output nodes are related to this particular note.
Then finally I'm going to have this compute method self and I'm just going to put a pass in there because
essentially this is just a placeholder method and it's going to be overwritten by the actual specific
operation that inherits from the operation class.
So I know it's a little confusing right now.
These three lines are kind of little mysterious but once you see the whole thing at scale of the other
operations placeholders variables and graphs.
I think it's going to make a lot more sense.
OK so let's go ahead and create some example operations such as.
So to do that we'll have ADD operation then I will say the wups in its going to take itself and then
the two things that we're going to add together are x and y.
So because we're adding these two things together those are essentially inputs.
So those are going to be our input notes for operation.
So let's go out and say super
in its and initialize or operationally passing in a list of those input nodes kind of following along
that graph that we just saw previously.
They're were to say the math computes and that's going to overwrite the compute function here.
And this is essentially going to perform the actual computation operation of addition.
So we're going to say self and is going to be whatever x variable we have whatever y variable you have.
And technically you could use X and Y instead of X underscore VTR.
But this is just so it's a little less confusing.
Least for me.
And then we'll say self input's is equal to whatever X we're able we have whatever y variable we have.
And then we're just going to return x.
V r plus white variable.
OK and again since it's kind of self-contained it's up to you whatever these variables are called.
But it's kind of make a separate that these are computations.
All right.
So that's the very basics of a operation.
So again all we're doing here is we're setting up the input notes this operation where it's going to
be output to so the output nodes then we initialize that per operation.
This case really simple one.
X and Y are inputting X and Y and then these inputs are going to when their computers return there are
some.
So let's go ahead and make two more here.
So instead of add we're going to make one called Multiply.
And typically for classes these would actually be uppercase.
But to follow along with tensor Flo's naming convention of having them be lower case right now because
when we use them and for these function operations like add a multiply matrix multiplication they're
actually lower case so this kind of such as follows along more with tensor flow that we'll see in the
future.
All right.
So multiply going to be the same thing because that's done here.
We're going to say times and boom that was pretty easy.
And finally let's do a matrix multiplication.
So they'll be Matt M U L matrix multiplication.
And this one is going to be the x variable and then we're going to say Dot Y variable.
We're going to basically assume that it's a PI matrix or num PI array and that can then have a dot method
off of it.
So the dot product here for matrix multiplication.
OK so those are our operations.
So again we have this base operation class and then off of that we can kind of write this compute method
for adding multiplying in matrix multiplication.
There's a lot more we could do here things like reduce mean that kind of thing that we'll see later
on.
Intenser flow but for a very basic example this is essentially all we need.
OK.
Coming up next we're going to discuss placeholders and variables and then finish out our actual graph
class.
I'll see you at the next lecture.