Welcome back everyone in this lecture we're going to be creating variables placeholders and graph classes
for manual neural network.
So let's go ahead and discuss these and then we'll hop over the Jupiter notebook.
A placeholder is essentially going to be an empty node that needs a value to be provided to compute
the output and its purpose is essentially to be a placeholder for data that you're going to bring in.
That is the features or labels etc..
So just a placeholder that's eventually going to be filled in by the data you provided.
It's a placeholder because you're not going to initially have that data.
It's going to come from your data source.
Variables are basically already going to be filled in with changeable parameters of the graph so you
can think of that as something like the weights of the actual neural network.
Then finally we have the graph itself and the graph the way we're constructing it here is going to be
a global variable connecting variables and placeholders to specific operations.
Let's go ahead and jump the notebook and code this all out.
All right.
Back at the notebook.
First thing you can do is create the placeholder wrap.
So say class placeholder.
Remember this is a no that's going to need to be provided a value later on.
So we're going to say the and it's self and we're just going to initialize it with the output notes
make them an empty list and then we're going to grab that global variable from the default graph.
So say default underscore graph and then we're going to grab the placeholders of the graph.
So basically this graph object is going to have a bunch of placeholders and then we're going to pen
this placeholder to it when we actually create that graph.
And we're going to do something really similar to our variable class or we're going to create.
So we'll have variables and the variables a changeable parameter inside the graph.
So we'll see it here.
It's going to take self.
And then usually often they'll have some sort of initial value such as randomly initializing the weights
of a graph or of a network and then we're going to say soft value is equal to the initial value and
then we're also going to say what are the output notes here.
Started off as an empty list and then just as we did last time we're going to append this.
So our default graph object is going to have some variables to it.
And we're going to append those variables.
OK.
So we discussed this default graph.
It's a global object.
Let's go ahead and now create the class for it.
So say class Grath.
And we're going to initialize it with three attributes and that's going to be a list of operations and
graph a list of placeholders and scrap and the list of variables in this graph.
So what does scrap actually doing.
This is essentially the main thing it's going to be connecting these placeholders in variables to the
operations that they belong to.
So again every time appear in these other placeholder and variable graphs when we're doing this specific
attribute or assignment right here this a default graph variables a pen.
All we're saying is hey this graph is going to contain a list of all the variables inside the graph.
So when we create a variable go ahead and append it to the default Gras variables and then we're going
to have one more method here called set as defaults.
So to make sure that if we have multiple instances of graphs we're connected to the right one.
We are to have this method here set as default and it's basically going to call global default graph
essentially setting the default graph as a global variable.
And that's what's going to allow us to access it inside this placeholder inside this variable class.
And also if we come back up here inside our initial operation so let's go ahead and add that into our
operation class.
Now that we kind of know that it exists or say default graph operations pen self.
OK.
So now we have operations placeholders in variables and we have a graph that keeps track of them all
in the form of a list and it also can then set its own graph as a global variable to be kind of accessed
by those three main objects and then we'll say default graph is equal to self.
OK so hopefully now you kind of get the sense that we have this graph object.
It contains placeholders in variables.
Variables are things that kind of can be changeable parameters within the graph.
Placeholders are essentially empty nodes waiting for you to provide them data information and then operations
will we know what those are.
Those are just computation operations like matrix multiplication multiply addition etc..
All right.
So now we have this graph.
Let's go ahead and work through a really simple example.
So we're going to do something really simple.
We're going to see if we can make this into a text box.
OK.
So we're going to something really important to say something like Z is equal to x plus B.
And we're also going to say is equal to 10 and B is equal to 1.
So that basically means we have the following problem where say OK if z is equal to x plus B if Z.
Or excuse me if A's 10 and basic will to 1 then I should have the following function.
I should say 10 x plus 1.
So now we have a formula here.
So I know we make this two lines here.
I know Z is equal to x plus be.
If I have these two variables A's equal to 10 and B is equal to 1 then I have this resulting output
of Z depending on what my value of x x Here is a placeholder depending on what value you provide for
x.
We can do these two computations a multiplication and in addition to get the sexual result.
So let's do this with what we just did right now.
We'll say G is equal to a graph.
So now we have a graph object.
We're going to set G as a default graph.
Now that initializes this global variable it's floating around.
And then we have two variables.
That is we have a that's a variable with a value of 10 and then we have B.
And that's a variable with a value of 1.
And this number 10 and 1 just totally arbitrarily chosen.
Ok then X we technically don't know what it is yet.
That's up to the user to provide because essentially the formula of a line right equals m s plus B.
So we have X here and have that be a placeholder no need sobriety thing because it expects it to be
provided later.
Now I have two operations.
I have a multiplication operation here 10 times X and then I have an addition operation the result of
that plus 1.
So let's go ahead and do the following.
I'll say why is equal to multiply and I multiply the variable a by the placeholder X and then finally
my final result is Z.
Right.
Add in the result of that multiply function which is why are most by class really and then B here and
then I have Z right here.
So the only thing left is to actually compute this Z.
Now in order to compute these various operations as well as set these variables in placeholders we need
to add in two more things we need to create a traverse.
Post order function and that's basically going to allow us to do a post order traversal of nodes and
that essentially mixtures that the computation is then the correct order.
For instance I need to make sure that a multiply this out first before I add these two.
Right now nothing is actually being done here because we haven't run this once I have that traverse.
Post order operation function ready then I can create a session class and the session class is going
to be the thing that actually executes this graph.
So right now I kind of have all these empty things.
None of these things have actually happened yet.
I have actually multiplied anything that added anything yet because we're essentially still waiting
on that placeholder.
So in the next lecture we're going to add in a function called traverse post order which is going to
the post order traversal of nodes.
Or you may be familiar with if you ever done anything regarding tree theory with computer science and
there we're going to have a session class and that session class is going to be the thing that actually
execute sorry thing.
OK.
So let's go ahead and do that in the next lecture.