Welcome back everyone to this lecture on creating the session for our manual neural network.
Now that the graph has all the nodes in place what we need to do is make sure we execute all those node
operations including those variables and placeholders within the session in the correct order where
we're going to do is use a post order tree traversal to make sure we execute the nodes in that correct
order.
Now as far as the way the actual post order traversal works you don't really need to worry about those
details.
We'll never really encounter this again throughout the rest of the course so I'm just going to copy
and paste this function from the notes.
You can feel free to check out the Wikipedia page on tree traversal.
It has the full step by step outline of how Post order tree traversal works.
But for now we're just going to copy and paste that function.
Then we're gonna manually code out the session class.
Let's head to the notebook.
All right.
Back of the notebook here I'm just going to copy and paste from the notes provided the post order traversal
and basically what this does it's just that post order mixtures that we execute the computations in
the correct order.
So for instance we need to execute a times X first and then after that we can do X plus B.
So all this does is it kind of does this recursive function and and it ends up returning a list of all
those nodes in their correct order.
So it's going to run this again the details of this.
You really don't need to concern yourself with them.
Instead we're going to do is essentially treat this as something that takes in the operation and it
makes sure that they're all executed in the correct order.
So once we have that general there standing of what that function is doing we can create our session
class.
So let's go ahead and create a method in the session class called Run will say sulf operation and then
we're going to have a field dictionary which is the same terminology used in tensor flow.
So the operation itself is going to be the operation to compute and then the feed dictionary is a dictionary
mapping placeholders to input values.
Remember right now in our graph we only actually have values for those variables.
That was that 10 and that one from earlier the placeholders are still waiting for you to provide them
a value.
And we're going to use the feed dictionary to provide that value.
The reason we're doing with a feed dictionary is because later on we're going to be feeding our network
batches of data.
So we're going to be kind of feeding it a batch through that dictionary.
So we're going to say the notes post order is equal to a call to that traverse.
Post order function and we pass in that operation.
So we're going to say for node in nodes post order we'll do the following checks we'll say hey if the
type of node is equal to a placeholder node then I need that node output to be equal to the dictionary
key with that node else.
If the type of node is a variable node then I should already have that value so that node output is
going to be equal to that node value.
Otherwise if it's not a placeholder and if it's not a variable that means I have an operation.
So else for the operation I'll say the node inputs are equal to and here to use list comprehension we'll
say input node thought output for input node and node input node loops to make sure that's correct.
We zoom out one level so we can see this whole thing.
So I'm saying OK if this is not a placeholder and it's not a variable then otherwise I have an operation
so for this operation you need to make sure my pets are owners also know that input is going to be equal
to the output of that input node for every input node in node input nodes.
There we go Michalos plural.
So it winds up with that attribute we created earlier that I always say that the output of that note
is just going to be a computer operation.
So node inputs and you may be wondering what this Asterix here for.
So the Asterix is essentially just an args Asterix and it's just a way for us to provide these inputs
without knowing how many inputs we may have throughout the operation.
So technically we don't really know the size of this list so we pass it into computer.
We're going to just say Asterix note inputs.
Now granted all the operations we've done so far if we scroll back up really only expect two arguments
so these computer methods are really only expecting two parameters here.
But hey maybe we have another addition operation that adds three together or something like that.
So since we technically don't know beforehand how many parameters are going to pass in we're going to
use this Asterix for ARX.
What I'm saying.
Yes.
And you can check out the resource link for more details on that finally we'll say if the type is node
output is equal to list then I'm going to say node output is equal to loops and pray no output so that's
going to convert the list to an umpire is.
And then finally after this method I'm going to say return the operation output.
So return the requested note value.
And make sure I get everything correct else type note is equal to variable make sure I have that.
This should be ilah else.
OK.
So perfect.
We have our check for a placeholder in which case we give it the feed dictionary value.
If it's a variable in that case we give it the actual value of that variable.
So if we kind of check back to variable come back up here number that variable had this kind of initial
value here.
So self-taught value of that variable.
That's what we're talking about when we say no value here.
If it's not then it's an operation of a placeholder or a variable.
So then we have our inputs of the operation and our outputs the operation the output is just the result
of computing the inputs where the input is just a list of those node input nodes.
OK so let's go ahead and actually execute this say sess is equal to an instance of session and then
we're going to say results is equal to sess run and Lotusphere to have an operation in a feed dictionary
so we're going to say operation is equal to Z because remember our operation all the way at the end
is this final one or we add y M-B and why and connected to multiply which is then connected to placeholders
and the variables.
So kind of background here.
I'm going to provide a feed dictionary and the dictionary is going to say X is 10 so we run that we
check our results and we get back 100 1.
So if we remember our original function or we're trying to compute it's Z is equal to x plus be so 0
to 10 x plus 1.
If I provide x 10 that's 10 times then is 100 plus 1 is 101.
Come back down here we get back 101.
So it looks like we successfully did it.
Let's go ahead and show this with some matrix multiplication which is kind of a little more in common.
We're going to be doing with tensor flow.
So starting this all over from the top I create a graph object then I'm going to set that as the default
graph.
I'm going to have some variable and in this case the variable a be essentially a matrix so 10 20 say
30 40.
So we just have it be a nested list for now later on tent's flow will be passing in them piracies and
then we have 1 1.
Check your brackets here.
Then we have a placeholder a waiting x and then we'll say Y instead of equal to multiply is a matrix
multiplication now with X and then we'll say Z is equal to add y in B.
So now if I do the same thing as before I create a new session and then I say run the operation equal
to that news the operation is created and we'll see if the dictionary is now equal to 10 as before.
Now we get back in array.
So essentially kind of the same operations we did before except now it's based off a matrix.
So you can also change this to one common one to match the notes and you should see 101 to one throw
one 401.
Perfect.
All right.
So that's the very basics of how a session is going to work.
So up next we're going to do is convert this to kind of a more traditional classification problem by
putting in an activation function and then doing a really simple classification example or create some
blobs and then we're going to classify them into two classes zero or one red or blue.
We're going to define a perception type model.
All right.
So that's it as far as the very basics of creating your own graph and your own session session may be
a little confusing at first.
Definitely check the time or take the time to kind of go through each of these lines and it may be a
little confusing because you kind of forget what these attributes actually are.
So if there's an attribute you don't recognize go ahead and come back up to the classes where we find
them and then see what they're actually referring to.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.