Welcome back everyone to this final piece of our Emmanual neural network.
We're actually going to perform a very simple classification problem essentially just kind of a linear
classification.
Let's hop over to the Jupiter note book and show you how it's done.
All right.
So we're going to scroll down here past what we've done before already.
And let's go ahead and define this as our kind of classification section so classification and the first
thing you need to do is create an activation function.
All right so let's have that going now.
So actually show you the activation function I want to plot it out.
So we'll say that plotted that PI plot as POPC and then English to say map plot live in line and then
I'm going to create the sigmoid function here which is a very simple activation function takes in Z
and then it's going to return 1 over 1 plus E to the power of negative Z.
So let's actually plot this out.
So we'll make a sample's z using some pie's Lynn space.
Let's go from I don't know negative tend to turn 100 points.
And then the result of the X activation function we'll say sample A.
It's just sigmoid called on samples the check and then say peel t that plot sample Z versus sampling
and then I get the sigmoid function.
So it looks like this.
You can see here that has that inflection point around 0 and that eventually as you go higher and higher
in your input it kind of peaks out to one point zero.
And as you go lower and lower it goes down to just zero.
So all values that are put it into this function have to be between 0 and 1.
So let's go ahead and make this into an operation because technically we can think of an activation
as an operations or say sigmoid inherit from the operation we'll say if in it self and will say Z we'll
use that super command to then call in it off the operation and we'll just pasand the input as z number
operation takes in those input nodes.
In that case whatever is going to sigmoid is just going to be Z there and then we'll have our compute
method which is just self takes and some's the value there.
And then we're Centrica to return the exact same thing we did up here so just copy and paste this will
see a return.
This right here there we go.
So now we have sigmoid as an actual operation that we can use.
So let's do a classification example and sikat learn actually has a really nice function and capabilities
to create data sets for us.
So I'll say from Aski learnt that they import and we'll say make Blob's and whoops mixture that should
be data sets.
There we go.
And then I'm going to say my data is equal to make Blob's.
And as you may have guessed this basically just creates a couple of blobs there that you can classify.
So if you take a look at shift enter it tells you the various parameters were going to be doing most
of them are self-explanatory.
So I'm going to be creating 50 samples and the number of features to status that's going to have is
just two features and centers essentially how many blobs are going gonna make.
We're going to make two blobs So this is just a binary classification problem.
And then let's go ahead and give it a random states and make sure you give it the same random state
number I do.
We'll show you later on Bill we'll go ahead and give it 75.
So if we take a look at our data now we have these two sets of features and if you scroll down here
you have the actual labels.
So if you take a look at the type that data is it's a tuple where the first entry in the tuple is the
actual essentially features itself and then the second entry or the actual label.
So what classes they belong to.
Let's go in and plot this out so we can get kind of a better idea of what actually looks like we'll
say features is equal to the first entry in that data and they will say labels is equal to data one
Xand I'm going to create a scatterplot of features all the rows in column 0 and then all the rows in
column one.
So if I do scatterplot of that I see here that I have two distinctive blobs So really easily able to
classify this and these two classes are highly separable.
And on the x axis as feature one on the y axis is feature two.
So essentially column 0 versus column 1 so we have two feature columns and we have clearly two blobs
here.
And then we can actually color them by the labels so I can say See for coloring is equal to labels.
And then I run that and I can see now they're colored.
And if you don't really like this coloring choice yellow versus purple if you want.
You can also add an see map here and then add in a color argument.
For example corm probably a little better of a choice here to the sewing classes.
So now we're going to do is use our neural network to actually separate these classes.
We're going to have a really simpler idea.
Everything we've been doing so far as kind of this week was EMCs plus B type of thing.
So we're going to be doing this same idea trying to draw a line that separates these classes.
So let's first do this manually going to say the following.
I will say x is equal to and P when space and it looks like we're going from around 0 to a little past
that so we can say zero to 11.
And if you want it can go negative 10:59 it doesn't matter a whole lot and they will create 10 points
between that and then let's try to see what kind of line would separate these classes nicely.
It looks like if we have whites the power of negative x that would kind of go from zero here to zero
there.
So let's go ahead and say Whyte's the negative x but then raise it up by about five.
So that should give us kind of this nice clear distinctive line we'll see if that works or say Y is
equal to negative X..
Well first if we just say Y is equal to negative x Let's see what that looks like.
And then we kind of see how we need to raise it.
So going to copy this same scatterplot and then on top of that I'm going to plot x versus Y.
So if I just do this plot right now the separator probably isn't really high enough so let's add 5 to
it.
Essentially an intercept.
Right.
And this looks like a pretty good line to separate it.
And what we can say here is that anything above this line belongs to the red class and anything below
this line belongs to the blue class.
In our case these two classes are really easy to separate.
So we're going to be using this sort of logic to say hey anything above this line that works and classify
it to be read blow to blue.
Now the next step is to actually define the perception of to model using a matrix representation of
the features.
So I going to kind of show a quick slide here to explain the process for doing that.
But before we go to Slide I need you to remember one key thing here.
Right now we're kind of formulating this as a y equals unmix plus b.
Remember that this Y and X are essentially just features we replace them here with the first column
the features and the second column of features.
So another way to think of this equation could be something like EF 2 is equal to negative EF 1 plus
5.
So the main thing I want you to remember here is that this X-axis is a feature so X is EF 1 and then
Y here is also a feature F 2.
Now let me show you a quick slide to show you how we can convert something that looks like this white
ghouls negative x plus 5 into some sort of matrix representation that we can adjust of our perception.
Let me hop over to a slide.
OK so here you have a slide kind of detailing the steps out.
We first start off with a basic equation for a line that is that Wike was emic plus B.
And then we fill out the actual intercept and the slope.
We get something that looks like this.
Y equals negative one x time.
Or excuse me negative 1 times x plus 5.
OK so that was the equation we just had that y equals negative x plus 5.
And as I mentioned remember that both line xx are actually features.
So we're filling that in with features from our data set.
Blob data sets.
So if we actually coded out with the features it'll probably look something like this the fourth bullet
point feature two is equal to negative 1 Times feature 1 plus 5.
And if we set this entire thing to be equal to zero then we get something that looks like this feature
two plus feature 1 minus 5 is equal to zero.
And if we were to write that in the form of a matrix we would say whatever feature matrix is.
So all those feature values to an EF 1.
Multiply that by one comma 1 Matrix because essentially feature 2 and feature 1 just have both multipliers
of one one Serb are from the same side of the equal sign then subtract five and you get zero.
So again this is converting that line into a matrix representation.
So we can then input features too.
So what would be nice is if we could have a placeholder ready to fit in those features too.
OK let's hop back over the notebook.
All right.
Back here in the notebook I want to quickly type out what we just described.
So essentially our equation needs to look something like this.
We're going to do a matrix of one one that's a one by two Matrix.
Now we're going to multiply that by our feature matrix.
And to make sure we can multiply it.
This feature makes tricks needs to have a shape of 2 1 and then we're going to say subtract 5 from that
and set it equal to zero.
So essentially the equation we're trying to fill out looks something like this.
So a matrix of 1 come a 1 and then multiply that by our feature matrix which is going to be in the shape
to buy one to make sure it can easily matrix multiply here then subtract five equal to zero.
So now we have a nice matrix representation of this line and we know that if this value as a result
is above zero then you're on this side of the line or the red side.
And if you're below zero then you're on the blue side of the line.
So the way this would look like in pi is the following.
We'll say umpiring 1 come a one then say dot products or matrix multiplication with any array.
And in this case we'll just choose a point.
So she's a point that's pretty visibly going to be in one of the classes.
So for example if I choose a point at 8 10 that's right in the middle of that red cluster that should
have a positive value as an output.
So here we'll say it's 10 and notice the shape here.
It's a one by two.
And then after all that we're going to say minus five and there we get a positive value back 13.
So we know it belongs to this class right here then we're going to do the opposite for another pointless
she's a point that should obviously be in the blue class.
That should give us a value below zero or below that line.
So let's use something like four and negative 10.
That should clearly be.
Or let's just say two negative 10.
That's really obvious.
So say pre-Reagan 1 1 dot product with MP array and then we're going to say what do we say to for feature
1 and then on feature to all say negative 10 minus five.
And that's definitely negative.
Negative 13 here.
So it's below this line.
It belongs to a blue class.
So that's the where perceptions are going to work.
It's going to just take in.
Hey is the output positive or negative.
And then it's going to assign the classes in that manner.
So very simple kind of linear classifier here.
So let's actually make an example session graph that can run this will say G is equal to graph.
We're going to set this as the default graph.
Then we're going to create a placeholder for X will say X are the actual features so we expect X to
be a feature array then we'll say w kind of as our weight is a variable here one one and they'll say
B is equal to a variable and this is negative five and then we'll say Z is equal to.
And the result of a matrix multiplication between W and X and then add to it.
And if you want you could do this in two steps as we've done before.
But that's what we need to figure out.
And then finally we're going to pass that into our sigmoid function say sigmoid Z because that's essentially
going to output a zero or one for us as we go along.
So remember right now we're classifying based on whether it's positive or negative.
And luckily the sigmoid function that we did earlier lines up with that.
So we'll come all the way back up here.
So we're going to say the following.
We're going to input the result of that into the sigmoid function and the sigmoid function is going
to give us a result that's going to be between 0 and 1.
And as we input this the further negative we input the more sure our model is going to be that it belongs
to the 0 class.
The more positive input the more sure our model is going to be that it belongs to the one class.
Now if it's something closer to zero that means kind of by definition that we're getting closer to this
line that we created.
So the closer we are to zero that means the closer we are to that line and the less sure we are about
which class this particular point should go to.
So keep that in mind.
So final step is the activation function sigmoid.
So then we're going to say yes is equal to session
and let's run this we'll say yes or a session run our final operation that we find is a member a post
or a traversals going to kind of go back and do the adding first in the matrix multiplication in the
sigmoid.
So we have our operation a.
And then we're going to create a feed dictionary for it and it is going to feed the results we did last
time we'll say eight and 10.
I believe that's what it was.
Scroll down here.
Yeah it was 8 and 10 and then we're going to run this and see what the result is.
It looks like we may have had a typo here so bad operant have for a so let's make sure or add there.
Looks like we had a typo here this should be Z vowel not Z.
So let's go back and change that in our sigmoid function.
Of course you can always check with the notes.
There should have no typos in them.
So is evil.
Run that again.
Okay perfect.
Let's come back in here and let's run all of these again real quick to make sure we have everything.
So graph set as default placeholder variable variable multiply sigmoid.
Run that and then we get 0.19.
So basically we're very very sure that this point is going to be long to class one which makes sense
because if you look at we're 8 and 10 so 8 over here 10 over here that's right in the middle.
So now let's do it for the other one maybe like a zero negative 10.
That should definitely belong to blue.
So we're going to run this again.
And like I say let's do something like for the features to add negative 10 run that.
And now we get something that's very very close to zero.
So notice here it's times ten to the power of negative six.
So this is essentially zero.
So it's also very sure that it belongs to the zero class.
OK so now we were able to successfully use our own graph objects placeholders variables activation functions
etc. to recession and actually perform a very simple classification.
And hopefully now that you know how to do this manually it's going to make learning tensor flow a lot
easier in performing all of this with tensor flow.
It's going to be much much easier than what we did right now.
This is kind of just eating your vegetables first before you get to jump in and dive into the really
nice features that a framework like tons flow provides for you.
So using intense flow is going to be a lot easier than all this because a lot of this can get scratched
your head and think about OK what exactly am I doing.
Step by step but tense flow is a really nice abstraction over all of this.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see it the next section of the course.