Welcome everyone to this section on convolutional neural networks in this section we're going to be
covering several things.
We'll start off with a quick review of previous topics and neural networks then we'll discuss some new
theory topics that will help set up your learning for convolutional neural networks.
We'll also discuss the famous EMIs handwritten digits dataset.
Then we're going to solve the classification problem of this with a quote unquote normal neural network
set up.
We're going to learn about the theory behind that convolutional neural network and then we'll revisit
the problem and solve it.
Convolutional neural nets.
After that they'll have the convolutional neural network exercise and the solutions afterwards.
All right let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.