Welcome everyone to this quick review lecture in this lecture we're just going to quickly review what
we've covered so far particularly pertaining to neural networks.
So we already understand how to perform calculations within a single neuron.
What we do is we have some data input X and we end up learning weights and multiply them by X and then
we add in some biased term and the sum of the results in Z.
And then we pass Z through some sort of activation function.
We have also learned that there's various activation functions or simple ones like percept trons where
they just look to see if the input is positive or negative.
Then there's also the sigmoid activation function as well as hyperbolic tension and then rectified linear
units.
We're also going to discuss some other functions later on then we understand that we can connect these
single neurons together to create a neural network in your own network that has an input layer has hidden
layers and an output layer.
And we understand that if we add more layers we end up getting higher levels of abstraction and that
will be even more clear when we begin to work with data types such as images.
As you have more layers each layer will then have a higher abstraction some layers will no edges layers
will know if you're doing facial recognition things like eyebrows etc..
So in order to learn what we need is some sort of measurement of error and that's where that cost and
loss function came into play.
And we learned that there's quadratic loss functions as well as cross entropy loss functions once we
have the measurement of error we need to do is minimize it by choosing the correct way and bias values.
And what we do is we use grading the scent to find the optimal values.
So that's basically our learning process.
We have some sort of measurement of error through the cost function and then we perform a gradient descent.
We can then back propagate the and descent through the multiple layers from the output layer back to
the input layer.
We also know of dense layers which are layers that are fully connected to every other neuron in the
next layer.
And later on we're also going to be introducing a soft Max layer's OK so that's just a very quick overview
of what we know so far.
However we still need to learn a little bit more theory before diving into convolutional neural networks.
So the next lecture we're going to do is cover some new theory aspects.
Some of them we've actually already introduced before that we haven't given any sort of reasoning for
them so let's go ahead and discuss these new theory topics in the next lecture.
I'll see there.