Welcome everyone to this lecture on the dataset this is a classic data set in deep learning and machine
learning in general.
So we're going to do as quickly cover some of the basics about it since we're going to be using it quite
frequently during this section of the course where we discuss convolutional neural networks and a big
part of neural networks with tensor flow in general is really understanding your data.
That way you understand how you're feeding it in the reshaping that occurs either you flatten it out
or maybe you add in some padding etc. as you feed it into neural networks.
So since it's such a classic dataset we're going to cover it in a little more detail.
Luckily as far as acquiring the data itself tensor flow has methods to automatically retrieve it from
the Internet for you.
We've already ran those for you so if you downloaded the zip file for this course you actually already
have a folder of the data set.
So the tensor flow downloaded version has 55000 training images 10000 test images and then 5000 validation
images.
So you can see here it's already split for you in a train test and validation or train test.
Hold out for you.
So what is the actual data set.
Well it contains handwritten single digits from 0 to 9.
And here you can see a couple of examples and a single digit image can be represented as an array.
So if we look at one of these digits a little more closely we can represent it as an array on a to the
plane and specifically we can represent it as a to the array of 28 pixels by 28 pixels.
So here we can see that this handwritten digit of a 1 is represented by values on this to the plane
where zeros are white and then one is black and values in between.
Aren't some sort of grayscale.
So again values represent the greyscale image so now we have a numeric representation of these images.
We can then flatten the cerate to be a one dimensional vector of 784 numbers.
So that's just 28 times 28.
And we can set it up as 781 by one or one by 781.
Either is fine as long as you keep consistent mentions throughout your training so you can see here
does a flattened representation of this previous array so flattening out the image ends up removing
some of that to the information such as the relationship of a pixel to its neighboring pixels.
For now we're going to ignore that side effect of flattening out that array but we're going to come
back to it later when we discuss convolutional neural networks in that because come illusional neural
networks when working with images actually take into account the relationship of a pixel next to its
neighboring pixels.
For now we're going to do when we have a basic approach to this data and classifying it into the various
digits we're just going to flatten it out into a single one dimensional array and we can actually think
of the entire group of 55000 images as a tensor or an end dimensional array where we have a total of
784 pixels on one axis and then 55000 training images on another axis.
And it's important to note that for the labels we're going to be using is one hot encoding.
And this means that instead of having labels such as strings that say one two or three etc. We're going
to have it's just a single array for each image the labels represented based off the index position
in the label array.
And this is where one encoding comes in.
So the corresponding label will be a one at the index location of its true label it is zero everywhere
else.
So for example if we have a picture of a hand written for then using one hot encoding we're going to
say that the label is the following list where if you go along and you find an explanation for that
is 0 1 2 3 4 you can see that there's a 1 there.
And that's the label that would be fed into our algorithm for the number for as a result the labels
for the training data.
It just ends up being a large two that mentionable array where we have 10.
Remember those are 10 possible labels.
Zura through nine by 55000 which are the training images.
Okay that's all we need to know for now.
Up next we're going to describe first a basic approach to classifying the dataset.
And then after that we're going to have a convolutional neural network approach.
Let's discuss in the next lecture a basic approach to trying to classify these images.
Neural Network.