Welcome everyone to this lecture where we take a basic or normal approach to the dataset for classifying
digits and this sort of approach is a lot of times the very first approach you see in deep learning
tutorials.
So it's always a good idea to go through it because pretty much every major framework will have some
sort of data set analysis or classification as far as a tutorial on how to use a framework.
So it's really important to understand this particular problem in a framework.
That way you can easily use it as an analogy for other frameworks.
So we're going to use what we know so far about neural networks theory and using tensor flow to solve
the endless classification.
Then after that we get to learn about convolutional neuron that works and see just how much of a performance
improvement CNN's can give you for image classification tasks something CNN's and general are really
well suited for.
The First off we're going to use this more basic approach.
Specifically a soft Max regression approach which is a really common layer and approach you're going
to see throughout more advanced neural networks as well.
So it's important that we go over it.
Now that's actually really similar to the methods we've already used in previous sections of the course.
So let's discuss what the soft Max regression is basically a soft Max regression returns a list of values
between 0 and 1 that when you some of them up or add them up they all add up to just 1.
And we can treat that as a list of probabilities.
So you can imagine that if we have a list of 10 potential labels that is zero through nine we could
then when we apply Sotha Max regression get a list of 10 probabilities.
And when you add up those probabilities that equal 1.
So that means that basically will choose whichever label has the highest probability or likelihood of
being correct.
Now you usually won't get 100 percent for one probability instead you'll get the relatively high probability
for one label then maybe second highest probability for a similar looking number and then everything
else will have not zero but something very close to it just because it's never 100 percent sure for
any one number and we're going to apply the basic soft max function as an activation function.
So let's go through that as well.
So if we use soft Max as our activation function.
The basic idea of soft Max is to define a new type of output layer for our neural networks and we'll
see a diagram of this coming up next.
But it essentially begins the exact same way as if the sigmoid layer something we've already worked
with.
So we form the output Z by having the weights multiplied by an input X plus a biased term.
However once we have that Z the activation function we pass it through is not the sigmoid function but
it's that it's this soft max function and according to this function it's just the exponential of that
output Z divided by the denominator the sum over all the output neurons and that's the soft Max.
And if we were to imagine this in a network format we basically get something that looks similar to
this except they would have a lot more x's.
And basically for each output we compute a weighted sum of X's add a bias and then apply the soft Max
and we can actually then write this out as an equation.
So you would get something like this where you have that output y equal to soft Max applied to the weights
multiplied by each of the inputs plus a biased term.
And then of course we're going to vectorize this procedure which would then look something like this
turning it into matrix multiplication and Vector addition.
And this makes it computationally a lot more efficient.
All right let's go ahead and open up a Jupiter note book and implement this with Python and Tancer flow
OK.
Here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
Let's go ahead and get started.
The first thing you need to do is importance and flow of course and then the next thing we need to do
is actually get the data.
Keep in mind I've already downloaded the data and it's included in the zip file for this course underneath
the convolutional neural networks folder.
There is a folder called data in case you need to download it again.
You can either check out the links in the basic approach notebook to download it manually or you can
use the sensor for commands to download it automatically for you.
And keep in mind if this doesn't work for you you most likely have some sort of firewall problem and
in which case you can always use the links in the basic approach notebook that download this stuff manually
some way or another you will need to have permissions on your computer to download stuff from the Internet.
So if you're on a work computer that may be an issue for you.
So I have it from sensor fluid that examples that's Tauriel and this import input data input data is
going to allow us to download the data set.
So I will say input data.
The read data sets it could just have auto complete that.
And then I will say this underscore data forward slash.
That's going to create a new folder for me with the data and then you also want to say one hot is equal
to true so that the labels are one and coded already for you.
So if you run this inside the neural networks for there which are highly recommended Do you should basically
automatically get something that says extracting the data.
If you do not run this in that folder you'll get some some output that says hey it's downloading a couple
of bytes downloading downloading.
So that depends on your internet connection.
But again if you're running this from another folder you will be downloading the data instead of just
extracting the data that I've already downloaded for you.
Keep that in mind.
I really recommend just run this notebook directly from where it is in the zip file.
So if we take a look at the type of what this is it's basically this kind of specialized tensor flow
data set than it already has a lot of convenient methods built into it later on when we deal with other
data sets we're going to have to basically make our own classes to create these kind of methods.
But for now we're going to take advantage of these convenience methods.
So I can say this and if you do that tap here there's a test train and validation.
So if you choose one of those sets such as train and then hit tab here you can see there's images labels.
There's also a next batch function which is nice basically feeds in batches number of examples epochs
completed etcetera.
So if we take a look at the images themselves you get the output of a bunch of arrays.
So then you can actually ask for how many examples there are as we discussed there's 55000 training
examples and you can check out the other ones as well.
If you want to know how many test examples are those 10000 and there's 5000 validation examples as we've
already discussed.
So let's quickly visualize the data.
Also import map plot lib pipe plot as PBT and Alson is say some time in the notebook that lib inline
Sugoi say this train images and if I check out the shape of this this is 55000 images by 784 pixels
remember that's just 28 times 28.
So I'm going to grab one of these
and this is an image so we can see here it's an image.
So what did you do.
Since it's flattened out I need to reshape this to be 28 by 28 and now I can see that it's been reshaped
and others brackets in here which means I can actually show this.
So I will say this is a single image is equal to that result that I'll say P.L. see him show that single
image run that.
And there we can see it's a handwritten three.
Pretty cool.
Now we're actually not going to be using color instead we're going to be using just a greyscale.
So to kind of show what that would look like you just say one of the color maps.
See map JSE underscore Gray and this is kind of what we're going to be training on.
All right.
So the other thing to note is that the data has already been normalized for you.
So if you take a look at single image and ask for the minimum value it's zero.
And if you ask for the maximum value it's 1.
So this is already normalized for us which is pretty nice.
So now that we understand our data again it's just an array of images that are all flattened out and
you could reshape that to visualize it.
However we won't be reshaping for training purposes.
We're going to do in the very next lecture is actually create the model.
So I will see at the next lecture.
We're going to take off right where we left off here.
I'll see you there.