Welcome back everyone right here where we left off last time.
So we have our data.
It's now time to create our model.
So again we're doing a very basic soft Max regression approach.
So I'm going to map out the steps we need to do here.
We need to create our placeholders so we'll have our placeholders which essentially going to be X then
we also need our variable's then we're going to need to create the actual graph operations then we'll
need to have our last function then we'll need our optimizer how we're going to optimize that last function.
Essentially what we're going to minimize and then we'll create our session and run all this.
All right.
So let's start off with the placeholders.
So our placeholder we only have one set of input which is our image data.
So I'll say T.F. placeholder and it's going to be flat 32 and we're going to indicate that the shape
is none because it's essentially going to be filled in by the batch size.
And then 784 because that's 28 times 28 remember we have flattened the race.
OK so that's our placeholder.
And then we have our variables which is going to be our weights and our bias.
So we'll have our weights here.
And this is going to be T.F. variable.
And then just go ahead and initialize this our weights and biases with zeros.
We already have a discussion of why this is probably not such a great idea.
But right now we want to keep things as simple as possible.
So we'll initiate weight some by ISIS as zeros.
Now typically you probably shouldn't do this but again this is just for simplification.
So our weight should be 784 by 10 because we have 784 pixels by 10 possible labels.
And then the other variable we need to make is the bias term.
So this is what we're adding onto that.
So that just needs to be the same length as the actual labels.
So I'll say T.F. variable that's going to be T.F. zeroes and then we'll just say 10 there.
So those are variables you can mess around and maybe add some random numbers here instead of zeros in
fact tensor float does have its own.
If you take a look at random here it has its own random normal and other things of that nature.
But again keeping things simple We'll do it all zeros.
For this particular set it will have a huge effect.
Now we need to create our graph operation.
So remember this is what we just basically went over in those slides trust.
If we just have a matrix multiplication between X and W and then we're going to add to it.
And if you want it called this z instead of y it's up to you then we need to give our last function.
So in order to have a loss function we need one more placeholder and that is the why true values.
So you do it up here or do it down here in the last function the pudding how you want to think about
things but will say that the y true is equal to T.F. placeholder here.
Flo 32 and then this is going to be none because it's the again the bet size and then 10 because there's
10 possible labels.
So we still need to add more for this last function here.
So we're going to use a cross entropy loss function very common loss function to use say cross entropy
to T.F. reduce mean and then we can basically directly import this from sensor flow we'll say T.F. and
in soft Max and it's cross-bench repeat with logic there and then we're going to say labels is equal
to y true SWI true.
Let me zoom out one level so we can see the whole thing.
And then we say Blodgett's loops is equal to Y and this is basically just tensor flows built in across
entropy loss function where you're basically passing in.
Hey these are my true values which right now is a placeholder.
The painting on the back is being fed in.
And then y is going to be your actual predictions.
And then this is going to be cross entropy loss just how off are you.
So we'll run that now.
And we also need to then optimize this.
So let's create our optimizer can zoom back in for this will say that our optimizer is equal to T.F.
train dot and we'll use gradient descent optimizer.
And let's go ahead and just say learning rates of 0.5 a little bit of a larger learning rate and you
can play around that later on.
But then we'll say train is equal to optimizer and we want to minimize our loss function that we just
created which is going to be that cross entropy.
So we run that we have our optimizer.
Now it's time to create our session remember whenever we're creating a session we need to initialize
all the global variables.
So we'll do the following.
We'll see if it is equal to T.F. global variables initialiser have that going.
And then we want to just run our session which means we'll do with T.F. that session as SPSS we want
to run that initialization.
So SEST run in it and then we want to train the model.
So we'll say for step in range and we'll do 1000 steps on the training set.
Again you kind of play around with this number and what's really nice about the dataset that comes with
tensor flow is it actually has a method to feed in batches.
So if we take a look at Amnesty's that train the next batch this is the method where you just need to
provide then the batch size and it will return a batch of training samples.
So we'll say we want 100 for our batch size.
And let's go ahead and say this is equal to batch X batch y.
So this is essentially tuple unpacking packing and if you read the documentation of what this actually
returns it just returns a tuple with your X and Y.
So your X data that is your 700 and 84 pixels and then your batch Y which are the labels that belong
to those pixels as is your training data you're getting 100 of those samples at a time.
And then we're gonna say session run we're going to run the trainer and then we need to feed the training
for the trainer sort of say feed dictionary is equal to our X is just our X and then are y true.
So if we come up here remember that was the placeholder.
So we can just say placeholder here so here's our placeholder that's related to the actual loss function.
And we're going to say why true is that going to be that batch of white values.
Now the hard part when you're doing your own data is this line right here usually for other data sets.
You're not going to have such a convenient next batch function.
And that's kind of where the difficulty lies in when you're trying to apply tensor flow and these more
complicated models to your own data.
A lot of your time is going to be spent cleaning up the data and reshaping it and formatting it in a
way where you can easily grab batches.
So we'll show that in another example in the future.
But right now we're basically taking advantage of the fact that this train has a nice little Next batch
method.
Your life will always be this convenient but for now we'll take advantage of it.
The final step when you perform in this session is to actually evaluate our model.
So first we need to figure out where we actually predicted the correct label and we can use tensor Flo's
version of emacs to do that.
Remember arke Max is just a useful function which gives you the index position of the highest entry
point and with tensor flow it gives you the highest entry point of a tensor along some axis.
So let's go ahead and show you how to do that.
So outside of the for loop we're going to say time to evaluate the model.
So we're going to create this little correct prediction.
And this is going to do the following.
First let's kind of break it down into steps.
We're going to ask for the RMX of why member that is the why we come up here that is the output.
So what our prediction is.
So we're going to ask Hey where we're in this position is why the greatest.
And because we're using soft Max that's basically asking what is the highest probability class in the
in the expedition's match exactly up with the labels so we're fortunate there.
And the second argument one is just telling it to do this all on access equal to one.
So we have T.F. arguments here.
This is going to return the index position of the label with the highest probability essentially just
saying what label it thinks it is and then what we want to do is compare this to.
We put a comma here after RMX wups of the actual true values.
So that's going to be quite true.
One and I want to check where these are equal to so tensor flow has a nice equal function where I can
pass these two tensors in and it basically reports back a list of booleans.
So the result of this correct predictions looks like this is going to kind of comment here.
It's going to look something like True False True etc. all the way for all our predictions.
So again all we're doing here is this T.F. the RMX why come a one.
Essentially it directly outputs the predicted label because of the way we set up one encoding as well
as the fact the we using soft Max regression and the output of this is the same thing except for the
true values.
And then we check Well where are they equal to each other.
And that brings us this list of booleans.
Now we want to convert this list of booleans to something that looks like a list of zeros and ones we
want to have True's be one and then falses be zeros True's be ones etc..
So we want to convert that.
That way it's easier to work with mathematically and then do things like do a mean or average of them.
So we're going to say that our accuracy is going to be equal to T.F. reduce mean sensu is chicken taking
the average and then we want to cast that list of booleans or output of Blands into floating point.
So to do that sensor flow again has a convenience function called TFK.
Or you can passen the actual tensor.
In this case create prediction and as the second argument what you want to attempt to cast to every
data type can be cast to any other data type booleans can be cast it into a floating point numbers where
True's 1.0 and falses 0.0 throughness ATF flow 32.
And then we're going to take the average of that which is just for sensor flow.
Reduce mean.
So all we're doing here is this inside line of T.F. cast's is converting this list of Trium falses to
ones and zeros.
And then we're taking the average of that.
And that's just going to be your accuracy directly because remember our actual results here are just
ones and zeros.
All right let's actually take the time to kind of explain these two steps because there's actually a
lot going on here for just two lines of code.
We'll start off with T.F. RMX y one of the ATF RMX why.
True.
So basically what these two are going to output.
Let's imagine we just have one input so we're only predicting one label versus a y true label that we
would get something like this.
So the very first thing that would happen is we'd get two results here.
Would you get something like I believe the label is three and maybe the true label is three.
In fact let's do it for two.
So we have our predicted data.
So let's say we predicted that the first number was three and the second number was for and then for
our true data the actual label.
Let's say we got the first one right.
That was a three.
But the second one was a 9.
So you can see that sometimes when people had the right fours they sometimes look like nines.
So our particular algorithm wasn't able to catch that.
So that's what's going on here.
When we ask for ARC Max it just returns back to sort of list of the actual numbers it predicted for
the classes it says and I think the first 20 examples three in the second one is four.
And then we say well the real values were three and nine.
Then when we asked for a TAF equal then the result of that is something like this.
We say true and false because here we can see that they're equal that first one is equal.
The second one however is not equal for is not equal to nine.
So then that is a correct prediction.
True false.
The next step after that is to cast that correct prediction into T.F. of that flow essentially casting
it to ones and zeroes.
So then we get a list that looks like this one point zero and zero point zero then the final step is
to reduce the mean essentially take the average of this.
And if you take the average of that well that gives you back a single number 0.5 and that number directly
relates to the percentage that you got.
Correct.
And that's because these are ones and zeros.
So if we take the average of one and zero.
So 1 divided by two is there a point five which directly results into 50 percent correct and that's
her accuracy.
So just these two lines are doing what are essentially almost like four steps here.
So we compare the predicted the true values we get back a list of matches we convert that list of matches
to actual numbers ones and zeros.
And because they're ones and zeros it means directly through math.
If we take the average of those we get back the percent that we got right.
Or the accuracy.
So in this really simple example we've got 50 percent right out of two samples inputted compared to
there two true labels.
So then we can actually run this.
So say print the result of a session run and I'm going to run ack because this accuracy is essentially
its own graph.
So that's similar to what we did appear as far as the fighting steps the take except now we're just
actually running accuracy.
And then it needs its own feed dictionary so the feed dictionary we're going to feed in this time is
the actual test set.
So we'll say x is equal to just test images.
So those 10000 images and then we'll say why true is equal to minus test labels.
So again pretty convenient that we have those methods and attributes the call but that's what we're
doing here to evaluate our model.
We have this correct prediction which just turns the actual predicted labels and true labels into a
list of true or false booleans and then we convert that to ones and zeroes.
Take the mean of that are accuracy.
So we're going to run that accuracy in feet in our data as WIPs.
Make sure I have curly braces there because this is a dictionary as x.
Where are the test images and why true is this test labels.
So let's run that and make sure I don't have any typos here.
So late how many typos will run that C looks like I do have one dictionary that should be an equal sign.
There we go.
Now let's run that running this for a thousand steps.
It looks like we get 91 percent accuracy.
Now you may be thinking daar That's pretty good.
A 91 percent accuracy on handwritten digits that only took a few seconds on this computer.
Not bad.
Well in fact if you compare this to some of the latest models this actually isn't that great.
In fact some of the very best models can get over ninety nine point seven percent accuracy.
So what we're going to learn now later on is how we can use convolutional Nero that works to perform
much much better than just a high or low 90s.
We're going to get up to the high 90s.
OK so if you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums but really take your time to go through
all of these steps.
Remember that you create your placeholders create your variables you have your last function you have
your optimizer you create your session and then run it as far as converting this for your own data sources.
The hard part is this kind of next batch England grabbing those images and those test labels so this
is the tricky part and we're going to spore that more when we actually have the exercise for a data
set that's not going to have these convenience methods.
But for now we're taking advantage of that.
And then we can evaluate our model.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.