Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the convolutional neural networks.
We're going to continue right where we left off.
Remember we were discussing the original convolutional neural network diagram and we were trying to
get a understanding of what the convolutions were.
Now what we need to do is discuss the subsampling or pooling portion of a convolutional neural network
and it's actually quite a simple idea.
So pooling layers will subsample the input image which reduces the memory use in computer load as well
as reducing the number of parameters.
Let's imagine we have a layer of pixels in our image.
Here we have a relatively simple input image is just six by six.
And recall that for this digital data set each pixel has some sort of value representing what we will
call a darkness so 0 to 1 or maybe negative 1 2 1 etc..
So here we have numbers filled out.
You can imagine that this grid is entirely filled with numbers and the way pooling works is we create
a two by two pool of pixels and that's known as a kernel.
And then we evaluate the maximum value and it doesn't have to be two by two.
It can be in any size you want but two by two is a pretty common choice.
Again kind of depends on the size of your input data and what you do is inside of two by two kernel.
You evaluate the maximum value and only the max value makes its the next layer.
So you basically decide the maximum value is going to be representative of the entire kernel.
So here we can see we have a two beta kernel we check OK what is the maximum pixel value and that's
the only value that makes it the next layer.
Then we move over by a stride.
In this case we can imagine our stride is to grab the max value there and continue along.
Now this pooling layer is going to end up removing a lot of information and even a small pulling kernel
of two by two with a stride of two actually ends up removing 75 percent of the input data.
However we should know that this is a really common step of convolutional neural networks as that vast
amount of input data from an image.
It's just basically going to be too computationally expensive to not have pooling layers for now another
common technique deployed of convolutional neural networks is called dropout.
Now we've actually discussed dropout in the past but let's have a quick review.
Dropout can essentially be thought as a form of regularization to help prevent overfitting and during
training.
Units are randomly dropped along with their connections and this helps prevent units from CO adapting
too much to any particular training set.
Now it's also quickly point out some famous convolutional neural network architectures.
So we already discussed Linette Phi and Lakhan But there's also famous sets like Alex that Google that
are Googling that read that and you can check out the research links to papers discussing these architectures.
But essentially each of these architects architectures is just a set of design of layers.
So for example in Alex that will look like this it has a particular stride for its convolution that
has a particular pooling layer that another pulling layer than another convolution etc. and we can see
here Alex that basically the first convolutions or just edges and blobs.
Then the third convolution suits Cripe texture convolutions as we go higher and higher we get higher
abstraction so then we can see the object parts and then we can eventually see objects classes able
to distinguish things between like a dining table or clock a ship etc. so you can see here it's able
to do up to a thousand or a hundred classes.
Now realistically Alex that is so computationally expensive that it's actually distributed apart multiple
GPS use.
So you end up seeing diagrams that look like this where only half the image is going into one GPU and
the other half is going to another chip you.
OK so now he should fully understand the convolutional neural network.
Remember we have convolutions then we have subsampling or pooling and eventually towards the end we
have some sort of densely connected neural network and we can even have a soft Max regression if you
want to use that for our output.
You can check out the various supplementary resources that are linked to at the very beginning of the
section of the course.
But now that we've covered the basics of convolutional neural networks let's go ahead and explore how
to implement one intenser flow on the data set.
I'll see you at the next lecture.