Hello everyone and welcome to the data convolutional neural network code along in this lecture.
We're going to connect the theory ideas that we previously talked about to actual implementation of
code intenser flow.
Let's open up a Jupiter notebook and get started all right.
So the first thing I'm going to do is import sensor flow of course as T.F. and then I'm going to set
up the data just like we did before.
We'll say from tensor flow examples tutorials.
This import our input data then we'll say this is equal to input data function and then we're going
to call read data sets off this and then it makes the pass in the correct location.
Otherwise you may accidently redounded everything instead of just extracting it.
OK.
And we'll set one hot equal to true.
Just like we did before.
So now I have my data set.
I'm first going to create a couple of helper functions.
Zoom in one level here.
So I'll create a couple of helper functions and I'm first going to create a helper function that will
help me initialize the weights.
Of a layer.
The next one is going to help initialize the bias of a layer and then we'll have some other ones that
do return a to deconvolution.
So basically taking a tensor and taking a filter and apply it as a convolution and then also do a pooling
helper function.
After that we should have enough to actually build out functions that create layers themselves.
So let me do a couple of cells here and then start initializing weights so initializing weights is pretty
straightforward.
Going to create a function called initialize weights and then it just takes a shape which will provide
later on.
Depending on the size of your images and the size of sensors so I'll say it ran them distribution.
So I to just grabbed the weights from a random tradition and the distribution I'm going to use is a
truncated a normal distribution.
It's going to have the same shape and if you do shift tab here it can tell you you can apply mean standard
deviation etc..
We'll keep them around zero but we don't want such a high standard deviation.
So say 0.1 and then I'm going to return as a variable.
These weights so T.F. thought variable in its random distribution.
The next thing we're going to do is create a function that will initiate the bias values we'll see in
a bias.
It just takes in a shape and we'll say in bias.
Vowels are equal to and in this case we'll just have them all be the same value we'll just have them
all be constants of we'll say 0.1 and we'll have the shape be the shape.
So these are just constants and we're going to return them as a variable just as we see them in the
past.
So those are only in it by his vowels.
OK so we have our Random weights and we initialize the biases all 0.1 and they all taken a shape depending
on the tensor.
Up next we want to convenience function that helps create that 2D convolution.
So there already is a nice convenient function within tensor flow that automatically creates a to the
convolution.
What it does is it takes in an input tensor and an input kernel or filter tensor and then performs the
convolution on it depending on what strides and what padding you provide.
So what we're essentially going to do is create a little bit of a wrapper around it.
That sets the parameters for us.
So I'm going to create a function called seal on the to the.
And it takes in an X and a W.
So what does X and W X that's going to be our actual input tensor.
So the shape of that is going to be the batch.
So that's that batch of actual images that will have the height of the images the width of the images
and then the channels.
So these channels if it's grayscale are just going to be one grayscale channel.
If it's red green blue or a color image will have multiple channels there.
So this is essentially just the input data and then W is going to be that kernel.
Remember back to that grid.
And this is going to have the definitions of the heights all say filter heights then filter with then
the number of channels that are coming in and then the number of channels you want out.
So then we're going to return our built in intenser flow to the convolutions you can see here is a bunch
of convolutions already built in.
So each month the basic to the convolution we pass in the input sensor passenger filter and then there's
two parameters we want to set here which is why we're doing this as a convenient function.
The first one is strides.
So what strides do we want to take each way in each dimension.
In this case we're going to do pretty vanilla just ones in every direction.
And then the last one I want to do is padding so there are essentially two codes we can do here.
One is valid and one is same.
So if you want to make sure that the size is the same then you can pad it with zeros.
So we'll go ahead and do zero padding which the string code for that is same.
And you can check out if you do shift tab here.
It has the full docstring for this.
That explains the various codes and what they mean.
So eventually come down here it says padding.
You have same and valid and you can go to the documentation tells you what padding out room to use or
what Same counts and what value count says.
So we just want the same size.
So this basically zeros out that padding or adds in the zeros for the padding.
Then up next we're going to have our pooling layer.
So this pooling is going to be another convenience function.
Basically the same as we did here.
So there's already a tensor flow pooling function that does this for us and we're going to add in some
parameters as a bit of a convenience for us.
So we'll do a max pooling rumor that basically has this little grid and it grabs the max value in that
grid by a certain stride.
So I'll say this is a two by two max pooling it takes in some tensor X and this X is the same X that
we just described.
So this X is just going to be the Bachche the heights the width and the channels here.
So it's that the tensor and then we're going to return the convenience function that's already built
into sensor flow so sensor already has the max pool.
And this takes in the actual tensor you want to apply this to and then it has a couple of parameters
case size strides and then padding.
So we already know what padding is that just pads it was duros sold put the same code there and then
we have case size and Streitz so case size is the size of the window for each dimension of the input
sensor and strides is the stride of the sliding window for each dimension of the input sensor.
Remember our input tensor is going to be a bunch of images so that's that batch dimension that we have
the height and width of an individual image and then the color channel.
So the only that basically pooling that I want to do is along the height and width of an individual
image which means as far as the size is concerned I'm going to do a one that I'm going to have a two
by two along the height and width.
So that's the actual pooling.
And then a again along the channels and I'm going to do the same thing for streite.
So we're going to stride by two.
So say one two by two and then one again and whoops there he goes.
There are my strides.
So again we're only really concerned as far as the pooling along in individual images height and width
which is why we're getting these images of 1 2 2 1 and 1 2 2 1.
So now we have our convenience functions that basically already set these parameters for us that we
don't need to provide them every time.
All we need to do now is call our little shorter functions instead of calling these long ones with these
parameters over and over again.
Now we're going to create two functions where we actually create the layers.
So the first one is going to be the convolutional air.
So this function in fact we'll just call it convolutional layer is going to take some input X and then
the shape parameter so we'll create the weights by asking in weights with the shape and the biases are
just going to run along the third dimension.
So I'll say it biases and then we're just going to pass in shape three here.
And then I'm going to return T.F. tensor flow and.
I'm going to use a rectified linear unit as the activation function.
So say r e l you and I'm going to pass in the to the convolution of input X with those weights Plus
the biased terms and that's my convolutional layer then I'm going to do just a normal layer or essentially
a fully connected layer.
So we'll make this function say normal full layer.
And this is going to take in some input layer of a size and we'll say the input size is equal to the
integer of the input layer.
And we want to get the shape of the index one they mention will say w initialize the weights and then
we're going to pass passen input size by size to create that layer and then we'll say B is equal to
initialize by its size.
And we're going to return T.F. makes for small allocation.
Remember this is just a normal fully connected layer of the input layer.
It's times the weights Plus the buys strips.
So now we have two functions one creates a convolutional air one creates a normal fully connected layer.
So it's time to actually build out multiple layers along with the placeholders do a loss function do
an optimizer initialize the variables and run the session.
I would say the hardest part of all of this is keeping in mind your dimensions.
Once you do this multiple times if image sets you start to get pretty.
So this idea of these for them actions just across the board you have your batch your height your with
your channels but in the very beginning it can be hard to keep track or just try to visualize these
kind of for the tensors floating around in the layers so it definitely takes a lot of practice as a
quick note to kind of understand these dimensions and have them be intuitive.
It's definitely not intuitive at first.
At least it wasn't for me when I was first starting out but now it's go ahead and start building out
our convolutional all that work.
So the first thing we're going to do here is create our placeholders.
So we have X is going to be a placeholder.
This is our actual data so I'll say to 32 and we'll see the shape we'll say none because that's the
size of that batch.
And then 784 because that's how many pixels are in the data.
So that's 28 times 28.
Then we have y true.
These are the y true labels remember it's one encoded.
Which means when I say to flip 32 I'll pass in the shape as none because it's again going to be the
batch size and then 10 because it's 0 through 9 because they're 100 coded.
So those are my placeholders.
I only use those for the feed dictionaries and now it's time to actually create the layers
so the first one we're going to say is the image layer.
That's essentially our input and we're going to take an the input X and I'm going to reshape it to the
following shape say negative 1 28 by 28 comma 1.
So why am I doing this because I want to reshape this flattened out array into the image again.
So 28 by 28 That's the height and width.
I remember this one.
It's just greyscale.
There's only one color channel there.
So now that's my image.
And then I go start off with my first convolutional.
So I'll say convo one.
So I have a convolutional where I need to provided the image and then I need to provide essentially
the shape of the actual weight tensor.
So this is where you can kind of play around with the values here.
We'll go ahead and follow that initial diagram we saw back in the slides where were has a five by five
convolutional there.
And then we'll say 1 and 32.
So basically this convolution is going to compute 32 features for each five by five patch.
So that means the weight sensor is a 5 5 1 and 32.
So those first two dimensions are the patch size.
So that's the actual patch five by five.
The next number is the input channels.
Remember we're dealing with grayscale So just one.
And then this last number 32.
That's the actual features you're computing.
So that's the number of output channels.
Then once I finished with that first convolutional there I'll go ahead and do my first puling layer.
So say the pulling layer that's attached to this first convolution is convo one pooling then going to
call my max pulling function.
So I was Max pool two by two and then just passen the results of that first convolutional air.
The next thing we're going to do is build our second set of layers so another convolutional air followed
by another pooling layer.
So say convoke too is going to be another convolutional layer that takes the output of that previous
fooling layer.
So I'll say convo one pooling and in order to build a deep network we're going to stack several layers
of this type.
So we want to do here.
For the shape give it the same five by five patches before and then remember or input right now is going
to now be 32.
And we'll say we want 64 features for each five by five patch and then we'll pass this in with pulling
again.
So we'll say convo to pooling is equal to max pool two by two and then we're going to pasan convert
to.
There we go.
Then finally we're going to flatten out this result Lehre so that we can connect it to a fully connected
player.
So we will say convo two flats is going to be convert to pooling except we're going to reshape it will
say kind of the two pulling we'll say minus one by and since we know you have a 7 by 7 image remember
the output here with 64.
We're going to say seven times seven times 64 and then we'll say fool or one is just equal to T.F. we'll
do a rectify linear unit for activation and we'll pass that normal full error with the flattens Larry
here convert to flat and then we decide on how many neurons we want here.
So we'll do 1024 run that and it looks like we may have a typo somewhere that says tensor object has
no attribute get shape.
So let's go back up to this normal foolisher if we take a look at get shape here.
I believe this should have an underscore.
Now let's run that again.
Come back here.
Run this again.
OK good.
So that takes care of that.
And then let's go ahead and add a dropout.
So what we do here for the dropouts try to prevent overfitting is we'll say create some holding probabilities
be placeholder
to float 32 and we'll say fool one drop out.
And luckily tensor flow has a nice convenient function for a dropout.
And he basically just passing the letter.
So we'll say fool layer 1 and the probability that it's kept.
So say keep probability is equal to the placeholder hold probability.
That way we can find it later on.
And then finally we'll say why predictions is equal to a normal full air pass in that full one drop
layer.
And then since we have 10 labels will pass and a 10 here.
OK so that's all are layers.
Up next we're going to do is create a last function and optimizer initialize the variables and then
run our session.
We'll go ahead and continue right where we left off in the very next lecture.