Welcome back everyone.
Here we are right where we left off last time we've defined all our layers and all that's left to do
is create a lost function our optimizer initialize the variables and then run a session.
So let's start for a last function we'll use cross entropy to be our last function and we essentially
just use the built in functions that are already intenser for us so we say reduce mean to take an average
and we'll say soft Max cross entropy and we're going to say that the labels is equal to y true which
will be provided by our dictionary later on and then we'll say logic is to why spreads why.
There we go OK it's all run that and then what we're going to do is set up our optimizer So our optimizer
we're going to go ahead and use an atom optimizer say Adam optimizer and then we'll say the learning
rates is zero point zero 0 1 and then our trainer is just going to beat for this optimizer to minimize
our loss which in our case is the cross entropy loss.
Then we're going to initialize our variables so say an equal to T.F. global variables initializer OK
now it's time to define our session.
So I'll say we'll run this for 5000 steps.
Keep in mind I'm running on a really fast computer it's also a GPU accelerated on a very good high end
graphics card so you may have to wait a while.
Much longer than I am to get results.
This could take up to several hours so keep that in mind.
Depending on the speed of your computer.
So say session run in it and then we'll say for I in range steps and again reduce the number of steps.
If you have a slower computer you won't end up getting as accurate results but they'll still run and
will say batch X that y.
Same deal as last time we're basically just grabbing from the next batch 50 so we'll do 50 images at
a time and this batch and then we're going to say session run run the training the optimizer and then
we need feed dictionary.
So remember that we actually have three placeholders.
We have the two classic ones which is just x and y.
So we'll say X is batch x and y true is that y.
And then we have the hold probability because remember we are designing that dropout layer appear.
We have this whole probability which is a placeholder and that basically is the probability that a neuron
is held during dropout.
So during training we'll go ahead and say 50 percent.
So each near on has a 50 percent chance of being held essentially randomly dropping out half our neurons
they'll say if I bought one hundred equals equals zero.
Meaning if you're on step divisible by 100 every 100 steps we're going to do something every 100 steps
we're going to report back our accuracy on the Tesa will say print will say on Stapp and then I can
use that format here.
So in a safe format I that I'm going to print accuracy.
And let's go ahead and calculate our accuracy.
We'll do the calculation essentially just like with last time will say T.F. equal T.F. RMX y pred come
a 1.
So this is the exact same calculation we did previously and will say T.F. RMX y true comma 1.
OK so we have our matches remember that's a list of booleans So we want to cast it into a list of floats
and then take the average.
So accuracy isn't equal to T.F. reduce mean and I'm going to cast that list of booleans that is the
matches into 32 perfect then it we'll say print the result of session run and I'm going to run that
accuracy measurement in my feed dictionary is then going to be the test results or the test set.
I should say so this test images.
So those are actual images that I'm feeding in.
And then why true is going to be honest.
Test labels.
Let me zoom out one level here so we can see the whole thing labels and then remember I still have one
placeholder for hold probability and there is the testing.
I don't want to actually drop neurons so I will say hold probability is 1.0.
Basically no neuron is going to be dropped because they'll have a hundred percent chance of being held
and there we're going to print a new line OK.
Let's make sure we don't have any typos.
Let's try to run this.
And there we go.
So you can see it's already started as you go and read out of the gate even just that 100 steps or you
have 94 percent accuracy which is really good.
And you can see here it's continuing and a 6 percent 97 is 7.
So this isn't exactly state of the art but it's still pretty darned good.
You can see here already approaching 98 after almost just two thousand steps.
So hopefully if we keep running this long enough and we can play around with the size of the convolutions
we'll get closer to 99 percent.
So 98 98 etc..
So you can see here a huge improvement by using convolutional Lares and pooling layers.
All right.
So I hope you enjoy that exercise eventually at the end.
We got pretty close to 99 percent accuracy.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q Any forums.
Coming up next is going to be your exercise for convolutional neural networks.
I'll see you at the next lecture.