Hello everyone and welcome to your exercise for this section of the course where you're going to be
using convolutional neural networks to classify the famous see far 10 dataset.
So this is an optional exercise to see far 10 data set to see a certain data set consists of sixty thousand
32 by 32 color images in 10 classes with 6000 images per class where there are 50000 training images
and 10000 test images to make a total of 60000 images.
Now the reason this is optional is because it is actually quite challenging especially given what we
know so far about convolutional neural networks and the main challenge is actually dealing with the
data and creating tensor batches and making sure everything has the right dimensions and size actually
creating that convolutional layers and creating the pulling layers.
Given what we've already covered is pretty straightforward.
In fact it's almost the exact same process as what we've just heard before.
And you can actually vary some of the parameters.
The real hard part is getting this data as an image and then creating that next batch function or actually
sizing it correctly.
Because remember with the data set all of that was taken care of for us under the hood.
When you're dealing with real data sets your own images or images that don't have these convenience
functions you're going to spend a lot of time actually creating those convenience functions.
And in the exercise notebook a lot of that's already been pre-filled out for you because it is a quite
challenging and time consuming.
So we're going to go through the exercise notebook and then you can decide whether or not you feel like
just treating this as a code along lecturer so you'll skip to the solutions lecture and code along or
feeling a little more ambitious just try your best and see how far you can get on your own through the
exercise notebook.
So let's open up that exercise notebook and show you where you can find the data.
Ok so here I am under the convolutional neural networks folder.
You should notice that there is a CNN project exercise notebook file go ahead and click on that one
and you'll also notice that there's a folder here called See four batches dash pi.
That's where the actual data is contain and it comes in five little batches here.
So keep that in mind and when you open up the exercise notebook you'll notice that there is a description
of what you're going to end up doing.
You're essentially going to be classifying between 10 classes or color images and you're going to follow
along with the instructions in bold.
Now step 0 called get the data actually already has all of this essentially filled out for you.
So you're going to load the data and you're going to use the code here.
That's already been made for you.
And the reason for this is it is really time consuming process and you're basically going to have to
manually convert these images and create these next batch convenience functions.
And because that's really time consuming and it doesn't actually have a lot to do of convolutional neural
networks it's more just kind of the dirty work of working in a python.
It's already been filled out for you so you can focus on learning about convolutional neural networks.
So if you scroll down here there's a lot of explanation about the data how it's formatted.
So there's tons of text.
You're free to read through then displaying a single image using that plot lib.
There's also little examples of showing that so there's some code here that says you need to fill this
out.
Put the code here that transforms the X array etc..
And once you're done kind of dealing with the data there is a little helper functions here such as the
one high end coding.
Then there's also a class that I made for you to set up the images of training setting them up and then
grabbing that next batch.
And it shows you how you can use the above code then you'll get to the create model.
And that's where you end up having a bunch of empty cells free to fill out.
And then she wants you to recreate those helper functions that we did earlier basically going to look
really similar to the ones we did in the dataset.
And if you want you can just kind of copy and paste if you forget what they look like then you'll create
the layers again.
And there's hints here on what shapes and what sizes to use.
So you can scroll down loss function optimizer graph session etc..
Now keep in mind this is going to take a long time to run.
I have a really fast computer so I ran it for let's see River 5000 steps and got 17 percent accuracy.
So we should kind of aim for around that and again kind of the whole half our first half of dealing
with the data.
It's been technically fill that for you.
But what I really want you to do is if you try to do this as an exercise go line by line and make sure
you understand a lot of this code actually that even write it.
It comes with the data set itself.
So for instance is an pickling function that actually if you go to the link of where to download the
data.
So if you come over here to download data and click on this link they'll take you to the data source
and then if you scroll down here the providers of the data actually kind of have instructions here of
how to open the data and pickle it etc..
So this is actually the code that's directly here in the notebook.
So if you're an independent researcher and trying to work this data you would've already had this code
available for you anyways.
And this is just kind of some convenience functions to working the code.
OK.
So take your time with this project.
It's a it's pretty challenging to be perfectly honest as it should be convolutional neural networks
are not the easiest thing in the world.
So take your time with this see how far you can get.
Again if you're going to do it as an exercise please make sure to read and go step by step through what
is the step zero of getting the data before you jump forward to actually creating the network.
So all of these cells need to be run.
You should be understanding every line as part of the exercise and will be going through that throughout
the solutions before you actually end up creating the model.
So don't just skip to create the model.
Make sure you understand all the code before it.
All right.
So coming up next we're gonna have a series of lectures going through this project and treating it as
a code along solution.
Again it's optional it's up to you whether you want to treat it as a code along.
If you ever get stuck during the exercise please check over to the solutions video where we'll have
full explanations for all the steps.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.