Welcome everyone to solutions.
Part one for the Safar it's an exercise for convolutional neural networks.
Let's go straight to the Jupiter notebook and get started.
OK.
Here we are for the project exercise notebook.
And a lot of the first steps in step zero is to just organize and get the data.
So there's already a link here in the notebook where you can download the data.
Keep in mind it's already been downloading for you.
So instead we're going to do just put a file path here as a stream to where the directory of the data
is.
And in this case it's for 10 batches pie from the zip file.
So that's a directory that contains several files that about 1 that attach to that about 5 et cetera
as well as test batch.
So each of those files is a python pickled object that's been produced with the Python C pickle library
which is essentially just a way of storing data.
So what we end up doing is we use this code right here on pickle to open up those files essentially
we're going to run these cells and then I have a list here of directory names that's already there underneath
that folder.
So we have batches mete out about 1 out of each two etc. all the way through that about 5.
And then we have our test batch.
So then I also have a corresponding all data 0 through 6 so essentially index or indices for that.
So we're going to do is run these two.
And I guess you could have also used enumerate instead of zippin these together like I did.
But we're going to say that the object all data index i.
Is that equal to an pickling Safar directory plus direc.
So all I'm doing is I'm saying OK for each of these files that's underneath this directory.
Go ahead and then put it in the list that the index position.
So if we come back up here and check out these actual files I'm basically saying unpick all these files
and then save them as part of the list.
So we're going to run these lines then and then when I'm going to do is each of these items in the list
I'm going to assign them to each variable.
That way I can easily call these variables.
So now I have variable names that essentially match up with the directory names.
So then I'm willing to run that cell.
And if we take a look at the first one that's essentially the meta data for this dataset.
So we have a dictionary here.
There's label names and these are all the possible labels or there's 10 labels here says pictures of
airplanes birds dogs frogs etc. also ships and trucks that we have 10000 number of cases per batch.
And there's also a note here on why there's bees in front of these strings of basically a way of denoting
and by literals.
And that's actually important because when you're using the keys of this dictionary you need to provide
the be there.
So that's why there's a little link here to a stack overflow post on that.
OK so then we also have the number of them mentions three thousand seventy two.
We'll explore that later on if we take a look at just one of these variable objects or remember this
and we just created up here at about one and we say keys off of it.
Notice we have the file names the data the batched label and then the labels themselves.
So when it's loaded this way each of the batch files contains a dictionary with the following elements.
First off it has the data already represented as a ten thousand by three thousand seventy two an umpire
array of integer numbers where each row of the array stores a 32 by 32 color image.
So you can already tell that it's actually a flattened out the first 1200 are 1024 entries contain the
red channel values the next are the green ones and the next are the blue ones so we already have to
start thinking about tensors with depth for that channel.
And then we also have the labels so that's a list of 10000 numbers in the range 0 through 9.
So the number index indicates the label of the image in the array data.
So this is just one hot encoding and each of these numbers that corresponds to one of these labels so
0 airplane 1 automobile etc. So in the dataset contains another file called batches of matter and to
also contains the python dictionary object and it's actually the one we were exploited up here has the
label names that correspond to those numbers.
All right.
So your real first part where you were asked to start coding something was to display a single image
using that plot lib.
You actually got a lot of helpful hints and code here.
So we wanted you to grab a single image from data batch one and display it with real teeth that show.
And there's actually several ways of doing this the Pennyhill want to do it one image at a time or reformat
the entire tensor images.
So you need to reshape and transpose an umpire array inside the data batch.
So you need to call data dictionary and then you could reshape all the images for formatted viewing
using this one line command.
So we'll do it this way first.
It will show you kind of a more intuitive way of how to do it one image at a time.
This transpose command is kind of hard to understand because it's essentially transposing for them engines.
So we run this mapped plot lib and map Libin line important umpire et cetera.
Then we're going to say is the following we'll say x is equal to data batch 1.
So it's our first batch of data and I'm going to grab that data from it.
Now unfortunately if I just say data they'll say hey that key is not there.
That's because of the byte string issue from before.
So has the box here which means I need actually provide an B and then I'll have the data.
So if I take a look at the current shape of my X it's right now 10000 images and essentially all the
pixel data for each image has been kind of flattened out into three thousand seventy two.
So that comes from for Take a look here.
We have 32 32 pixels and three color channels for each of them.
That's where that three thousand seventy two is coming from.
So each of these images is 32 by 32 and then we have three sets of information essentially one greyscale
image per color channel.
So one representation of reds one representation of greens and one representation of blues.
So we're going to do essentially copy and paste this command here.
And this will conveniently reshape and format all the images for viewing.
So if you run that and then check out one of those images 0 you in the beginning the Saray and this
is an array the capacity directly with Piel t m show.
So if take a look at the shape of the.
It's 32 by 32 and then it has three.
So basically has 32 by 32 pixels and 3 stacked layers one for each color channel.
And this is something that T are guilty the show can understand and they can say Piazzi show and see
x 0.
And here we can see a picture of a frog 32 by 32 pixels and you can grab kind of other random images
let's say 99 you can see here is a picture of a car.
I don't know THIRTY-NINE there's a picture of let's say a cat.
It's kind of small here.
Of these you can see aren't really that clear even for humans.
I would say that's a duck or goose.
Maybe their neck 12 horse OK.
Nice.
All right so we saw to do this one line kind of all automatically.
Let's go ahead and explore what's actually happening here of transpose and this reshape.
By doing this all one image at a time in a manual fashion.
So I'll come back down here and I'm going to reread the data in well say about one and I'm going to
grab that data and if I take a look at the shape of my data I can see that it's in 10000 by three thousand
seventy two.
So I already know I need to reshape it.
It's still 10000 training images.
But I need to reshape it into three color channels 32 by 32 pixels.
So then let's go ahead and say this is all my images so now they have all my images.
Let's go ahead and just grab one.
So I'll say this is a sample image.
So if you take a look at my sample now I have this and the array.
Now if I take a look at the shape of my sample it's three 32 32.
So that actually doesn't work for Piel t show because remember Altium show needs it to be 32 by 32 pixels.
And then the three color channels here.
Which means if I actually tried to do something like this where I say peel t him show on this one sample
it's going to report back hey you have the wrong dimensions here.
So if you scroll down it says Invalid dimensions for image data which means I need to kind of shift
this around.
So if I take a look at my shape again I can see here I have along the zero axis the three color channels
and then along Axis 1 and access to those 32 pixels.
So I will end up doing is I will say sample and then I'm going to transpose this and I'm going to shift
these two over one to the left and then set the zero axis all the way to the end essentially matching
up all we have over here.
So those comments are then pretty straightforward.
I'm going to set the values at access one and access to when I transpose this to the first and then
I want the values on Access 0 to be all the way at the end just like they are over here.
So then we shift that zero.
So you can see each of these numbers corresponds with the index position of the previous shape and then
the location underneath this transpose method basically shifts them.
So now if I say peel t him show off this one sample I can see the sample of the frog.
So that's how you could do this and you could kind of make a function out of this to basically reset
the shapes of each individual image.
Now in order to do it across the entire array that's where this transpose comes into play.
And this as type you are eight that comes directly from the link.
So basically tells you to use as type.
OK so let's go in and move along.
So you can circle those various images here.
Here's an image of a truck.
Here's an image of a car etc..
All right.
The final thing we have to do is just go through these helper functions for dealing with the data.
And part one of our solutions lecture the very first thing was this function one high end code which
just takes in a vector of labels and then we don't have 10 possible values and it's going to return
essentially as a to the matrix of just a bunch of arrays of one hot and coded for the 10 possible labels.
So we say end is equal to the length of that vector of labels.
We make the output equal to zeros where it's.
And so that's the number of actual inputs in that vector by vals.
We know vals is 10 because there's 10 possible labels.
So we have and by 10 then we're going to just basically reassign out where range n is going to basically
access that current vector and then we're going to set that equal to 1.
So we have our range of in comma there.
So that's the indexing set that to 1 and then return that out.
So essentially it's the Matrix where each entry is going to be that list of one high end coded labels.
We have this class Safar helper.
And this there's a bunch of stuff.
So I'm going to zoom out one level here so we can kind of get a look at it all.
So the first thing it does it grabs a list of all the data batches for training.
So it's dated batches 1 through 5 and then we have the test batch.
So that's just the test batch we initialize them into variables for later on we have self-training images
self-training labels self-test images and self-test labels.
Then after that we have this other method called set up images.
And what this does is it just sets up the images.
So it does it through reshaping and transposition just like we did appear.
If you scroll back up what it's basically going to do is set this up so this reshape transposition for
all those batches of data.
So what we did there manually is going to end up doing it across the entire data set.
So what it does is it vertically stacks the training images using the stack here.
So it does that for all the training batches that grabs the data 4-D and all the training batches than
vertically stacks them together.
So now you have those 50000 training images.
So the train length should be equal to then 50000 and then we're going to reshape.
And we're also going to normalize the training images.
If you notice back up when we were kind of plotting these values let's see if there's any values here.
I guess not.
So scratch one of these.
So if we see the max here it's actually two five.
So we want that to be one.
So coming back down here all we're gonna do is after we do the reshape to 3:32 32 and then we do the
transposition.
We're going to say divide by 255.
So it's basically just dividing by the max value to normalize the images that we're going to one hot
encode the training labels off of that.
So we're going to horizontally stacked this and then we're going to say grab the labels 4-D and self-taught
all trained batches.
So remember we have all we have this other dictionary entry or key for labels just like we have for
data that is going to print setting up test images and test labels.
So it's going to do basically the exact same thing.
But now for the test images.
So we did it for the training images appear.
Repeat that for the test images and then we have this next batch method which is going to serve pretty
much the exact same way the next batch image method works for that.
And this dataset.
So we're going to say x is equal to self-taught training images.
And what I'm going to do here is just note that the 100 dimension in the reshape call is set by an assumed
Bache size of 100.
So I have a hundred here and that's because later on I'm going to assume that batch size is going to
be equal to 100.
Well I could also do is an passen batch size here.
OK so then we say reshaped by 132 three to three.
So again hundreds because I'm assuming the batches of 100 and then I'm going to grab from Celta I up
to Celta I plus the bat size for training images and then for the trained labels I'm going to say self-taught
I up to CELTA.
Plus the batch size then I will say Celta eyes to Celta I plus the batch size then I'm going to do a
mod by the length of the self-training images and then return x and y.
And that's basically just my Bachche.
So how do we actually use all this above code.
All you have to do is before UTF session you run these two lines you create an instance of Safar helper.
Then you set up the images and then if you want to grow a batch you just do this batch is equal to that
object.
Next batch give me 100.
All right.
So that's all you have to do.
And up next is creating the model.
So we'll go ahead and do that in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.