Welcome everyone to part two of the solutions for the Safar it's an exercise.
Let's go right to where we left off last time and finish this up.
All right so mainly the solutions.
One was just going through the code that was already provided for you in understanding how it actually
works and how it actually produces images.
Now it's time to actually create the model.
So we're going to do the following I'll say imports tensor flow as T.F. and then we're going to create
two placeholders one for data X and then y true.
So their shapes should make sense to you.
Now we have T-Rexes a placeholder and it's going to be T.F. flow thirty two or three Remember the need
to provide a data type and the shape is just going to be none because that's dictated by the batch size.
And then we're doing 3 2 3 2 3 3 2 3 2 pixels three color channels then we're going to say why true
is equal to a placeholder as well to 32 as well.
And then this shape is just going to be none because of the batch size.
And then 10 because it's one encoded.
So again your typical shapes is going to be images height width and then channels just like we did for
the digits data set.
So I had these two placeholders for my data and my labels and I'm going to create one more cold hold
probability and no need for shape here because it's essentially going to be a single number of what
percentage you want for the probability that neurons are being hold when we actually perform dropout.
All right so now we have a whole probability then we have the helper functions.
So you have the option of grabbing the helper functions or seeing if you can recreate them yourself
for hard challenge.
Well just go ahead since you've already gone through these in great detail during the mist with CNN
we'll just copy and paste them here.
So remember we initialize weights initialized bias.
We have these helper functions for a to the convolution Max pool two by two.
And then convolutional.
And normal full layer.
And if you want you can kind of play around with these sizes maybe you want to see three by three pulling
or maybe you want to do different strides for convolutional to the.
Again totally up to you.
But we'll go ahead just use the same values as last time.
Should be fine for our purposes.
And now it's time to create the letters.
So we're essentially going to create the same type of layers as we did last time.
Again a lot of these sizes are up to you just some things are going to be aware of the fact that three
color channels and that the shapes are 32 by 32.
So we'll start off creating convo 1.
So our first convolution layer is convo underskirt one that's going to be a convolutional Lehre takes
center data X and then our shape will go ahead and have it be four by four.
And then we'll say three and three to
and then we're going to do a pooling layer after this all say convoke one pooling.
And that's just going to be equal to that Max pool function.
And then we passen Canova 1 now it's up to you what size you want these actual convolutional filters
to be here we're just using four by four but you can always play around with those values.
So next we want to create in other convolutional there.
So it's going to do that we'll say Canova 2 is equal to a convolutional layer and then we're going to
input the result of the first pooling will say shape is equal to 4 4 and then all going to say 32 64
here and then we're going past that into pulling so convoke to pooling is equal to max pool two by two
and then pass and the result of convo to OK.
So we have to convolutional errors leading into two pulling layers.
So we have kind of one leading and one pulling that leads into the second convolutional there and then
we have pulling after that.
So next we're going to create a flattened layer by reshaping that pulling layer into minus 1 8 by 8
time 64 or essentially negative 1 four thousand ninety six and we did a really similar step with the
digits dataset.
So we're going to see convo to flat and always say tenderfoot reshape going to reshape that last puling
layer and we're going to reshape it to negative one by eight times eight times 64 so that you create
a new fooler using the normal full air function using this fine layer all these 1024 neurons will say
full layer 1 is equal to T.F..
And again this is going to be a normal error that uses the rectified linear unit.
As the activation functions will say normal full convo to flat 1024.
Next we're going to create the dropout layer.
So that's also pretty straightforward we'll say.
Fool ONE drop out is equal to tensor flow.
Neural Network dropout full air 1 and we'll say the probability for being held is equal to that placeholder
recreated hold prob and hopefully this feels really familiar.
This needs to be keep prob not just prob keep prob there we go.
And like I was saying hopefully it feels really familiar because this is almost in line directly from
the examples that we walk through.
So finally we need to set the output so we'll say that our predicted y value is equal to a normal flare
that has the full one dropout layer and then 10 year on is here because there's 10 possible errors.
Now we're going to use a loss functionally as a cross entropy loss function.
Well say cross entropy is equal to T.F. reduce mean.
And then we'll say T.F. and thought and then we call soft Max cross entropy and will provide the labels
to be quite true.
And the logic is to be why spreads are predicted values.
They're essentially comparing our predictions to the true values that we want an optimizer.
So we'll say optimizer.
And this is basically the same things we did last time is T.F. train we're going to use an atom optimizer
and we'll set the learning rate to be zero point zero zero or 1 something you can kind of play around
with there as well.
And then we want to use that optimizer to minimize our loss.
So say optimizer minimize cross entropy.
Next create that in a variable that we always do to initialize everything so global variables initialiser
OK.
Now it's time for the graph session.
So you can see here we already have some output so I'm going to clear that by running in that cell that's
empty.
And let's build that will say with T.F. session as SPSS.
I'm going to say a session run will say T.F..
Actually you just need to say in it's here
and then for I in range.
And this is up to you how many train steps you want to do.
I did five thousand.
So let's try that out.
Our batch is going to be equal to C.H. the next batch.
So we want to make sure that we provide a batch size in there.
So if we scroll back up remember there's instructions here and how to actually use the above code to
make sure that we actually ran it.
So we're going to create an instance of that Safar helper and then set up the images.
So if you run this lips Safar help result define wups for author on these cells.
There we go and let's make sure 100 codes not define that or come up here and run this one too.
So now that I ran these two there you go.
So it set up the training images labels set up test images labels.
It's ready to go.
So should be ready to feed batches using this next batch command will come back down here.
It will say we'll grab a at a time.
And as I mentioned earlier you can change about if you want.
There was a session run train and we need to provide a feed dictionary will say x is equal to match
zero.
Why true is then going to be that one and we'll provide a hold probability of 0.5 just like we did last
time.
So a 50 percent chance of being held next we're going to run some tests here.
So I will say if I mod 100 as equal to zero meaning or on a hunter's step are basically a step that's
the visible by a hundred.
Say Prince the step and we'll just say that format.
I say things with it and this dataset.
Let's zoom in here to see it clearly.
Then we're going to do the exact same thing as the last time we'll say matches T.F. equal T.F. RMX of
widespread one and they'll say T.F. RMX of y true come a 1.
So that returns that Boulia a list of where they matching.
Set up an accuracy measurement which is going to be reduced mean and I want to cast that list of booleans
So when the cast matches to be to float 32 and then I'm going to print out session run run that accuracy
and then we want to provide a feed dictionary now of the test data sets.
So we do that is we basically just call it off that Helper Object that we created so we can say S.H.
grabbed the test images.
Why true it's going to be S.H. groud the test labels.
So these are attributes from the subject and they will say hold probability is just 1.0.
So we want everything to be held while we're testing and old print new line
OK.
Let's go in and run this check for any typos I'm sure I made one or two.
So run that.
OK.
Looks like we actually are doing pretty good.
So immediately right off the bat we're jumping straight to 50s and I'm going to fast forward in time
until this is done training for 5000 steps.
But you can already see we're kind of approaching 70 percent accuracy which is kind of what we're shooting
for.
So let me jump forward in time until this is done training for 5000 steps.
OK.
So after around 5000 steps looks like we just barely hit that 70 percent accuracy mark that we were
looking for.
But mind this may take a long time to run on your computer the pending on how fast the computer you
have especially if you're just using CPQ.
Right now I'm running this with GPS so it only took me around one or two minutes to run this whole thing.
It could take definitely much much longer depending on how powerful your computer is and if your computer
is really low power you may even run out of memory.
So kind of keep that in mind.
You can always use other services like AWOS or paper space to try to run some of this online.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I hope you found this exercise enjoyable.
And now we definitely encourage you to kind of play around of some of these values.
Now you play around the shapes of the filters and just really make sure you understand the basic flow
here.
It should feel really analogous to what we did together with the data.
Again really hard part for when you're dealing with your own data is basically creating this class that
kind of handles the images and reshapes them.
I would say is probably by far the hardest part because as far as the convolutions are concerned a lot
of that there are just too lenience calls and just taking advantage of tensor Fullers built in functionality.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next section of the course.