Welcome everyone to this overview lecture on reinforcement learning.
So is reinforcement learning reinforcement learning allows machines.
And what we're later going to call software agents to automatically determine the ideal behavior within
a specific contexts such as playing a game in order to maximize the performance in that context such
as getting a high score in that game.
So reinforcement learning uses a simple reward feedback and it's required for the agent to learn its
behavior.
And this is known as that reinforcement signal basically reinforcing good behavior.
So there's lots of different types of algorithms that fall under reinforcement learning and you should
know that not all of these algorithms actually require frameworks such as tensor flow.
Now all of them need some sort of neural network tensor flow situation.
OK so let's discuss the four main things that concern reinforcement learning.
And that is the agent the environment the action and the reward.
So all these four things are connected through basically a loop.
You have the agent which is what we're actually going to be programming you can essentially think of
that as either your network or software program et cetera.
The agent is going to take in observations and also a reward later on from the environment and the environment.
A lot of times when you're reading about reinforcement learning it's some sort of game.
It doesn't always have to be a game.
It can basically be anything you want it to be such as learning how to walk down a path.
But in this case and because we're going to be using open gym later on we'll mostly be dealing of games.
But once you take an observations from that environment you get to perform an action on that environment
and that basically creates a loop.
So you have your agent it performs an action onto the environment such as moving a piece in whatever
specific game you're playing.
And then from that it taken observations and you also take in a reward level and the reward level basically
the finds how well you performed in that environment.
So let's break this down a little more formally.
So our agent or program or bot it can receive inputs based off the environment and it can also perform
actions that we have the environment itself.
That's the actual setting that the agent is interacting with.
A lot of times it's often a game and examples but it can really be any real world or artificial environment.
And keep in mind you need to be able to represent this environment in a way that an agent can understand.
So what I mean by that is that they need to be some sort of array or some sort representation that your
program can understand.
So if you're dealing with a real world environment such as teaching a robot how to walk down a hill
you're going to need to have cameras on that robot and then eventually those images need to be translated
to arrays that your agent can understand.
Now previously it was actually really difficult to create environments that were easy to use and that
were shareable.
But later on we're going to discover how open the eyes Jim library actually helped solve this pretty
big problem so we can actually focus on building agents instead of building all the necessary frameworks
of an environment.
Now as far as the action is concerned that's the actual interaction your agent will perform on the environment.
So you can move in an environment maybe choose the next move in a game etc..
That's the actual action.
Then comes the reward after you perform an action.
So the reward is a metric that allows your agent to understand whether or not the previous sets of actions
either helped or hurt in its overall goal.
So these four aspects are fundamental to reinforcement learning and the way open gym works with variables
designed to fit within this framework.
It's going to allow us to focus on model building.
So you're going to hear these terms again and again as we work with opening.
Jim and keep in mind reinforcement learning isn't just for games it's for a variety of tasks.
Games are just an easy way to clearly show all the major aspects of reinforcement learning.
Which is why when you're learning about reinforcement learning it's really popular that you see it in
the setting of things like board games or simple tasks.
All right that's it for this lecture.
The next lecture we're going to discuss a little further about open gym library.
I'll see you there.