Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
We're going to be discussing open aiight.
Jim what is the toolkit open.
AI is the basic nonprofit organization that's behind this tool kit.
And then we'll also discover the documentation behind open eyes.
So first off let's discuss what is open A-I open and it is a nonprofit AI research company.
You may have heard of opening before due to its ties with people like Elon Musk or Sam Altman and their
basic motivation is to help discover and enact a path to safe artificial general intelligence.
If you follow the mosque and his comments on the dangers of artificial intelligence you may already
have some familiarity of this but basically open he is trying to bring a path forward where the basic
research of artificial intelligence is more shared more collaborative more open in hopes of enacting
a safe path for the general development of artificial intelligence.
So what ends up happening is that they released this toolkit called Jim.
So that's what we're actually going to be working with open aiight Jim.
And that's a tool kit the AIDS in developing and comparing reinforcement learning algorithms.
There's two parts to open AI Jim and the part we're really going to be dealing with is the open AGM
library and the Python library.
That means we're actually going to directly import it will say import Jim and you can use pipin knowledge
him to install it.
But it's a python library with a collection of environments that you can use with your reinforcement
learning algorithms.
And basically before opening I Jim it was quite difficult to try to get some sort of general environment
for your reinforcement learning algorithms.
But now with opening gym it becomes a lot easier to test reinforcement algorithms on the same environment
as someone else on a computer.
Maybe half the world away.
So it makes it really convenient to build models and compare models.
So we'll be using the Python library.
There is another aspect of open the gym that I want to talk about.
We won't really be using it but it's the open gym service and it's a site in API we can compare algorithm
performance on the environments the opening gym provides So what we're going to do is we're going to
explore the official documentation before diving into work.
Opening gym with Python.
Just seeing it a little bit more familiar with what the actual documentation pages look like.
So open up your browser and go to gym.
Open AAE dot com or just do a quick Google search for open gym.
And so probably the first page that pops up.
So let's open up our browser and head to that.
OK.
Here I am in my browser.
If you go to gym opening dot com it should automatically link you back to the page.
So here you can see the open aiight gym is totally open source.
You can check out all the code all the examples et cetera as well as the documentation page.
But in case you're having trouble finding this one I want to do show you how you can get this just from
going from opening his official Web site.
So let's hop over to that here am.
Opening night dot com.
A lot of times it changes what the actual home page looks like but you should see some sort of link
to their systems either down here or over the top navigation bar.
So you click on systems and eventually somewhere along this page you should see.
Jim says Jim the open air that.
You'll go ahead and click on that.
It'll take you to Jim the opening column which currently links to this page.
So if you scroll down on this page eventually you should see that it has some link for the documentation.
So you click on that and it will take you to the more documentation like page and then you can hit here
on view documentation.
And here is the official documentation for opening night Jim.
So this is what we're going to be learning about.
And as I just mentioned it consists of two parts the open source library which is mainly what we're
going to be dealing with and this is basically a collection of environments.
So that's the really hard part that Jim has basically taken care of for you if it's providing you with
environments that you can have your agent interact with take actions upon etc. to try to find some sort
of reward.
So if you click here on environments you can check out the various environments are.
So there's a bunch of the free environments right now and depending on when you're viewing this page
sometimes those pictures don't load.
But there is a cart pulling environment which that's the main thing we're actually going to be messing
around with.
But there's also a boardgame environment such as go.
So if you ever heard of Google's deep mind you're probably familiar go there.
And then there's also Atari games such as aere Pac-Man alien cetera.
Keep in mind some of these environments such as Atari require additional libraries to install such as
an Atari emulator.
So we're only going to be dealing with these classic control problems that don't require any additional
libraries.
If you do require other environments go ahead and read the official documentation and additional libraries
you need to install for this course.
We're going to try to keep things as simple as possible for our reinforcement learning lecturers so
we'll only deal with things that don't require an additional library beyond Jim.
So we have a Tory board games Toltecs safety.
There's even Minecraft there's soccer there's doom etc. So lots of stuff here on these environments
and you can check the documentation as well.
And there's also even a forum they can click around and play around with.
OK.
So that's all I wanted to show you.
As far as opening night Jim is concerned we're going to do in the next series of lectures is actually
show you how upon installing opening a gym how you can interact with it as a Python library.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.