Hello everyone before we actually get started with coding.
Opening night gym.
What I want to do is cover just a few basic setup and best practices when working with the gym library.
So let's go ahead and review the best practices with open gym for working of opening night gym.
I actually recommend that you use either a text editor or an integrated development environment instead
of a Jupiter notebook.
What we're going to be doing of that opening gym is rendering some to them mentionable drawings or environments
and sometimes those renderings have issues of Jupiter notebooks.
So what I recommend doing is using either a text editor such as subline text editor or Adam text editor.
A simple Google search of those will just take you straight to the download page or if you want.
You can use a full integrated development environment such as pi charm and or basic set up is going
to be to code out the PI files or the high scripts in the editor and then execute the code at the command
line.
There are many possible plug ins for subline Texan Adam text editor that alive.
Also have the command line or the terminal directly inside those text editors open AI.
Thus again technically work in the Jupiter notebook but sometimes the pending on your operating system
running multiple renderings of an environment can lead to freezing or just very slow behavior of the
gym.
So it always works when we run up Paice groups so that's what we're going to be using for this course.
That way in case you're using another operating system you don't get hung up on any errors but you can
if you want attempt to first off use cheaper notebooks.
OK so we're going to do right now is quickly check the opening.
Jim is installed and also show you how to run a PI script as well as going through how you would download
a text editor if you need it.
And I want a quick note here please feel free to use any either text editor or development environment
configuration you prefer.
So we're going to be using atom for this series of lectures.
It's a open source free text editor from hub.
And remember you have many options including just ticking of Jupiter notebooks in case you prefer that.
So right now we're going to open up our browser and go to Adam.
Let's hop over to that.
OK so here we are.
Adam Oh Adam is just a basic text editor.
It's open source and it's free is provided from get hub and depending on what operating system you're
using you should see a download button here.
If you're on Windows you see the windows installer if you're on a Mac you should see the Mac installer.
And if you're on Linux or Bluetooth should see some sort of download of either S.H. file or some sort
of installation file.
So go ahead and click on that and install the Adam text editor.
It's a basic text editor and it's going to provide us things with syntax highlighting for that py files
etc..
So go ahead and download that and then I've already downloaded it.
Open it up on my computer.
Let's jump to that now.
All right so once you open up Adam the first time it should look something like this.
Well we're going to do teach you one last thing which is how to install a terminal package.
That way you don't have to keep jumping back to either command prompt or terminal but instead you can
have a terminal directly in the Adam text editor.
This is optional you don't need to do this.
You could always just open up your terminal command line separately and run up high script from there.
But let me also show you how the general insulation package works and that them click here where it
says install a package and then say open installer and that will open up this page and then you search
packages.
So you're going to search for terminal and then hit enter and then it will say the featured packages
and it's going to say searching in packages for terminal and eventually you should see in this dropdown
list the platform you dash the terminal.
And this is the package that allows you to have basically a little plus sign that open up a command
line directly in the Adam text editor.
So I already have it installed but you should see a little Install button there.
If you can't find that just by searching terminal go out and search the entire name platform you know
dash ID dash terminal install it and if you ever want to mess around with the settings you can do is
click here in settings and this will take you to the platform your ID settings and as you scroll down
here what I recommend you do if you're on a Windows computer is to override the shell sometimes by default.
It uses power shell.
You can go ahead and copy and paste this line right here in and send it to your Siham the executable
file.
That way it launches the command prompt.
It's sort of the power shell.
Once you've done this you may need to restart items to go ahead and close out them again and open it
up.
Once you've done that you should see at the very bottom a little plus sign you can click on that plus
sign and that opens up a new terminal for you.
And here you can run things such as straight python from the command line so you can get Python and
they have this little terminal in your text editor.
So let's go ahead and quit this and let's practice and make sure that we have Jim installed onto our
computer.
So where are you going to do is you're going to activate C-f deep learning environment.
We've been using.
And Jim should already be installed in T.F. deep learning.
But just in case it isn't you can use Pipp install Jim enter.
And you should see it installed Lotusphere already get the requirement already satisfied because they
already have gym installed.
Once you've done that you can go ahead and run a thought PI script.
In this TFT planning environment let's review how to do that.
So we're going to just say file will save new file and this will open up a new file here and we're just
going to say import Jim and then we'll print out.
It works right now.
There's no syntax highlighting because I haven't actually named this or save this so I'll say file or
list control SLB easier just control as or commands.
And then you can save this wherever you want.
So since I'm under C users Marsat right now I will save it there.
So I've moved over to that directory and then I'm just going to call it my test.
Jim py file.
Hit save and notice once becomes a PI file.
What's going to happen is it's going to automatically open up all the folders there and your project
folder.
And it's also going to import that syntax highlighting which is nice and useful for us.
So then what we can do here is Bechet this command line.
Just type in Python and then begin to type in the name.
My test.
Jim you can just do tabbed to autocomplete there enter and you should see eventually it works.
Hopefully you don't get any error that says Jim not found if you're getting an error saying Jim not
found then triple check that you've activated your learning environment and that you also installed
Jim using pipin Solanum.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
Again you pretty much have total flexibility as far as what kind of method you want to use for running
these dot scripts for Jim.
You can use the Jupiter notebook but if you ever get into bugs then I recommend that you download that
you print a book as it by script and then just run that PI script at your command line.
So if you really use the Jupiter book you could technically keep using that as well.
You actually don't need to switch to a text editor but I'm going to be using a text editor here just
to make sure that everyone no matter what their O S here can follow along with me with no bugs or no
errors when rendering their gym environments.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.