Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to discuss just the very basics of creating in an environment with opening gym library.
So we're going to explore how to create the carpool environment.
One of the most basic environments that comes of opening a gym and it also doesn't require any additional
libraries to be installed.
So let's discuss what the actual carpool problem is.
So the goal of this carpooling environment is to balance the pull on the cart and the car can move left
or right and you can imagine as the cart moves around the pole will end up sliding down.
So we have actions available to us in order to move the cart either left or right in an attempt to balance
the pull.
Well actually Theale actions in this lecture that will deal in a future lecture.
But right now just keep in mind that we're going to be able to enter one of two actions either zero
for left or one for right.
So we're going to move that car left to right to try to keep it up pull balance as far as the environment
is concerned.
It's actually going to be represented with a pie array.
So even though the opening I Chim library comes a nice rendering tool so you can visualize all of this
as far as your actual model is concerned.
It's just going to receive back a number higher rate for floating point numbers and those floating point
numbers will indicate the horizontal position.
So there's some initial position of the cart which we mark at zero.
And then the horizontal position can be either to the left of that initial mark.
So that would be some negative number or to the right of it.
So we have that first horizontal position.
Then we also have the horizontal velocity.
So that's how fast the actual cart is moving left or right.
Then we also know the angle of the pole itself as well as the angular velocity of the pole as it tends
to fall down.
So we can grab these values from the environment that umpire and then we'll use them for our agent right
now let's just focus on the very basics of creating this environment.
So I will open up my editor or open up whatever IP you're using to create your PI scripts and follow
along with me.
Let's go to the editor now.
OK so right here we have a PI script files called my test Jim and the first thing we need to do is actually
import Jim.
So I will say import Jim and we'll just do that.
And now it's time to actually create or make the environment that we create or make an environment is
create some sort of environmental variable we'll say envy.
And you can ignore this kind of drop down right here.
It's just basic drop down help for Python but it's not necessary here.
There we're going to call Jim.
Well called the make method off the gym.
So you say Jim thought make and then the passing some string code for the environment some environments
as I've mentioned before have dependencies such as the Atari game environments require the Atari emulator.
But in this case we're going to be using the environment that doesn't require anything to keep things
simple and it will be just cart pole dash vs zero.
And if you want more string codes you can always just check out the documentation.
So you click on the environments page that we saw earlier and then choose any string you want.
If you get an error it's probably because you needed the pendency.
So go ahead and look up on the documentation what dependencies need to install.
So once you've made the environment what we wanted to do is reset the environment to its default starting
stage.
In our case the shifts that the car is at the Zero location.
So we say reset.
Open and close print sees on the environment.
And then what you can do is you can render the environment over several times steps she can say something
like for tea in range 1000.
So for some 1000 times steps we're going to do is we're going to render the environment and rendering
the environment basically creates this little pop up that allows you to view the environment.
And then what we're going to do here is we're going to do the following.
The worry about this line of code is something we're going to talk about a lot more in the next lecture.
But essentially what I'm going to do is I'm going to call the action space office environment and then
I'm going to call a sample open and close princes.
And what this line does the Slide 11.
It's basically saying take some sort of random action from the action space from the actions available
to us were either 0 or 1 left or right.
What this is going to do is going to randomly sample that and then provide that step into the environment.
So we shouldn't actually see the pull balance we should eventually just see some sort of random sliding.
And what should happen is that slides off the actual page.
So let's save this and run this so we'll say Python.
My test Jim that pi.
Just have to complete that and make sure that you're running this with your environment activated or
they gym installed.
Otherwise we're going to err enter to run this and eventually should see a little pop up there and you
should see it swing off the page.
OK.
So that's all we have to do.
Again the lines here that really focus on is you make your environment with some sort of street code.
Again the string codes available to you and the documentation reset the environment to the starting
position and then for a certain number of time steps you can render the environment which is what we
just saw.
And then you can't perform an read off that environment.
So we're going to focus on next as a quick note.
It really doesn't matter what you call this temporary variable because we don't actually use it inside
this for loop.
So it's common to just have an underscore here because underscores are typically kind of throw away
variables stuff you don't really end up using inside your for loops so just keep that in mind if you
ever see this.
It's really come just these underscore there.
All right thanks everyone.
And the next lecture we're going to focus on being able to take actions and reading the environment
I'll see it there.