Welcome back everyone to this lecture.
We're going to be talking about Jim observations.
So you may have noticed that we were calling each and every step and then passing an action into it
the environment step function that we saw earlier returns back really useful objects that we can use
with our learning agent.
So let's go ahead and discuss what actually gets returned back when we call that step function.
There's four key things that get returned back.
One of them is called an observation variable.
So you call that step function off your environment you pass an action and one of the things is going
to give you back is the observation and that's the environment specific information that represents
the environment observations.
So those can be things like angles of velocities the state of a game etc..
In our case there's reason the cart pull we actually already know that there's a fourth dimension array
which has information such as the velocity at the current position angular velocity and the angle of
the pole itself.
So that's the observation that gets returned once you call that step function.
There's three more things that also get returned the pot calling the step function.
The next one is the reward.
And that's the amount of reward achieved by the previous action.
Remember we passed an action in that step function and then we can get back in a reward amount.
So the actual scale of this reward it varies based off what environment you're using so certain environments
such as car pool are going to be different in their scale of reward versus a go game.
But overall the agent should always want to increase that reward level so you can think about it as
you always want to increase the reward.
The actual scale of that number may change though depending on your environment.
Another thing that gets returned upon passing an action is the step function.
Is this done variable.
And that's just a boolean indicating whether or not the environment needs to be reset.
So you can imagine this is going to be really useful because you can pass this into a WHILE loop.
So while this environment is not done yet you want to keep passing in the actions so that allows you
to basically set up your agent ready to learn and you keep doing this over and over and over again for
a certain number of iterations and then you stop those intermediate iterations based off the environment
being done or not.
So what would actually indicate whether the environment is done or completed.
Well that can be things like losing the game of Pac-Man that would issue the done variable to be true.
Or for instance your pull tipped over all the way.
That means it's done it's time for the agent to start over and reset etc. and then finally there is
an info object that also gets returned.
That's a dictionary object with some diagnostic information.
It's usually used for debugging.
We don't really see it use that much in these lectures.
But it also gets returned.
Let's go ahead and explore what this looks like in practice.
I'm going to open up my editor and create another postscript.
OK.
This is the postscript we were working with earlier we imported Jim we created that Karpel environment.
We reset the environment to its default state.
And then for about a thousand time steps we kept rendering the environment that was a little image we
saw.
And here we have this environment thought step action and then we passed then some sort of action.
And in this case we haven't really talked that much about the actual space.
We will the next lecture.
But this right here this line in the action underscore space that sample that just provides a random
action.
And eventually if some of the random actions the cart just swings off the page.
OK so let's explore what else this step function actually returns.
And for this we actually are even going to render the image so you won't see an image pop up.
The environment will still go.
We won't just be rendering the visualization of it.
And we're just going to run this for one timestep because I want to actually run this for a two time
steps.
Does it really matter because I want to see what's actually returned here.
So let's go ahead and do this.
When we say environment reset we're going to set that equal to observation.
And essentially we're going to be doing here is saying this is our initial observation.
So initial observation and then let's go ahead and print out the observation.
Okay.
So we have our initial observation.
We reset the environment and then we print out the observation and this observation is basically just
going to show what the environment state is right now.
So we're going to see an umpire rate of four steps basically.
So let's save that and let's run this script will say Python.
My test whip's my test Jim PI enter.
And here is our initial observation.
So this is the state that the environment starts out.
And so that is what return is return when you reset the state.
This the array here and this basically represents that poll standing straight up with the cart in the
middle position.
And some things are barely off zero so you can see here that it's already starting to feel a little
bit.
If it was straight up it would just stay that way so we needed to be tilted a little bit so that it
can continue to start moving.
OK.
So let's go ahead and separate this line right here.
And set that as action.
So remember we haven't talked that much about actions yet.
But again this is just performing a random action.
So in that environment the action space we will talk about this term for the next lecture.
Sample It basically take a random action and set that as reaction then I'm going to pass that action
into step later on.
Our agent is actually going to take care of doing these actions.
So we have our action.
And we passed that into step and the step function returns for things.
And these are the four things we were discussing in the slides.
So return back in observation a reward a done variable and the info and we can set that equal to environment
step.
So here I'm just doing tuple and packing to grab the four things that are returned as a result of passing
an action into the next step of the environment.
You reward your get back an observation a reward the stun variable and info and I'm just going to copy
and paste from the notes a bunch of print statements that print these out along with a little string
indicating what they are.
Only place that in here.
All this is just from your notes.
But all I'm doing here is I'm printing out each of these with a little bit of spacing for readability.
So we're going to perform one random action that I'm going to print out the observation print out the
reward.
Print out the done variable and then print out info.
So let's save that and run this again.
On my test Jim and I'm going to expand this because basically we it render render everything we just
have a bunch of stuff printed out.
So let's scroll back up here.
So we have our initial observation that is this right here.
And then we performed the one random action and you can see here now our observation has changed after
performing that random action.
Our reward return back is just one point zero.
Is it done.
No it's false it's not done yet.
Which kind of makes sense after one timestep you're unlikely to have the pool fall over yet and that
info because we don't have any debugging issues.
Just an empty dictionary.
Then we perform another random action.
We get back another observation.
The reward right now is just 1.0 done.
False info etc..
So you can imagine is if we're performing an action that moves the poll with a less angle across that
vertical basically fixed in the poll so it stands straight again.
Our reward is going to be bigger.
So eventually we're going to want our agent to take in these four values and do whatever it needs to
do action wise either go left or right to initiate a bigger reward and right now convert based reward
is 1.0 because since we're performing random actions we're not really doing anything.
OK.
So that's really all we need to understand about this.
We can get back an observation a reward a done variable indicating whether or not we're done with this
particular iteration the environment and then back this in for debugging.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture where we begin to discuss how we can
actually set actions into the environment.
I'll see you there.