Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're finally going to discuss Jim actions and basically show you how you can perform very basic actions
in your environment.
So we're going to do is create a very simple policy and our policy is going to be if we notice that
the pole is falling to the right.
We will move the cart to the right to try to adjust for that change and vice versa if the pool is moving
to the left starting to fall to the left will try to move the cart to the left to basically try to catch
it.
Now this is a very simple policy it's not taking into account things like the angular velocity of the
pole how fast it's falling down or even the velocity of the car.
So it's going to shift left and right and this sort of strategy is eventually going to fail.
But let's go ahead and do it anyway just tweaking it some practice with the action capabilities of the
environment.
And we're also going to explore just a little bit of that action underscore space variable that we've
been looking at before which means we'll do a little bit of Python code straight into the command line.
You don't really need to follow along with that but that's just more for exploring the action underscore
space variable.
OK let's open our text editor and if you want you can also open up your command prompt.
Let's hop to that.
OK.
Here I am at my text editor.
I haven't emptied up my script file but what I want to do first is with my environment activated I'm
going to call Python.
And this is going to allow me to basically explore some of the extra capabilities of Jim.
So we'll see.
Import Jim and then we're going to do here is create an environment just as we did before.
Basically we're doing this all at the command line.
So we'll say cart pull cash the zero past in that string and then we're going to have here is the ability
to say in the dot and then if I hit tab here I'm going to see the various attributes and methods that
are available to this environment.
And the one that we've been working with right now is action space and there's another one called observation
space.
So these are the two space attributes.
So let's go ahead and call action space.
And if you do a dot and hit tab again it's basically working like a Jupiter notebook.
You can see that we have contains sample shape etc..
So if we just do the action space call that with no extra prince is there an action or enter excuse
me.
You see that we see discrete too and that basically means that our actions we have two the screen numbers
available to us.
And if you look up the documentation again that's just 0 and 1.
So the total space of the actions available are just two discrete numbers zero and one left and right.
And then similarly there's an observation space.
You can do tabbed out a complete that.
And if I hit Enter Lotus we get Box 4.
So there's four observations that come back.
And those are the current position velocity the pull angle and the angular velocity.
And if you want to know more about that again you'd have to check into the documentation.
Basically all these environments are documented in open the eye for what actions are available and what
observations are available.
And this is one quick way of knowing if you're on the right environment.
So here we have two discrete actions available and for observations to get back.
So I'm going to quit this now.
And then it's clear that and let's minimize this a little more.
So let's go ahead and do that hard coded policy.
So we'll start by saying import Jim and I'm going to create an environment variable.
Jim make and again it's just going to be carpool.
Zero and I'll set my initial observation observation which is spelled right to be equal to reset here.
So we're going to reset the environment to its defaults.
And then let's go ahead and do this for 1000 times steps.
So for one time steps in this environment I will render the environment so we're actually going to view
our policy.
You don't always have to do this especially when you're training maybe you're not going to be watching
a computer so you don't really care about rendering the environment.
But for now we will go ahead and see what it looks like and the next thing to do is grab the four things
that are observation returns back.
So remember or observation returns back the current position the current velocity and you can call these
whatever you want the pull angle and then angular velocity.
So I just created four variables there and I'm going to essentially unpack this tuple of the observation
and now it's time to actually create a very simple hard coded policy.
So the pull angle is greater than zero than what's actually happening here.
Well the angle is measured off a straight vertical line from the cart which means if it starts to lean
towards the right and getting a positive angle and it starts to lean towards the left off that vertical
line I get a negative angle.
So if the pull angle is greater than zero then I know it's starting to lean towards the right.
So if the pulls lean towards the right.
Let's go ahead and move the cart towards the right.
In an attempt to try to fix that.
So we're going to say action is equal to 1
else.
Well in that case we know that the angle is going to be negative meaning the pole is falling to the
left.
So we can try to move to the left.
So I'll say action is an equal to zero.
All right.
So again very simple hard coded policy here and we're going to go ahead and then just perform that action.
So I'll say observation reward done info is equal to the environment.
Step and then import that action.
And this is the very basic idea of how you can use open aiight gym for environment and working within
an environment.
So these are the absolute basics and we're going to do is eventually use tensor flow to try to create
a reinforcement learning algorithm.
But it's important to understand everything that you see here because these are the basic building blocks
that we're going to use when creating our learning agent.
So let's go interview each of these lines.
We import Jim.
We make the environment.
Again you have some sort of string code here that you look up in the documentation for each specific
environment.
Certain string codes have dependencies such as the Atari games.
Then you reset the environment to the default that's going to be your first observation and for how
ever many times steps you want operationally you can render this.
So if there's a visual aspect to this you can see the visual aspect.
Then you go ahead and grab whatever the observation returns back.
In our case we saw that this observation returns back four variables.
The cart position cart velocity at the pole angle and angular velocity.
And then you're going to have your learning agent do some sort of logic here or some sort of learning.
Right now we have a simple hardcoded policy where we're just moving left and right depending on the
puls angle.
Then once you've done that you're learning agent will decide on an action you're going to feed that
action into this step function off the environment.
And then that's going to return back a new observation to a new set of positions and velocities a reward
that your agent is eventually going to use trying to maximize that reward an indication whether or not
it's done.
So if this is done what you may want to do here is that say maybe put this in a for loop and put your
learning agent within a while loop so that it keeps iterating over while not done or something similar.
And then you also have this info which is used for debugging purposes OK let's save that right now and
let's actually see how this performs we'll say Python my apps my test Jim.
So my test Jim that PI enter.
And we should see kind of wobble a little bit and then it's a field but you can see here that it performs
a lot better than just random sampling.
When you ran them sample they went straight off the screen.
But here we can see it trying to adjust.
And then it failed.
All right.
So by now we should understand how you actually work with open a gym.
The next step is to use test flow to build out a learning agent.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.