Welcome back everyone.
So we've already seen how we can create a simple hard coded policy basically go left when the pull is
leaning left to go right when the pull is leaning right.
But how about now we create a simple neural network that takes in those for observation values those
angles and those velocities and then tries to output some sort of probability or indication of whether
you should go left or right.
So again we're going to design a simple neural network.
It takes in the observation array passes it through a hidden layer and then outputs to probabilities.
It's actually going to output just one probability and we're going to turn it into two.
We'll show you how to do that later on.
But essentially it's going to output the probability to the left and the probability it should go right.
And then we're then going to choose a random action weighted by the probability scores.
Our network output.
So let's go out and diagram this network.
What it actually looks like.
So essentially in the left hand side we accepted those four observations from that array and then we
can pass it in through as many hidden layers as we want.
This is a pretty basic problem.
So we could even just use one layer here but we'll go ahead and show you how to use two just so we can
review how to use the sensor for a layer's API.
And then once we have that we're going to pass it in all into one single neuron.
And this last single neuron is going to be a sigmoid function you're on because it's going to output
a single probability the probability that we should go left.
So that's going to be between 0 and 1.
And by having the probability that we should go left we can say one minus that probability is the probability
that we should go right because we know these two probabilities should add up to 1 or 100 percent.
So for instance we may get back the 30 percent probability or point three that we should go left that
means we know that the network is saying there's a point seven probability that we should go right.
So we have those two probabilities.
And what we're going to do is doing multinomial sampling based off those probability weights.
So we're going to sample to choose either the action 0 or 1 based off the probabilities.
Now notice this is critical here how we're not just automatically choosing the highest probability for
our decision.
So even though we make it 70 percent chance to choose right and 30 percent chance it's shoes left.
We're not just automatically going with the highest probability and going right and that's because we're
trying to balance out attempting new actions versus constantly choosing well-known actions.
Otherwise your network might get caught in a loop and constantly return back the same action.
So once we understand this network and code it out which we're about to do later on in the feature lecture
we're going to explore how to take into account historic actions by learning about policy gradients.
But right now let's go ahead and code out a very simple neural network.
Let's open up our text editor and get started.
OK here we are as a text editor.
Let's go ahead and get some imports in.
We'll say tensor flow as t.a.
We're also going to be using Jim.
And then finally we'll say important high as and P.
So those are imports all out of the way.
Now it's time to create the network variables so we know our observation space has for inputs those
angles and velocities.
So we'll create a variable called number of inputs and that's going to be equal to 4.
And then also create some hidden layers.
We'll just have them have four neurons and then the number of outputs we want at the end of all this
is just going to be equal to 1.
And that's the probability to go left so probability to go left which we then know for say 1 minus that
probability that's going to be equal to the probability to go right.
So just keep that in mind that we here that one minus probably it's got left is equal to the probability
to go right.
And then finally we're going to say initialiser and this is going to be the initialiser for the actual
T.F. layers.
And if you're feeling a little fuzzy on the T.F. layers API go ahead and visit the miscellaneous section.
We cover it there but we're going to call A.F. contrib layers and we're going to call in variants underscore
scaling underscore initialiser and we've seen this in previous lectures.
All right.
So those are network variables.
Now it's time to actually begin creating the network layers.
So we essentially have one more sort of a variable to create but it's actually a placeholder.
So we're going to create a placeholder for the data that's coming in the observations.
Going to be to float 32.
And the shape is going to be equal to none by the number of inputs.
Now let's go ahead and create a hidden layer and this is more of an input layer actually but we'll keep
the naming the hidden layer one.
And it's going to be T.F. layers we're going to have a densely connected layer here.
It's going to take an exit placeholder and it's going to output number of HIDDINS So we'll just have
that before neuron's coming out.
Then we need to choose an activation function so that we can choose T.F. will go in to rectify linear
unit.
And then finally we need a kernel initialiser and we'll have that be the initialiser recreated before.
OK let's go in and create one more layer.
That's essentially the exact same thing.
This is pretty much overkill for this problem but that's just a practice using that T.F. layers API.
So it's pretty easy to use once you have that one layer.
We can just create another one and call this hidden layer 2 and instead of taking in the actual input
X we can have it taken hit and layer 1 and then instead of them hidden we can actually keep that in
there it's going to go to four and then we have the activation function and curtainless chalets at the
same so then we have our output layer here.
So our output layer is also going to be T.F. layers thence it's going to take an hit and layer 2.
But then instead of outputting in other four neurons just going to be a single output number of outputs
is just one.
And that's a probability to go left so we know probabilities have to be between 0 and 1.
So our activation function this time is going to be the sigmoid function and the initialiser is actually
going to be the same we'll say Colonel initialiser is equal to initialiser
Okay.
And if you ever need to reference this code it's all available to you.
In the notes so we have our output layer and recall that this output layer is returning back essentially
a single number the probability to go left to it's going to be between 0 and 1.
So let's go in and say probabilities
probabilities is equal to.
And we were going to construct here is T.F. concat going to concatenate along axis is equal to 1.
And we're going to do two values together.
This is basically so we can get it in the form that we can later play around with.
With T.F. multinomial and that is the output layer.
So recall the ability to go left and the other one should then just be up 1 minus the output layer.
So it's a probability to go right.
So the reason we're doing this T.F. of concat is so that we can get the action using T.F. multinomial
in the past and the probabilities here and the number of samples we want out is equal to 1.
So basically this is just one way we can do this without having to export things into a pie and then
sticking them back into the tensor flow we're grabbing and creating these probabilities.
Essentially this tensor of probabilities going left and going right and then using that conjunction
of T.F. multinomial to actually bring back some single action either zero or one go left or right
and then finally we're going to say it is equal to T.F. global variables.
Initialiser
OK.
So what we need to do next is actually train.
The session is actually pretty straightforward.
We're going to do is we'll create a step limit so only allowed to do 500 steps within a training session
and then start creating the environment will say Ian V is gym make and then we'll pass and carpool the
zero and let's focus on the session here.
We're going to say with T.F. session as we assess I'm going to say in run.
Or you could also say sense that run in it the other way is fine then for every episode we'll say episode
in the range of epi.
So let's go to find epi how many times we actually want to run this.
So we'll say we'll run this 50 times and the step limit is the limit.
In each actual episode.
So we're going to run this to 50 episodes of the game and within each game we're only allowed to take
500 times steps.
After that we'll go ahead and just declared done if done hasn't already been declared.
Now it's very unlikely the way the simple near your network set up that will ever hit close to 500.
In fact you'll probably get much closer to something like 20.
And in fact let's go ahead and create some average steps here so we'll say average steps is equal to
an empty list for now and then later on we'll append to average steps and then take the mean of it so
we can see how long we were actually able to last for a neural network.
OK so I'll say for AI episode and range eppi.
So basically we're going to run this 50 times.
I'm going to reset my environment so say observations equal to reset and then after I've reset in my
environment I'm going to say force that in range up to my step limit some 500 steps for this particular
game.
I will do the following.
I will say action value is equal to action evaluates because remember action appear.
If we scroll up is this result of this multinomial right it's going to be 0 or 1.
It requires a feed dictionary.
Based on this graph we just created.
So we'll come over here and will say that the feed dictionary is equal to time to create Dictionnaire
here X and we're pass the observations here.
But we need to reshape these so we can't just pass in a straight array due to the way it's set up.
It will start complaining about the shape so we need to reshape this to be equal to one by the number
of inputs.
So needs to be a 1 by 4.
Recall sometimes some PI returns back something like Blink comma 4.
So we're reshaping this one by four so it's really a one dimensional array instead of just something
like a comma for array.
OK so we have a reshape.
We're feeding that in.
We should then get an action.
So then we're going to feed in the action.
But the way that we set up our action when you do a little bit of indexing off of it.
So the true action value we need to index twice suffer this because of the way we're actually calling
it here.
It's mainly due to the way T.F. multinomial returns things as far as it's tensors in order to get that
actual zero or one call.
When you do this sort of indexing.
So this actually returns back 0 or 1 and then we're going to pass that in to our environment step function.
We remember that we actually passed and the actions are one.
So we have our environments that passing in that action and then that's going to return back the observation
the reward whether or not the game is done.
And then some in full for debugging later in case we need it.
All right.
So finally we also want to say if done maybe we fell over got off the screen or something.
We're going to say average steps and I'm going to append the current step we were on because maybe it
declares it's done it falls over after one step.
Or go ahead and put that in there.
And I want to prints done after steps so hopefully we can see this gradually go up and then we'll probably
have around 20 and then we will say format's step.
So don't expect this neural network to perform very well.
The one we're going to do next will perform much better but we'll say if done average steps and then
we're going to break out of this for a loop here.
So basically we're in a run through 50 games.
We have a limit of per game only 500 that's unlikely to reach 500 steps ever.
In fact more likely that we hit done probably the poll is over and then we apan what step we were actually
on when that happened and we print out a little message saying Hey we're done after this many steps.
And then finally at the end when it prints out after blank episodes
average whip's after blink episodes Khama average steps per game was and let's go ahead and then format
these answers in.
So after the episodes average steps that's going to be equal to MP that means a number I mean of the
average stepstool list Okay.
And then finally we're going to close off the environment in case it keeps running.
Now if you wanted to you could also set a render somewhere here so you could say environment not render
But since we're actually treating the model essentially if you render it you're going to see the cartful
or the pole fall over over and over again 50 times which is not super useful and it'll basically slow
down your calculations so we're not going to be rendering anything.
And then finally let's go in and test this out we'll say Python test or my test Jim that PI enter and
let's see if that works.
No module name senseful it's because I forgot to activate my environment.
So make sure you activate your environment will say T.F. the learning activate that.
And then after this is done activating.
Now we're going to do a python.
My test Jim that pie OK let's run that make sure won't have any errors.
Hopefully we see a bunch of print statements coming out as it's training.
OK small typo here.
Forgot the extra I in initialiser.
So let's go back and get that right here.
Initialiser and hopefully that was the only typo.
Save this try again.
Hopefully around any more debugging.
And there it goes.
So after 50 episodes average deaths per game was 30.
That's kind of including the very first ones that should have performed pretty poorly like 10 and 7.
Big and see here were lasting an average of 30 times steps.
That's not actually terribly good.
It's actually pretty bad.
But this is a pretty simple neural network.
If you want you can try playing around with how many episodes you get trained for.
You can go ahead and get trained for something like 250.
Save that and run it again.
But even She'll see that you're hitting the limit here.
And the main limit that we're hitting is the fact that we're not really learning from our sequence of
actions in fact see after 250 episodes it performed worse.
So what we're not taking into account here is the actual history of actions.
Instead we're just doing is saying based off your previous action.
Give me the probabilities.
And since we're also sampling based off probabilities we may be choosing the wrong one.
We may maybe folks a little too much on learning new actions.
So a much better way to train all of this is to use a policy gradient.
So what we're going to do in the next lecture is explain what we mean by policy gradients and then after
that we'll actually code out policy gradients which is a much more sophisticated way of performing reinforcement
learning.
Right now we're kind of just feeding in the observations and kind of randomly picking out based off
some probability sampling.
We're going to learn that that's actually not a good way to solve even these simple problems.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.