Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on policy gradients.
Now our previous neural network didn't actually perform very well and this may be because we aren't
really considering the history of our actions.
Instead we're really only considering a single previous action and it's immediate reward instead of
a sequence of actions and how that may affect rewards in the far future now this is often called an
assignment of credit problem which action should actually be credited when the agent gets rewarded at
time t.
Should it be only the actions that happened right before team minus one or the entire series of historical
actions and a lot of times just depends on the actual environment that your agent is working with.
So if we have this problem of assigning credit to certain actions in the past we end up doing is we
apply a discount rates.
And this allows us to evaluate an action based off all the rewards that come after the action not just
the first immediate reward.
So let's go ahead and describe how this works mathematically what we end up doing is we choose a discount
rate and it's typically around somewhere between 0.9 5 and 0.9 9.
And we'll explain how changing that closer to either zero or one affects the actual calculation.
But you essentially use that discount rate and apply a score to the action with this falling formula
let's say our is your total reward that gets returned back from the environment and is that discount
rate that point ninety five point ninety nine number.
You end up doing is you calculate a specific score for the action.
This is actually different than the reward.
This is a discount score that you're assigning of that action and it's calculated by the reward at time
zero when you actually immediately do that action.
And then you add that to the next reward times the discount rate then the reward that comes after that.
Times are discount rate squared.
Then the reward that comes after that one time your discount rate to the power three and so on and so
on all the way until you get that final reward times the discount to the power.
And so you can see that future actions and the getting less and less because if you have something that's
less than 1 and you keep squaring it that becomes a smaller and smaller number.
So the closer that discount rate is to one that means the more Future Awards will have the closer that
discount rate is to zero.
That means Future Awards don't count as much as immediate rewards.
And hopefully you can see that if you to kind of plug in some numbers into this score formula that choosing
a discount rate often depends on the specific environment and whether actions have short or long term
effects.
We can kind of look at our poll problem and decide that the action of moving left or right is probably
only going to have a short term effect.
It's not really going to be important 50 actions into the future whether or not it turned right or left.
However it probably has some importance.
A couple of actions into the future so that will help you decide on whether you want a discount rate
as you mentioned before.
Closer to one meaning there's more weight on Future Awards or if you want it closer to zero you're more
effected.
You're more concerned with short term effects so Future Awards don't count as much as immediate rewards.
And it is a careful balance.
They are going to sign on based on the environment.
And it's also something and play around with to see what models perform better.
So let's quickly diagram this formula.
Again what we're doing here is we're saying ours we're award these are at discount rate and we're calculating
a score by doing this summation multiplied by the discount rate as an action gets accounted for Future
Awards.
OK so in this diagram we see here on the left hand side we have our agent or bought and then it's going
to perform some actions and get some rewards.
And in this case we're just looking at three time steps.
So those arrows on the top in the case what actually happened in the environment.
So the first action we perform is right or we give the signal of one and the pull went up a little bit.
It got straightened out.
And for that we get a reward of plus 10 then because of that.
The next apt actually happened to take is going left or entering zero.
And again the pull goes up so we get a plus 10.
However the next action going right ends up with the pole falling over.
So then you get a negative 100.
So if we want to do is analyze the score of that first.
Right now we're only looking at three time steps here.
So typically what we did in the last year on that work is we just assign plus 10 to this action of going
right.
However in a policy gradient situation we want to learn if going right happened to have an effect in
the future such as when the pool fell over.
So we end up doing is we take the some of those discounted rewards.
So we end up saying the original reward 10 plus the discount times and X are Warten Plus the discount
squared times.
The next reward negative 100.
And so we end up applying a score of actually negative seventy point seventy five to that initial action
of going right.
So you can see here that we no longer treat this action as a positive.
Instead we have a negative.
So this was a bad action to take due to the effect they had in the future.
And that's the whole idea of a policy Gradina being able to take into account the rewards that happen
in the future based off your initial action.
So because of this delayed effect sometimes good actions may actually receive bad scores due to bad
actions that immediately follow a good action.
So if we look back here maybe what is really going left on that second action that caused the poll to
fall over.
So there is a delayed effect there and good actions may receive some bad scores due to that.
But to counter this will we end up doing is we train over many episodes and on average good actions
will end up receiving higher scores.
Now we also then in order to do the actual calculation is normalize the actual scores by subtracting
the mean and dividing by the standard deviation and these steps can actually significantly increase
training time for complex environments and you're going to notice that yourself when we actually code
this all out and end up training over many episodes as we get further and further along in future episodes
or more playing of the game.
You'll actually notice that the training time takes longer and longer.
So implementing this grading policy of python and sensor flow can be a bit complex so we're going to
do is quickly go over the steps that we're actually going to be performing in our DOT PI script.
So the first one we're going to do is have the neural network play several episodes of this game then
the optimizer is going to calculate the gradients.
So typically what we've been doing is we call minimize on the optimizer.
But this time instead of minimizing it we're first going to actually compute the gradients and then
we're going to compute each actions discounted and normalized score using the form that we just discussed.
Then we're going to multiply that gradient vector by the actions score and negative scores will end
up creating opposite gradients when multiplied.
So that allows the neural network to learn based off that policy gradient.
And we also want to calculate the mean of the resulting gradient vector to then perform gradient descent
so because of the complexity of manually implementing this policy gradient technique with tensor flow
I really encourage you to check out the extra resources for additional examples and explanations because
as far as the overall idea is concerned it's pretty straightforward but implementing it specifically
with tensor flow can be a bit complex so just keep that in mind take your time.
When we actually code along with it.
OK.
In the next lecture we're going to hop the text editor and code out this policy grading.
I'll see you there.