Welcome back everybody.
Let's go ahead and get started coding out our policy greens.
First we need our imports.
We're going to be using tensor flow of course as well as Jim Lewis as well as Jim and pi so say import
comp. that isn't.
All next step.
Let's go ahead and define our variables.
Very similar to what we did before.
We're going to say the number of inputs will we know that's four.
There's four observations coming back.
Number of hidden neurons let's also keep it for and we'll just do something simple like just one layer
here and then.
Number outputs is going to be one again.
Basically for that action whether you're going left or right and this time we're also going to be finding
a learning rate for our sense of say 0.01.
And we will be using again the T.F. layers API.
So we're going to have an initialiser again will say initialiser is equal to T.F. contrib layers.
And we're going to do it just like we did before the variants scaling initialiser or so we have our
variables.
Let's go ahead and create the network it's going to look similar to what we did last time with a few
minor changes.
So first we are going to create our placeholder and the placeholder is going to hold 32 and the shape
just like last time it's going to be by the number of inputs and then we'll have our first layer let's
call it the hidden layer that's going to be T.F. layers but then Slayer that's connected takes and XTi
inputs has four hidden units or four neurons I should say the activation function.
We're going to go ahead and choose.
Let's go in and choose Eliu for this.
When I was testing around that perform a little better than the rectified linear unit units an exponential
linear unit.
And we also need our kernel initialiser initialiser synthetical to the initialiser we find before and
then our next step here is to actually get the outputs and we're going to do this in two steps.
One of the logic.
And then on the outputs and we'll explain why in a second here.
But we're going to do the following.
We're going to say T.F. Clear's dance Pessin or hidden layer.
And then we want the number outputs out basically just one.
And then we're also going to then find outputs and we're going to pass this sigmoid function.
And the reason for that we're doing this kind of two separate steps.
Previously we essentially did all this in one layer is because we're going to be using both these variables
before and after the function is applied.
So right now it's go ahead and do.
Well we're going to do after this him would function is applied which is get those probabilities.
So we'll say probabilities just like we did last time is equal to if we're going to concatenate along
X to 1 values and it's going to be outputs and one minus outputs.
Then we're going to here is have an action and that's going to be able to multinomial just like we did
last time and we're going to pass in the probabilities and say a number of samples equal to one.
OK.
So very similar to what we did last time except here we're basically splitting this up into two steps
because we're really using both these variables.
And then finally we want to do is actually get some sort of output y to train the network on.
So we're going to say why is equal to and we'll say it's going to be one minus the actual action.
So the action is the probability to go left remember that.
So unfortunately we can't just say one minus action because this action is actually still a tenser and
intenser flow.
But we can easily convert it to a floating point number using tensor flow.
You can say T.F. to flow on that action.
And that way we can interact with it with a normal floating point number.
Right now it's a sensor here to spy action so you can only deal with it if you were to have another
tensor representing just one point zero.
But because we actually want this just to be a floating point number at the end we're going to go ahead
and translate that action or transform that action into a floating point number here.
Next up is for the last function in optimization.
So we're going to be defining cross entropy here.
So T.F. and I we're going to say sigmoid cross entropy with Blodgett's
and we'll say the labels is equal to Y and largest sequel to lodge it's here
OK.
Then the optimizer set that equal to T.F. train and we're going to use an atom optimizer
and then we're going to apply the learning rate from earlier.
OK.
And this is where it's going to differ a little bit from what we've done before.
Well we're going to do.
Instead of minimizing the optimizer we're going to compute the gradients using cross entropy.
So we're going to see gradients and variables because this returns back actually two things we're going
to grab the optimizer and instead of saying minimise based off cross entropy we're going to say compute
the gradients so kind of this in-between step here.
So usually when we did end up doing is saying optimizer minimize cross-bench B.
Right now we're competing the gradients because we're going to multiply these later on by the discounted
scores.
Now in order to work with these actual gradients and variables that are return back when we compute
the gradients later on we're going to want to apply the gradients.
So what we need to do here is a little bit of kind of tensor flow code.
I'm going to copy and paste this from the notes because it's a bit of a lot of code here.
So you can go out and feel free to copy and paste this but let's walk through what this code is actually
doing.
So we've computed the gradients and according to this cross entropy and then we make these three variables
here and lists the gradients themselves the Greaney and placeholders and then the gradients and variables
feed.
So then we're doing a little bit of tuple unpacking here.
So for the Greaney and variables that are returned when you compute the gradients off your optimizer
we're going to append just a gradient to our list of gradients.
Then we're going to create a placeholder here so say gradient placeholder.
Notice the singular here instead of placeholders.
We create a single placeholder for that specific rate and then we append that to this list of placeholders
and that is here we have a list of the gradients analyst the placeholders for the gradients and then
we're going to do here is we have this gradients and variables feed.
We append both the grace the gradient placeholder and the variable here.
Basically creating a list of tuples.
Then once we've done that we're going to at the end of all this say that our actual training operation
that we're doing here is the optimizer and we're going to then apply the gradients and that's going
to be that final feed we just made there.
All right.
So kind of some heavy tension flow just to make sure that we can separate out these steps of actual
gradients instead of the typical minimized function we did before then we're going to do here is quickly
create in it that we did for T.F. global variables initialiser
and then also say saver's equal to T.F. train saver because we're going to save our model later on.
OK.
Now we need to create some or award functions and you can also check out the resource notes there's
a few links or basically URLs that have hints and tips and useful links according to some of the code
we did specific things like how optimized can be gradients how to calculate programmatically what the
atom optimizer actually returns or what methods are available.
And then there's two functions here.
This helper at this count rewards function.
And at this can normalize rewards function.
So I'm going to copy and paste them again from the notes because that's a lot of code to kind of just
go through as far as timing is concerned.
So instead of just going to basically explain it.
So there's two helper functions here will really help her function.
And then one main function this helper function is going to calculate the discount rewards.
So let's walk through this it basically takes in the rewards and then applies the discount rate you
get back the discounted rewards.
So we create this 00 array that has the same length as the rewards that you pass in.
And then we've also taken a discount rate that can be 0.9 5 or 0.9 9 ET cetera.
And then right now we have the cumulative rewards equal to zero.
So we're going to say first step in reversed range.
Length of rewards.
So notice how we're basically going backwards here.
We're going to say that the cumulative rewards is equal to the rewards of that current step plus the
cumulative rewards times the discount rate then we're going to say that this kind of rewards of that
step is equal to the cumulative rewards.
So I think what makes it a little confusing here is the reversed function being used.
But basically the reverse allows you to go backwards starting from the length the awards all the way
to zero here.
So that's what we're doing here and basically what we end up returning is an array of the discounted
towards Once we have the counter awards we can end up doing is by passing in all rewards and the discount
rate we're going to use this help or this rewards function and then normalize them using the mean and
standard deviation.
So this is the main function that we're going to be using later on and what it's going to do is taken
all the rewards and the discount rate.
So I notice that this is going to take quite a while to actually calculate this function as we play
more and more games that you take in all the awards particularly at this country you're using then you
create this empty list called all this kind of rewards and then you going to save for every single reward
in this list of all rewards will you end up doing is you append the actual result of help or this rewards.
So the rewards and discount rate so so what's happening here.
We're going to have a giant list of a bunch rewards from all these games that you've played.
And eventually we're going to pass these in to the help her this kind of rewards which is this function
right here that actually calculates the discount.
So this calculates the discount and then once you have that well we end up doing is we flatten this
out using concatenate and then you calculate the mean deviation and then you perform the normalization
here subtracting the mean and dividing by the standard deviation for every set of counter awards in
all this kind of rewards.
So this is essentially if we scroll back to the left here this this kind of rewards that we end up creating
is going to be a giant list of a bunch of rewards for each of the games that we've been playing.
All right.
Once we've done that the next thing to do is to actually just code out our actual training session.
So we're going to do that in the next video but once you come to the training session that we can then
run the train model on environment and then visualize how it performed.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.