All right.
So here we are where we left off last time it's now time to actually begin creating our session.
So the first thing I want to do is create our environment.
Say Jim go ahead and make carpool version 0 which is just the shorter version of carpool.
And we want to specified the few more variables for this training session.
One is the actual number of game rounds we're going to go ahead and do.
So say number of game rounds is equal to 10.
Then we also wanted to find the maximum of game steps will allow.
We'll just set that as 1000.
Even though it's probably unlikely that we reach a thousand steps.
Basically how many times steps in a single session of the game will we allow the model to do before
we actually manually say it's done and the number of iterations and the number of training or excuse
me a number of times we actually run this it's going to be let's say 650.
You can go ahead and run something lower around 100 to actually get a model to perform well it has to
be probably above 600 but obviously it's going to take longer training time and then we also need to
actually say where our discount rate is.
We will choose 0.9 0.9 for now you can play around with that as well.
So let's say with T.F. session as SPSS will say the session run the initialiser to initialiser actual
variables and then we're going to have several four loops in here.
So the first we're going to do is for the number of actual iterations.
So for every iteration in the range of the number of iterations with this number of iterations we're
going to print what iteration we're currently on.
So on iteration.
And then let's go out and save format and passen iteration there.
Then we're going to create a list called all rewards and analysts called all gradients
then for every iteration we're going to do is we're going to play an amount of game rounds.
So essentially since we said 10 game rounds four for every single iteration.
So six hundred fifty times we're going to play ten rounds at this game.
So we'll save for game in range number of game rounds.
So it's one of these We're going to say the current Warde's and the current gradients.
So notice the difference here we have all the records and all the gradients that we're keeping track
of on an iteration scale.
But then for the actual game rounds we have the current wards and ingredients for that particular round
games.
Let's go ahead and create our observations for our environment so we get those initial four observations
in that array and then we'll say for step in range and this is the max game steps.
Technically this isn't necessary you could just let it go until it finishes or says done but we'll go
ahead and have a cutoff like 1000 steps.
Like I mentioned it's unlikely I would ever actually reach 1000 steps.
That's quite a long running of that game.
Then we'll do the following.
We'll say grab the action value.
And the gradients value basing session run and we'll grab action and gradients from what we find before.
And then we're going to pass in a feed dictionary
Let's go in and zoom out just a little bit so we can see how this whole thing.
So say feed dictionary is equal to x and we're passing in observations now remember observations sometimes
it gets returned back as something like comma four instead of one comma for as far as shape.
So we will reshape this so will reshape this to be one by the number of inputs which is essentially
just one by four as we expected.
OK so we get Becher action value in her gradients values.
So then we want to perform that action so will say operations reward done and info is equal to just
like we did before passing into the step function.
Grab the action value.
But because of the way it's handled in intenser we need to do some indexing here.
So we need to grab it using two sets of indexing then we're going to get the current reward and current
gradients.
So the current rewards we're going to append reward here and then we'll say the current's gradients
we're going to pen gradients value here and then if the game is done.
So let's say we fail the game the pool fell over.
We'll just go ahead and break
OK.
So that's all we're going to do basically play that game 10 times.
And then once you've done that we're going to take our list of all the rewards that we've been earning
so far and append the list of the current gradients and the current rewards so current rewards loops
make sure we do append here and do the same thing for all of gradings append currents gradients
OK.
There we go.
So we just appended the list to our rewards and then the next part is basically going to be multiplying
those adjusted scores with the discounts against the gradients.
So the next step then is to apply that discount and normalized rewards function so let's do that here.
We'll say all rewards isn't equal to calling this count and it normalized rewards all rewards.
Discount rate and take note about the indentation here.
We're doing this in line with this for loop here.
So take careful note of that can be very easy to mess that up.
Ok sweet and normalize the rewards and then we'll also create an empty feed dictionary that we're going
to use in just a second.
So say the dictionary is then equal to an empty dictionary which you can just say by having some empty
curly braces they're.
And then the next set of instructions is actually going to be applying the scores that we just calculated
to the gradients.
So this is actually probably the most complicated part of this and it's really easy to get a typo in
here and mess this up.
So I'm going to copy this from the notes get a copy and paste this and then kind of explain we're going
on here.
And the reason it's easy to mess up is because it's a lot cleaner if you use it to list comprehensions
really just one list comprehensions but has to form statements inside of it which is why it's condensed
and there's a lot going on here.
But it's a little cleaner this way than having a bunch of nested for loops.
So let's take a look at we're doing here.
We're going to say for every variable index and every gradient placeholder in the enumerated version
the gradient placeholders are more numerate just gives you back and index location.
We're going to grab the mean gradients.
So that's going to be taking the average of the result of this list comprehension.
So here you are doing is you're multiplying the reward times all gradients except it's just a single
gradient because you take it at the game index for that step at the variable index.
And essentially these two for loops are for you to grab these index locations so you multiply the correct
reward by the correct gradient.
And that's probably what causes the complexity here.
The fact that you need to grab the correct game index at the correct step at the correct variable index
because remember now when you take a look at all the rewards you have a bunch of them and you have a
bunch of them for each game and a bunch more for each iteration.
So this sort of miscomprehension just makes sure that you multiply the correct award by the correct
gradient.
Then once you've done that in your feed dictionary what you're saying is for this particular gradient
placeholder now you have the ingredients there and then once you have that you can actually run your
session so we can say in-session run the training operation where the feed dictionary is going to be
called to the feed dictionary we just created and then we can see the following.
You'll say Prince saving graph and session so that after each time we perform this we'll go in and say
the grafting session and we'll say Savir that save save the session and save this somewhere and we'll
say models slash my mom my let's see policy model.
And then we can also do that just saves the actual session.
We can also export the graph if we want to run this in another file so we can show you how to do that
as well.
We can say Medhat graph the F equals T.F. train export Medich RAF Flip's.
And then you give it a file name.
So you could say file is equal to models and let's go ahead and have this be my policy model.
And it's a metafile here.
We'll go ahead and add these two forward slashes here.
So we actually create that their victory OK.
So then we're going to save that and then we'll will the model and we'll go ahead and run it on the
environment.
So I'm going to copy and paste this code from the notes as well because essentially the exact same code
here except we're going to render it so we create the carpool environment.
So the observations.
And then we load up the models that we just trained up here and then we say just do a single run except
we're going to actually render the environment this time.
So we can actually see visually how it performed.
So let's come up here.
Let's go ahead and run this.
We'll go ahead and run this for let's say 750 steps going to save that.
Let's expand the terminal here and let's call this we'll say Python and right now I wrote this all into
my test Jim.
Pi will hit enter and let's make sure we don't get any typos or errors here.
Hopefully we didn't get any.
Make sure you actually check.
So let's see module's flow has a variance scalar initialiser looks like a forgotten extra either.
Let's go to 11 and fix that.
That seems to be a common mistake for me.
So to fix it they're come up to 11 and fix their Hopefully that's it.
Let's go to make sure we don't actually miss an eye somewhere else.
So Python might touch him up by running the one more a typo one or 5.
Come down here fix that as well.
Save it one last time and hopefully that took care of all the typos.
OK.
So here you can see we're saving it off every iteration and then we're going to be running through this
over and over again.
If you want.
You don't have to be saving each iteration.
That is a little bit of extra time to keep saving it.
But just in case there's a crash somewhere it might be nice to have it save on like the 500 run instead
of having it crash on five of one and then not having it at the very end.
So just keep that in mind.
I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done training.
All right.
So we're getting close to the very end.
Hopping forward in time here.
Once to hit 750.
We should see it run that train the model on the environment.
So you should see the run there pop up.
There it is.
You can see here it's bouncing quite much a lot better than what we saw earlier.
Keep in mind it's supposed to cancel once it leaves screen.
So that's where we see it close.
Once the cart leaves that little section of the screen but you could see there it was able to actually
balance the pole thanks to this policy gradient.
OK.
Thanks everyone.
Make sure to check out the notes in case you need to reference any of the code you saw here.