Welcome everyone the tensor flow basics section of the course so I've already had a crash course on
the very basic libraries that we use of Python.
And then we've already covered a very basic introduction to neural networks.
Now it's time to use this section of the course to expand what have already learned and begin to actually
explore tensor Flo's framework approach to neural networks.
And hopefully you're going to be seeing lots of parallels with our own simple implementation that we
performed in the previous section.
So let's cover what this section is actually going to do.
We're first going to start off with just going over the basic syntax for tensor flow and then we'll
discuss tensor flow graphs variables and placeholders.
And those are all going to feel very familiar based of what we've already covered.
Then we'll actually implement a tensor float neural network then we'll continue showing some simple
examples of using tensor flow for a regression task member that's supervised learning as well as a classification
task.
So we have to code along lectures one for aggression one for classification.
Then to make sure you feel comfortable all the topics we've covered in the section we'll finish it off
with two exercises a regression task exercise and then a corresponding solution lecture as well as a
classification exercise.
And again a solution lecture for that.
OK let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture where we began the basic syntax of tensor flow.