Welcome everyone to this lecture on tensor float graphs so tensor flow makes heavy use of graphs and
a lot of this actually happens behind your code basically behind the scenes or under the hood.
But let's go and discuss the basic idea behind graphs graphs are sets of connected nodes.
And sometimes these are called vertices and the connections themselves between nodes are referred to
as edges.
So if you have two notes that are connected the connection itself is an edge between those two nodes
and intenser flow.
Each node is an operation with possible inputs that can supply some sort of output and hopefully this
feels familiar from our previous section.
So in general with tent's flow we're going to construct a graph and then execute it.
We're going to start by showing a very simple example in Python and then we're also going to discuss
how tensor flow uses a default graph.
So the very first graph that we're going to create is this one right here where essentially it's going
to have two nodes each of them a constant.
So and one and two are the two nodes and the respectively the constant that these two notes hold are
one and two that we're going to put them into an operation node and three which is going to be an add
operation and then they'll output three.
Let's open the Jupiter notebook and code this out.
Or it's already imported tensor flow as T.F. And let's start by creating our first two notes which are
just those constants.
So say T.F. constants We'll have that one here and then into to that second node is also going to be
a constant and we'll have that beat too.
So then our third node and three is just going to be.
And one plus and two.
And now we've essentially created a graph where we have two nodes and then the operation noter and three
is just that adding them together.
So then we're going to say with CEF session as SPSS go ahead and set the results as sess that run that
third node for us and then let's go ahead and print that result.
And here we have three.
So if I had just asked to print the third node I would have gotten Hey tensor and this add six.
Just because I've been calling code before and then it reset the kernel but again here we have the actual
result after running it in a session.
So I want to briefly talk about default graphs with tensor flow.
When you start tensor flow a default graph is created and you can actually create additional graphs
pretty easily.
So for example if I say Prince T.F. dot get and then there's going to be a default graph.
It's also a default session.
But let's just talk about graphs for now.
So if I run this it says TFK default graph and it returns back the graph object.
I currently have operating at this point in memory on my computer.
Obviously you're going to have a different point here when you print this out.
So then I can say G is equal to dot graph.
And then if I check out print G I can see it's grabbing a different graph here that I just created.
So now I have my default graph and then this variable g which is another graph.
So if I want to set this new graph as a default what I can do is the following.
I'm going to recreate two graphs again.
One is going to be graph one which is going to be the current default graph.
So I have graph 1 is the current the build that wrong graph 1.
The real is the current default graph.
So if I say print graph 1 that memory does Lineup with my default graph.
So look at CCS are at the end.
Here we have CCPs 0.
So graph 1 is currently my default graph I'm going to say graph 2 is equal to some graph run that prints
graph 2.
So now currently I technically have three graphs.
I have my default graph in graph 1.
I have this letter which we won't really be using but that's also a graph.
And then I have graph 2 over here.
So what would happen if I wanted to set graph 2 as my default graph.
Well all I can do is the following I can say with graph to dot and then each graph has a as default
command.
So then I can say with Graph 2 as a default then I can do something.
So let's go in and say print and anoints say graph 2.
We use the is operator in Python to say is gets default graph.
So now that prints true.
So I can say with Graph 2 as a default print graph too is the fault graph.
And if I try to print this line outside of this with statements and you can copy and paste this.
Notice that it's going to be false because currently outside of this at a global scale graph one is
currently the default graph.
But if I ever have multiple graphs and I want to set one of them as the default I can say with this
one as the default.
Now typically for pretty much all or use cases throughout the course this sort of definition of setting
something as a default graph isn't going to be too important for us.
It mainly comes into play as far as our notebooks are concerned when we kind of need to reset things
and make sure that we're dealing with one graph.
As we get multiple variables in multiple graphs sometimes towards the end of a cell we want to make
sure hey we have one graph here and it's one thing run one operation.
So we'll reset it as the default.
But you won't really see this command that often throughout the course.
I just want you to be aware of it so that when you do see it it's not kind of a total mystery.
OK.
So that's basically it.
Hopefully this first part felt really familiar to you because we've already done it kind of like three
times.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to begin discussing variables in placeholders with tensor flow.
I'll see you there.