Welcome everyone to this lecture on using tensor flow for variables and placeholders so there's really
two main types of tents or objects in a tensor flow graph.
And we're going to talk about variables and placeholders and they should feel already familiar based
off the last section of the course.
During the optimization process tensor flow tune's the parameters of the model to try to get a better
fit on your training data and the variables can hold the values of weights and biases throughout the
session variables do need to be initialized.
So when you're running your session you're going to run a line command that initializes all the variables
that you've already defined.
Now let's talk about placeholders placeholders as we've already discussed are initially empty and they're
used to feed in the actual training examples.
That is your actual data that you're training your model on.
However you should note they do need a declared expected data type.
For example T.F. flow 32 with an optional shape argument.
So what the placeholder is doing it's going to be empty at first.
Essentially a placeholder and then your data is going to be fed into that placeholder.
A lot of times in small batches so that placeholder needs to know mainly two things what the data type
is going to look like whether it's going to be an integer floating point number etc..
And then it also needs to know the shape of the data.
All right let's go ahead and see some examples of each.
And then once we understand placeholders and variables we're going to be ready to build our first model
with tensor flow.
Let's open up a Jupiter notebook.
All right.
So just very quickly I'm going to show you the syntax used intenser flow for variables and placeholders.
And I'm actually going to create an interactive session here so I'll say T.F. interactive session.
That way it can run all of this in different cells.
So I'll say my tensor is equal to.
And let's go ahead and create a tensor of let's say a random uniform.
So we'll say random uniform and we're going to make this be a four by four and if we take a look we'll
say minimum value is zero maximum value is 1.
So now we have this tensor So if I take a look at it my tensor it's this random uniform tensor flew
32.
So notice here has 32 data type.
So then I'm going to create a variable and this is going to be T.F. variable and if you take a look
at the initial arguments here you have an initial valuable initial value excuse me trainable collections
etc. mainly all we have to do is just tell it the actual initial value.
So we're seeing actual value is equal to my tensor.
The rest of that can be under defaults.
So now if I say print's my variable I now have T.F. variable.
So if I actually want to run this variable.
So if I say session run my variable you'll notice you get a failure here and that's because as I mentioned
in the slides you need to initialize your variables so you're going to see us run initialize lines pretty
much every single model we build.
So the way you do that let me husht to come at this out first is you need to say in its is equal to
T.F. and you'll say global variables initializer initialiser open and close parentheses and then will
you need to do is run this initializer first.
So I'll say that session run.
And a lot of times you'll see us run this nation with with session.
But right now we're just doing interactive session.
So I need to run this initializations or say SEST thought run in it.
And now all these variables have been initialized so I should be able to run this line again.
And hopefully now I see that four by four matrix of random uniform numbers.
And there it is four by four random numbers.
So again the key thing to note here is when you're creating a variable and you intend to use it in your
session you're going to need to initialize all these variables and it's quite simple after you create
your variables.
You just set this in two global variables initializer and then some more in your session you're going
to run it.
And that allows you to run all of these variables in the operations that depend on them.
Placeholders look really similar.
So I'm going to make a really simple placeholder here.
PH's equal to we'll see T.F. leps place holder and then mainly the thing to say is what data type to
expect and what shape to expect.
So for instance a lot of times you can just say T.F. will say flow 32 or 64.
Generally for us 32 bits of information is more than enough for all our training.
And then depending on what shape you expect you can say shape is equal to something like none or 4 or
maybe four by four etc..
That really depends on the data itself.
So we're going to cover that in a little more detail later on.
But for now we can just say there is no shape and then we have a placeholder.
OK.
So again those are variables in placeholders.
So really the thing you need to remember out of this lecture is that once you create a variable before
you run it in your session you need to initialize all the variables placeholders essentially the same
thing you provide a data type.
And as far as the shape it's really common to have a shape that looks as far as the tuples concerned
something like none.
Comma 5.
And the reason a lot of times if you're looking stuff up in the documentation you see placeholders with
this first one being none is because none as this first one can be filled with the actual number of
samples in the data which if you're feeding it in batches you may not know beforehand before creating
the placeholder.
So a lot of times you'll see that none and there will be more clear as we create our own models and
sensor flow.
All right.
Now that we understand this we're ready to build our first model which we're going to do in the next
lecture.
I'll see you there.