Welcome everyone to this lecture we're actually going to construct our very first tensor float neural
network.
We've learned about all the pieces that work with tensor flow such as sessions graphs variables and
placeholders and with these building blocks we can now create our first neuron and our neural network.
We're going to create a neural network that performs a very simple linear fit to some to them internal
data that is we're going to have some features and then we're going to just say what is why given this
X source steps are the following.
We'll build the graph initiate the session and then feed data in and get some sort of output back and
we're going to use the basic components such as placeholders variables that we've learned so far to
accomplish this task.
So what does or graph actually going to look like when we designed this linear fit.
Well it should look like in matrix form something like W X plus B is equal to Z and you can see here
that it's has lots of parallels with a simple linear line of y m x plus B.
Except we're kind of choosing different variable terms here to line up more with kind of the classic
neuron.
So we're going to have a weight variable w and then we're going to multiply it by a placeholder object
x.
So that's what we're actually going to feed in our data.
We're gonna have an operation and matrix multiplication and then to that result we'll have another note
in the graph which is going to be another operation where we add in that be variable that we can pass
into an activation function such as the sigmoid function.
Afterwards we can add in the cost function in order to train your network to optimize the parameters
such as that w term.
And that beat her let's go ahead and build out the neural network.
We're going to start with just a really simple review of using placeholders variables graphs and sessions.
Just going to do some simple additive operations and multiplicative operations then will actually build
out the neural network but chip to chip it up and get started.
OK first thing to do in the notebook is a couple of imports.
I'm going to import some pies and P and sensor flow as tya and then I'm also going to be setting some
random seed of values here.
That way you can make sure you get the same random results.
I do and T.F. are a tensor flow also has a set random seed Suddenlink say and P that ran that seed set
it to 101 as well as tensor Flo's random seed.
And you want to make sure you run the cells in the same order I do.
If you run a cell more than once you may not get the same random numbers that I'm getting here.
So pay attention to this little encounter OPERATOR And you can always restart everything but just saying
kernel restart and run all or you can just go sell run all let's come over here and create some random
data.
So this is just for demonstration purposes.
I kind of want to show you how you could build a very simple session for simple operation such as addition
and multiplication.
Once we have that down we'll actually create our neural network.
Right now I'm just going to create some random data points.
So we'll say Ampyra in that uniform.
Going from zero to 100 and then let's ask it to be in the shape five by five.
And let's get our Random data out.
So here we have a random array and you should have the exact same number of values I do here.
Then we're going to do the same thing for a random B and P ran them uniform and the only thing that's
going be different here is the shape of this it's that five by five it's going to be 5 by 1.
And then if you want check it out.
It should look like this.
And again you should have the exact same numbers I do here.
If you are concerned you're not going in same numbers just run the seed in the same line or the same
cell as these random uniforms.
Up next we need to create placeholders for these random uniform objects so let's go in and create them
or create two variables A and B they're both going to be placeholders.
And the only thing I really need to provide here is what data point or what data type I expect so we'll
say to float 32.
Now we're going to say B is equal to T.F. placeholder to float 32.
Later on when we talk about convolutional neural networks that shape parameters going to be more important.
But right now a and b just default shape Nunn's fine to float through to both of them.
That's totally fine.
Now let's create some operations to really simple operations just additive and multiplicative.
So there's two ways I could do this.
One is I could call these methods off the tensor flow.
So there is an add operation directly up tensor flow.
And if you do shift enter here it says returns x plus y element wise thing to do is called Multiply
here.
Multiply tensor for has that as well and its performs X times Y element wise and then it also has a
matrix multiplication at all.
And it says multiplies matrix A matrix B cetera.
But what's nice about tensor flow is that it can actually understand the builtin Python operations or
operator symbols so we can say a plus b and it's going to understand when we actually pass that intersession
that I'm just asking for.
In addition there Cendant going to also say Moel up for multiplication operation is equal to a times
b.
Now what I'm going to do is create some sessions that they can use graphs with feed dictionaries to
actually get results off of these operations.
I'll type out with session as S S S I want to get the results of this ad and I will say session or cesse
thought run and then I need a passen the operation as well as a feed dictionary.
So we have our operation here at up and that's going to add a plus b remember a and b those are placeholder
objects.
So they still need data.
And the way we provide data using Tusser flow is with a feed dictionary our feed dictionary is going
to be a dictionary where the keys are the actual placeholders and then the values corresponding to those
keys is the data that has to be filled into those placeholders.
For example I can say a is going to be the value 10 and B is going to be the value 20.
So I can say print ad results and when I run this I should see 30 because 10 plus 20 is 30.
Now we can go ahead and it's it's just 10 we're going to add in our random data here.
And now when I run this I see the results of adding those together and this is Matrix addition because
member had a 5 by 5 and 8 5 by 1 here.
But you get the idea that essentially you're just having a field dictionary have a placeholder and then
that data you're going to feed it.
Let's do the same thing for our multiplication result.
So say multiply result is equal to session run.
And then our location OPERATOR We have a feed dictionary here and then same thing we can say Rande a
and then B is brand the B and then we're just going to print those results or say multiply results run
that.
And now we should see two results here.
So we see two matrices and if you want you can add a print new line.
So they're a little more space than there you have it.
OK.
So that's a really simple example of running a session to create a graph with a feed dictionary.
Up next in the next lecture we're actually going to create the example neural that work that we discussed
in the sleights.
I'll see you there.