Welcome back everyone.
I'm here in the same notebook as last time so last time we just created a really simple session graph
and now we're going to do is create a very simple example neural network just to kind of get the flow.
And then after that we're going to create a full network example we'll create some artificial data that
does follow some sort of linear trend and then we're going to create a neural network that can solve
this regression problem with a cost function and an optimizer.
But again I want to build this up really slowly because if you see all at once it looks a little confusing.
So we built up this really simple example of a graph that is just an addition operation and the multiplication
operation.
Now it's build up a really simple neural network.
A lot of times in your neural networks you're going to have a top level cell that has a bunch of constant
variable names defined for example and features your data probably won't change features as you train
it hopefully.
So Ill say lets our data has 10 features to it.
Then you'll do something like define how many neurons are going to be in the various layers right now.
We'll just pretend we have one layer of three dense neurons so we'll say.
And then neurons is equal to three.
All right.
Now we also know we need placeholders and variables will create a placeholder for X so T.F. placeholder
and we need to provide in the data type.
So we'll say flow 32 which is basically we're always going to be using in this course unless we specifically
have integers and then we also need to find the shape.
So it's really common to say none because that depends on how big of a batch of data you're feeding
into your neural network.
And then as the second parameter here we do know the number of features.
So we should expect X to be receiving an array of the number of samples by the number of features.
So it makes sense that the rows are the number of samples and then the columns or the number of features.
So typically a sort of placeholder is going to look like.
And then you're also going to have variables.
For example we have the W variable for our weights.
We'll just say T.F. variable and we want to initialize these weights using some sort of random unus.
And we'll discuss this later on.
What are good ways to initialize Waite's initialize the term of abayas terms.
But right now we're going to use brand than normal That's the random normal distribution that's built
into tensor flow.
And then we're going to find the shape of it to be the number of features by the number of neurons in
our layer.
So in this case we have one layer and it's going to just be dense neurons and we're going to do a similar
thing for our biased term let's say T.F. variable and we can either just have this zeros or ones that
really matter for example but I'll say T.F. ones.
And in this case the shape is just going to be number of neurons.
And the reason for that is because remember w is going to be multiplied by X for matrix multiplication
we have to make sure that this dimension of columns matches this dimension of rows when you're multiplying
it.
And then this dimension of dense neurons needs to match up well how many neurons you have as far as
the bias term that we're adding in or that be.
We're going to need to make sure that just matches the number of neurons because we're adding B but
we're going to multiply X by W..
So that's the reason we have these specific shapes so we'll run that then we're going to need some sort
of operation and activation function.
So you'll have something like X times w or W X doesn't really matter here.
And then all that will be a matrix multiplication between X and W then we'll have z be the output of
that so be T.F. add X and W B.
So notice here now I'm using those tensor flow operators instead of just saying Asterix or plus.
Because I want to make sure that tons flow understands that doing matrix multiplication and addition
typically actually smart enough to convert as we saw appear these pluses and Asterix but a lot of times
the documentation you want to make sure you specific that it's tensor flow so we'll go ahead and kind
of stick with this convention for now.
And finally we want to pass this into some sort of activation function.
So I'll say a is equal to T.F. dot and there's lots of activation functions available for you.
There's the 10 H or hyperbolic tangent activation function.
There's also if you do T.F. dot and n dots are e l u.
There's a rectified linear unit and later on we'll see kind of higher abstractions is just create an
entire layer of specific neuron types.
But for right now we'll just do a really simple activation function of sigmoid and then we pass on the
OK.
So what do we have so far we find the number of features on our data then neurons the placeholder variables.
Then we said OK multiply X times Y or excuse me x times w then add B to the result of that and then
pass the result of that into the sigmoid function.
Now it's time to run this in a really simple session and then we're going to say in it is equal to T.F.
we want to say global variables initialiser run that and then we'll say with C-f session as s s s I'm
going to run D in it for the initialiser and then I'm going to say the la out.
That is the result of each of those neurons is going to be session run a number that's that kind of
final operation that has the rest of those operation graphs in place or operation graph I should say.
And let's pass in a dictionary.
So we just have X as a single placeholder and it's going to fit in some random values from non-pilot
say random random and we'll have to have the shape of one by and of features.
So I'm essentially just feeding it one sample.
So our results are not going we just make sure we have that correct.
Forgot to actually make this a dictionary.
The Riego curly braces and curly braces.
OK.
So our result as I mentioned is almost going to be meaningless because it's just a really simple example
more for syntax.
But here we have the results later out of each of these neurons.
So again we had three neurons up here.
And when we ran this with some random data your results may be different depending on how many times
you ran ran them but you should see some sort of results out here and hopefully you also see that all
the values are between 0 and 1 because we're using the sigmoid function.
Now the absolute key thing to notice which is kind of stopping this from solving our problem is the
fact that we're not adjusting the values of W or B.
We basically just said OK choose some random values of W have B's all equal to 2 1 and then run this
one time and see what happens out.
That is not how we actually run a neural network.
We want to then go back and adjust W and B or are different variables based off some sort of cost function.
So we need have some cost function and some optimizer in order to adjust W and B.
So let's go ahead and now work through a more realistic example of some regression.
Just a really simple regression example.
So let me label this as kind of our simple regression example and this is probably going to be the most
realistic example we've seen so far of tensor flow everything before this have kind of been really toy
examples or incomplete partial examples.
Now it's time to actually kind of dive in.
So I'm going to say X data is equal to lend space 0 by 10 by 10.
So I want 10 linearly spaced points between 0 and 10 and then I'm going to add just a little bit of
noise to it.
So we'll say random uniform and we'll see negative 1.5 to 1.5 by 10.
So then what does this actually look like.
Well it looks like some numbers between 0 and 10 using linearly spaced except we went ahead and added
some noise to add or subtract that from noise to it.
So we have these random numbers and we're adding or subtracting them to the linearly spaced points here.
So let's actually now plot this out and we're going to have a label attached to it.
So the labels are also going to be and P will in space 0 to 10 to 10 and then I'm going to add in some
random uniform data here.
Same deal.
1.5.
And then let's say 10.
Now it's not a huge deal if you don't get the exact same numbers I'm getting here because we want to
do is have a model that can fit to just kind of some noisy data that has a linear trend.
So I want to plot this out to show what we actually created here.
So x data versus Y label and whoops I forgot the important that.
Let's do that now we'll say.
Import map plot.
Type plot as Piazzi.
And since I'm in the notebook I need to say map plotted in line remembering to say Pulte that show you're
not using a Jupiter note book.
Now let's run this.
And let's also make sure that we're running it with points.
So I'll say Asterix here.
OK.
So I have my data and it looks like some random data but there's clearly some sort of a linear trend
here which makes sense because technically the data is exactly the same and Piland space zero through
10 unpeeling nearly spaces are 310.
We just added a little bit of noise to it.
So we randomly chose a value between negative 1.5 1.5 for each of these points and then added it to
it.
So your data should be different than mine or maybe you have the exact same data.
Nop that's not really what matters here.
What matters is you have some sort of linear trend and it should be a pretty obvious linear trend which
is sort of similar points and higher points if you are not getting a trend which would be extremely
unlikely then just run these two lines again and you'll have a trend.
OK.
So we have some noisy data.
Let's go ahead and actually create our own your own network to start off.
We're going to go ahead and do the following.
We'll say Remember I'm trying to solve like was Amex plus be here.
So let me actually make this into a comment or something so there we go we have like was exposed be
so I'll say M is equal to T.F. variable and we can go ahead and initialize this so let's initialize
this with some random values.
I'm going to say N.P. random ran 2.
So this is going to give me two random values and I'm going to initialize M and B to be random values.
So again does it really matter if you have the same or and the values are not for this part.
I know I said previously for other sections or other lecturers that didn't matter here.
I would actually kind of prefer if it did not have the same Thalia's I did.
That way you can really see that the neural network is working for any random data set.
And we're going import this right here and pass that in.
So the reason I'm doing that is just to make it really obvious to you the student that can be right
now are just totally random numbers.
So I want you to get to ran the numbers and initialize these variables as random numbers.
It's going to be up to the neural network with the cost function and the optimizer to fix these values
to actually create a nice fitted line here.
So I'm going to run that.
And speaking of the cost function Let's go ahead and create it.
Now so I will create a variable called error.
And currently the error starts off as 0 then I'll do the following.
I'll say for x and y in Zipp which is essentially going to make a list of tuples of each point in X
Dedo of its corresponding y label.
I'll do the following.
I will say y hat which has my predicted value is equal to m times x plus b.
Again this is just our linear equation here.
This is my predictive value.
So right now my predictive value is probably going to be way off because the values of m and b are just
totally random.
So we need to fix this in order to fix this.
I need to have some sort of cost function.
Calculating the error.
So my error.
I'm going to add on the squared error.
So will say why is the true value member.
Why is that actual.
Why label.
So we're treating this Y as a true value.
And I'm going to subtract my predicted value which is why.
So when we start off this error is going to be pretty bad because these are random values.
So I'm going to measure my error and add on this and then I'm also going to square it to punish higher
errors.
So again this is what we want to minimize.
We want to minimize error which is why this is our cost function.
In order to minimize this we need to use some sort of optimizer which is step number two here.
So we'll say optimizer is equal to T.F. train and this is where we actually use grading the set.
Remember we discussed how grading the sent figures out how to best reduce that cost.
So if you say T.F. but train G.R. you should be able to tap autocomplete the Create the optimizer parameter
we need to provide our grading the optimizer is the learning rate.
Remember that the learning rate here basically defines how fast are we going to descent down on this.
And if we have two large learning rate then we may overshoot the actual minimum that we're looking for.
If we have too small of a learning rate then it's going to take us forever to actually do that gradient
descent.
Now for different problems different learning rates apply.
But right now let's go ahead and just use 0.00 one can check if it has a default learning rate.
I'm not sure if it actually does.
But right now 0.00 one that's a pretty common thing to start off with.
It really depends on your particular data set.
What makes sense.
And later on we'll also learn about things like some more advanced optimization functions.
But right now keeping it simple we have our optimizer.
We need to tell our optimizer what it actually is looking to minimize.
So our optimizer is going to have a method called minimize.
And we want to passen the variable it's trying to minimize it trying to minimize error.
Ok so now we have that and we're actually almost ready to go.
We need to do is create that global initialiser for the variables or say global variables initialiser
and then we're all that's left is really to create the session and run.
So let's briefly show everything we just did here as a quick review and then we'll run our session.
OK so what we actually do for the simple regression example I need some sort of data I want that data
to have some sort of linear form.
In order for me to predict a simple whitewalls mix plus B line on this.
So what do I do.
I say ex-state is linearly spaced from 0 to 10 of 10 points.
And then I add a little bit of noise to it also add a little bit of noise to the label.
So I get some sort of fit that's linear but again it's noisy that way it's not just a perfect straight
line.
So you should have some sort of noisy data say here but it does just have a general trend to be kind
of this line here.
OK.
So I want my neural network to solve this equation.
Weikel X plus B.
So I'm going to initialize it with a random value of M that is the slope of the line as well as a random
value of B.
That is the intercept and I show that I'm doing it randomly just by choosing the values that this random
output.
So I want to make sure that you don't think these are some special values that I'm choosing.
You should put just some random numbers that non-pay provides you then I need to calculate the error.
So I need some way to measure how off I am.
So I will say go ahead and predict y hat and then compare it to the true y label here.
Square that and that's going to be my error.
Then I need to perform gradient descent to attempt to minimize the error.
So I want to optimize this and that's going to be what the actual trainer is going to be.
And then we have global variables initialiser Baltz create the session and run it.
So say with T.F. the session as se s I'm going to say.
SS run in it's and then now I have to decide how many steps to take.
So how many training steps am I actually going to perform.
So let's say training steps is equal to 1 right now.
That's probably way too low but we'll see what happens will say for I in range of the number of training
steps.
Go ahead and say let's scroll down here session.
Run and run.
Train remember train is that optimizer is trying to minimize that error.
Then finally I want to fetch back my results so I don't say final slope and the final intercept was
is equal to session run and I'm going to grab an and B from my session.
So I'm going to run this.
I would expect this to perform a pretty bad job just off of one training step potentially just should
be what we started with.
Let's go ahead and evaluate the results and to do this I will do the following.
I will say X test is equal to the linear space it will go from negative 1 to 11.
Just this is just for the plot to look a little nicer.
Now we want 10 points in between that and then I wanted to say why pred for the plot is equal to Y calls
X plus B.
So you know I have y is equal to x.
Plus B.
So I'm going to choose the final slope that my model said was good.
After just one training session that is going to multiply by x test and then I will say plus the final
intercept and let's plot this out.
So we'll say Piazzi plot x.
Test data and then y plot.
And then I want to grab my actual real data over here.
So it's copy that and paste it here and let's have this be a red line.
So I'll say are here.
So I run this and you actually notice after just one training step that a pretty good job of fixing
those weights.
Let's go ahead and run it for a little say 100.
It's a really simple equation.
You can see it already had a pretty good fit.
But if we run it again then we can see we have a better fit.
OK.
So again let me just do one here.
It's hard to see the differences because the data is really easy to fit to you can see our line is probably
a little off.
But when we run it a 100 times we're able to choose better m and b values.
OK.
That's really all there is to it for this simple example.
Coming up next we're going to do show you an even more realistic example of a tensor regression.
Now we're really going to kind of hammer this in and we're going to deal with a panic state of frame
kind of show you what it would look like to read in some data feed it to the regression and with a lot
more data points will have to fit it in with batches.
But for now go ahead and take this step by step.
I would really recommend you check out the notebook and review it really understand what these last
couple of cells are doing here.
OK.
You have any questions post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'll see you at the next lecture.