Welcome everyone to this lecture on a sensor flow regression example we're going to code along for more
realistic regression example and will also introduce tensor Flo's TFT estimator API which is a much
simpler API for basic tasks like regression and classification.
There are already lots of machine learning algorithms that can perform regression tasks and classification
tasks very well.
And the purpose of tensor flow really is to try to solve problems that typical machine learning algorithms
can't solve things like image classification or later on we'll see how we can use tensor flow for things
like word embeddings or even using her current neural networks for time series analysis.
Those are problems that are really hard to solve without the use of a deep neural network or specialized
neural networks using tensor flow simpler examples like typical regression tasks and classification
tasks are pretty easy to solve.
Well depending on your dataset with other machine learning algorithms and because of that sensor flow
has a nice estimator API that's going to make your life a lot easier if you decide to use tensor flow
for some of these more basic supervised learning problems.
So let's go ahead hop over to Jupiter notebook and show you how to perform a regression task on a more
realistic data set.
All right.
I'm going to start off with a couple of imports.
I'll do some PI SNP.
Most also going to be using Pandurs and I will import that plot lib pipe plot as Piazzi and then set
map plot live in line and then later on we're also going to need to use tensor flow of course.
Let's do that as well.
Import tensor flow as T.F..
But we're going to do for this regression task is do a huge dataset.
So we can actually create a very large data set and in the next lectures when we actually cover classification
we'll use a real data set for that.
But right now I still want to do a gradual progression from the last lecture.
So we'll create our own data set.
So I'm going to say linearly spaced from one Sezer point zero to 10.
And instead of just 10 points we're now going to do a million points.
So this is a huge dataset.
So we're not going to be all to do exactly what we did before.
And then I'm also going to add some noise to it just like we did last time.
So when I say noise is random random and and we need to pass in length with data.
So you know how many noise points to have.
So if I take a look at my x data it's essentially just these evenly spaced values and see there's a
million of them.
So the step size is really small.
It's like POINT ZERO 0 or users are one step size and then if I take a look at my noise at least the
shape of it I can see I essentially have a million random points from this normal distribution.
So just a bunch of random points that I'm going to add onto that.
Let's go ahead and create those.
So I will have the following function.
My line is going to be modeled by Y is equal to a mix plus B.
And I'm going to set B equal to 5 for this model and then I'm also going to add in some noise.
So I'm going to add in the noise levels.
So let's actually do this.
We'll say that Y true.
Is equal to choose a slope of 0.5 and then I'm going to multiply that by my X data.
And then I'm going to do plus five here.
So I have m equal to zero point five and that's something that we're going to try to figure out using
our model and then I'm also going to have be equal to plus five.
And to make it a little harder for our model I'm going to put in some noise here.
So now we have our y true values.
Again just following week X plus B we're slope is 0.5.
Our intercept value is 5 and I've added some noise to it.
So it's not just a perfectly fitted line.
Now it's actually create this data and I get these panderers to kind of concatenate some stuff together
and also make plotting a little easier.
So I will say My data is equal to and it won't say PD that concat which is short for concatenate and
we'll see how we use that in a second.
But before we do that over here I'm going to create a data frame.
So let's first make our data Frank so say X the f is equal to the data frame and the data is going to
be equal to my x data and the columns are just going to be equal to x data.
So there's my X data frame and then I'm going to also create my y data frame so of say white is equal
to PD data frame data as you may have guessed is equal to white true and the columns are going to be
equal to.
Let's just say why.
All right so I have my two data frames and if I check them out right now I can say x d.
Let's just check the head of that data frame the first five rows.
So there's my X data.
I can see it's going along very slowly.
Step size.
And then if I take a look at why if there are my values and you can see here the noise has definitely
been added in there.
Let's go ahead and concatenate these two so that I have these two columns together.
So the way you concatenate two data frames is quite simple.
Just say PD that Concat.
And then I'm going to pass in a list of the data frames I want to concatenate together.
So we have white F and then I also want to do X data.
So let's actually do X for so x the f y d.
And I want to concatenate them along x is equal to 1 because I want to do it along the columns.
So as the second problem here I will say x is equal to 1.
If I didn't have that access argument it would kind of stack them like pancakes if that makes sense.
And if I take a look at my data there it is x and y.
So a lot of that there let's just get the head of it.
So the reason I did that is because it's going to make it a lot easier to actually plot this out.
If I were to try to say my data dot plot that's going to take a really long time and it may actually
cause the kernel to crash because it's going to try to plot a million points instead of just plot a
small sample of that and what we can do that is really easy with a Pandurs data frame which is kind
of whole point that all I need to say is my data sample and equals let's say 250 and then that's going
to return back 250 random samples you can see here by the index that these are just random samples of
the data frame.
So here you have 250 random samples.
This is a small enough thing that I can plot out.
So now I'm going to call plot off this and I'm going to say that the kind of plot I want is a scatter
plot and let's say x is equal to x data and Y is equal to Y.
So now let's run that.
And here's my plot so I can see here my data is going from zero to 10 and the x axis also from 0 to
around 11 ish on the y true label and that's because we added in some noise and some of these points.
So you can see here definitely a linear trend and you can see that we've added some points off of that
line.
So the true line right here number y true is defined as a slope of 0.5 multiplied by the x data.
The Intercept is at five.
So if we scroll down here we can see that it would intercept around 5 if there's kind of a linear fit
here.
And then there's some noise up and down off of that.
So we want tensor float to try to fit a line here.
And we should see it kind of go very close to five as the intercept and have a slope of 0.5.
Let's go ahead and see how much flow can make this happen.
The first thing we have to realize is that a million points is a huge amount of points to pass it at
once.
And a lot of times when you're dealing with deep learning and just neural networks in general you're
going to have humongous data sets because the more data the better usually for training a lot of these
complex models.
But the problem is you can't just feed in a million points into your neural network at once.
So you do instead is you create batches of data you feed in batches of the data for training batch by
batch.
Let's go ahead and show you how to do that.
So I'm going to say my batch size create a variable is equal to 8.
So going to grab 8 points at a time and you can also change this around so maybe 10 points of a time
it'll points at a time.
There's no true right or wrong answer for batch sizes certain batch sizes really depend on your data.
Obviously if I only had 8 data points and patches would it really make sense if I have you know a trillion
data points maybe do larger batches.
Otherwise you'll be waiting all day and you won't use all your data.
So right now batch size 8 that's fine.
And we're going to create our variable just like we did last time.
So that's the slope remember.
And let's go ahead and just started off as a 0.5 and we'll say B is equal to T.F. variable.
And that's going to be one point 1.0.
Let's actually make these random numbers again just so we show that the network is actually working.
So I'll say any random rant and rant and then give me two of these guys.
OK so there are my two random numbers.
We're going to grab these and insert them the Rigaud and we'll grab this one as well and insert that.
OK.
So now I have my two round numbers we could have also initiated that as negative.
Not a big deal.
You can see here I'm choosing just two random numbers to initiate my slope and my intercept just like
I did in the last lecture.
So how many variables here.
Now let's create our placeholders.
And now we're going to have two placeholders one for the X and one for the Y so I have my X placeholder
T.F. placeholder and it should be a 32 bit flow.
And the size we're just going to say batch size.
So we're going to fit it in in batches so feet in eight points at a time and it's going to be the exact
same thing for the White ph.
So I can actually just copy and paste this here.
OK.
So I want you to kind of get used to this workflow of first creating the variables then creating the
placeholders then the next thing to do is actually define our graph.
In other words the actual operations that are taking place.
So what are we trying to do here.
Remember we're trying to build a Y model that models out that y equals x plus B.
So I have m as my placeholder I'm going to multiply it by or excuse me I have as my variable then I'm
trying to adjust number.
That's kind of a weight slope that you're trying to adjust.
And I have X as my placeholder that's going to be fed in data through a feed dictionary and then I'm
going to say plus be in another variable.
So right now my model is right here Y model and this is essentially my Grath that I'm trying to compute.
Then we need a last function and we're going to use some T.F. tools to kind of make this into one nice
one liner.
So we have to reduce some and say T.F. square of white placeholder.
Remember that is the true white value subtracts our actual prediction.
Whoops Y model Y underscore model.
OK there we go.
So this is our last function again.
Essentially the same thing we did last time except now I'm using T.F. Square for these kind of convenience
functions here.
Now I could also sort of s.c.s square something like Asterix Asterix too but to kind of match up in
the documentation.
It's nice to use these tensor flow optimize function calls.
Up next once we ever lost function it's time for the optimizer.
So let's put it in.
We're going to say optimizer is equal to T.F. train and we're going to use the same thing we did last
time which is call a gradient descent optimizer.
Later on we'll discover other optimizers.
But we're going to set a learning rate and let's go ahead and just set it to zero point zero or 1 and
then we actually want to tell the optimizer what to minimize and make sure I put this one in there so
I don't get any spelling errors and they'll say optimizer minimize the error we just made
OK.
So I have done the key steps here created my variables create in my placeholders define my graph essentially
defining the operations I've defined my last function here.
And then I have my optimizer which is trained to use gradient descent to minimize that loss function
or that error.
Now let's go ahead and create our in its variable for initializing the variable so I'll say it is equal
to T.F. global variables initialiser and let's run the session.
So we're going to do the following we'll say with T.F. session as s s s.
First thing need to do is run that in it.
So actually initialises those variables and then now I have to decide how many batches I'm actually
going to run through this.
So let's do 1000 batches.
See we'll see kind of play around with this.
You can play around with this number right here batches and this number right here that size.
So I'm going to run this through 8000 samples and see if that's enough for it to fit a nice linear fit
here.
And it really should be enough because we're not adding that much noise.
And even with kind of our eyeballs we can see here that there's clearly a linear trend.
So the models should be able to pick it up quite clearly even of 8000 samples.
It should be enough.
We don't need to feed it in a million samples although we could get you know maybe overfit toward trained
data but we'll discuss that later.
We'll say for I in range batches are going to send the thousand batches in then we'll do the following.
We'll say some random index is equal to any random thought Rand I.A. length of X data the size is to
that size and that I'm going to create my feet dictionary.
So that's going to be X placeholder.
I'm going to send x data Rand I.
Well say why placeholder amble to y true random index and then filing a say session run train where
I find the feed dictionary
as feet OK before we actually execute this cell and get the results back.
I want to go line by line what's actually happening here.
First thing we need to realize is I'm going to feed in 1000 batches of data where each batch is a corresponding
data points where we have an x data points and the y label.
Remember this is supervised learning to make sure that these batches are useful.
I don't want to just send eight by eight by eight.
Instead what I want to do is grab a random data points from my dataset.
The way I can assure that is by creating this variable right here and the reason it's called Rande underscore
A&amp;E is because this is going to correspond to a random index.
So I'm going to use that random Rand integer number that just returns a random integer and grab a random
integer from 0 up to the length of X data and kind of a shorthand you can just pasand length of X data
and then I want to make sure I grab 8 of those and those are going to be my index points.
Then I'm going to use those random index points past them into my X data and the corresponding y true.
And now I have my feed dictionary.
Then I run that into this training optimizer.
And there you have it.
So that's the reason of these two lines right here.
This random index actually chooses the 8 index points that are going to be part of that random batch.
So you want to make sure that these matches are basically just a batch size number of random points
from your data.
So we're going to train this model on thousand data points and hopefully that should be enough for a
good fit.
So once that is done I'm going to grab the actual predicted a model M and model B So that's the slope
and the intercept.
And when I say session run and go ahead and grab those placeholders so am and be OK.
Let's run this should be relatively fast depending on your computer.
I'm running this on a pretty fast computer so it may take a little bit of time for you if it's taking
too long.
Just reduce the number of batches.
Let's go ahead and check out our model.
But before I run this I want to show you what we initially started off member model M was a variable
that started off as a random 0.8 one the true slope should be pretty close to 0.5.
So if we come back up here the true slope I said was 0.5.
So let's see how he did down here.
I run a model M.
So there it goes 0.5 2.
And remember we added noise in there so that pretty much makes sense.
And again the bias that we initiated with should be fine.
The variable started with 0.1 7.
Let's see how it that will say Model B.
And there we go very close to five as well.
So essentially we're doing extremely well given that we added noise to the data set.
We can actually visualize these results quite easily.
I can just say y hat is equal to my x data times my model B or C ME model M Plus my model B and then
I'm going to say my data sample 250 points again.
Plot this out as a scatterplot where x is my X data column.
And why is my y column.
And then I'm also going to say Piazzi up plot x data versus Y hats.
And then let's make that a red line.
So I run this and I can see I have a pretty nice linear fit there.
And what it can also do is then kind of player of the batch sizes Let's see what happens if we run this
for 10000.
How much difference it makes.
Number we add noises data so it may not make a whole lot of difference.
You can see here now it's pretty much five.
Exactly.
Now we're getting a little closer to 0.5.
They're not going to be a huge difference in the actual plot.
Maybe you notice that a tiny bit at a drop.
But certainly we're getting a good linear model of it.
And remember we have noise toward data so we can expect that to be absolutely perfect.
All right.
So definitely go line by line on this.
Make sure you understand each step.
The main ideas are to.
Once you have your data create the variables create the placeholders define the operations in your graph
define some sort of error or last function.
Set up the optimizer.
Set up the trainer initialize those global variables and then if you have a huge data set you also want
to somehow feed the data in batches that are basically ran the batches from your large dataset.
And a lot of times that's the hard part actually figure out how to grab those batches of data as you'll
see later on in future lectures.
It's kind of challenging sometimes to work on a new dataset and fitted in batches.
All right that's it for this kind of Part One and Part Two we're going to jump right back into that
notebook where we left off here and show you how you could do this whole thing with the TFT estimator
API which is going to make your life a lot easier.
And we're also going to show you how to perform a train test split.
Technically we've been doing this kind of wrong.
We haven't been doing the train test blip so let's go ahead and do that as well.
Once we have the estimator API in place I'll see you at the next video.