Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to see how we can now solve the regression task with the tensor estimator API.
Now there are lots of other higher level API such as carious the senseful layers API tensor Flo's slim
etc..
Now we're going to cover the most popular ones later on in the Miscellaneous section of the course.
We'll usually deal with either a pure tensor flow or this estimator API just here in the beginning to
kind of get you slowly ranking up on your intenser flow skills.
But right now let's quickly describe how to use the estimator API.
So the T.F. estimator API actually has several model types to choose from going to quickly show you
the various options.
So here are the estimators types.
There's first just the classic linear classifier and it just constructs a linear classification model.
And there's also a linear regressors which constructs a linear regression model.
Things that we've seen in the past then there's also the densely connected neural network classifier
which constructs a neural network classification model and then there's also the DNN regressors which
is densely connected neural network regress model.
So before we had these classic linear classification and linear regression methods now we can use neural
network classification models and there's slight differences in how you can use these two which will
cover later on when we actually show the examples of the way the feature columns have to be given to
the estimator object.
And then besides those there's actually combine versions.
So there's DNN will in your combine classifier and it just constructs a neural network.
And when you combine classification model and similarly there's the same thing for the regress or you
don't have to worry about memorizing.
Right now we'll walk you through it very slowly and again we'll cover it in more detail than that miscellaneous
section.
So in general the format to use these estimator API is we do the following.
We first the final list of feature columns and the feature columns.
It's actually a special estimator data type.
So you end up doing is you can either define just a general feature column and then pass that into a
list or later on we're going to see that the estimator API actually has a lot of built in tools to help
you deal with things like categorical features and not having to worry about making dummy variables
out of them.
So the final list of feature columns are typical example right now it's going to be really simple.
So you're basically just going to see us make that estimator feature columns API call but later on we'll
see more complicated examples and we'll see how the customary path can really help you with that.
So once you have the final list of feature columns what you end up doing is you create the estimator
model and then after you do that you go ahead and create a data input function.
And that's just another convenience.
The major API has for you the data input function is basically an input function that either takes in
your data as a null array or there's a separate data input function for Pandurs data frames.
So if you like working pie you can stick a pie if you prefer Pancho's.
You can stick with pand those is just two different calls depending on what kind of format your data
is in.
Then once you've done that it almost works like if you're familiar of sikat learn it works like one
of their.
Machine learning model objects So basically once you have your estimator model and you pass in the feature
columns you call train to train the model.
You can call it evaluate it to evaluate it against some test data that you already know the labels for
and then you can also separately call predict.
So maybe you have some test data that you don't know the correct labels for and you just want to predict
what you think the labels could be called a predict method.
So you have to train a method evaluate method and predict method all the estimate or object.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.
Keep in mind this is a really simple example so it may not be the best use case for the estimator API
just because it really only has one feature later on for the other examples of regression and classification
that we'll see later on in the section.
You'll see the estimate API is a lot more useful here.
OK let's start off by creating that feature.
COLLINS We were discussing earlier I'll head over to the notebook now for underscore column and then
Dot again you can see that there's different columns so you can basically apply two.
And we're going to show a lot more examples of this in our classification walk through our code along.
So right now I'm going to kind of wave my hand over this part but keep in mind we will take a much deeper
dive into this feature column but I'm going to say T.F. feature column Gnumeric column because we do
have a numeric column value of x data and then if you do shift tab here it needs a key and a shape so
I'll say the key is to string x and the shape.
Remember we just have essentially one dimension here so just say shape is 1.
And then this whole thing needs to go into a list.
So we actually just have one feature here so we have all the feature columns essentially just a list
of a single item here a single feature column and it's a numeric column.
So kind of keep this in mind for the classification code along.
We're going to walk through a realistic example that has many more columns and what we're showing here.
OK so we have our feature set up.
Then we set up our estimator and to do that.
This is basically the main part of the API say T.F. dot estimator dot and then we're going to do a linear
regress or so there's a linear classifier and if you actually go back here you can see that there's
various T.F. estimators There's also a dense near on that were classifier and that's neural network
aggressor.
We'll talk about those later on but for now we have a simple regressors.
So we're going to say T.F. the estimator that linear aggressor and then we need to tell it where are
the feature columns.
So it has a parameter called feature columns.
And then you pass in that list of feature columns that you created.
And again we're going to see much more complicated examples where we have more than just one feature
column OK.
Then you should see kind of a bunch of warnings blah blah.
But don't worry about that.
It's just basically information.
So estimator has been created and this kind of works basically like a psychic learn as the mater if
you've used those before.
But I also want to show you how did that train split you've got over it before.
So let's actually implement it now.
We'll say from S-K learn the model underscore selection import train test split and then if we say train
test play here I'm going to do the following or say that X train and then X event or X tests.
Really depends what we want to call it and then why train and then we have y evil or white test is equal
to train tests.
And then I'm going to pass in my X data and then I'm going to pass on the true values for that.
And let's go ahead and say my test size is equal to 0.3.
And then let's also give it a random states of ones or want in case you kind of want to follow along.
All right.
So now I've done my train split.
Let's confirm that I kind of check these out.
So if I take a look at my training data.
I want to actually print out the shape of this trick.
So check out the shape and I have 700000 points that make sense.
My training point should be 70 percent of my data and 70 percent of a million is 700000.
Let's go ahead and check the same thing for my x evil.
So say X eveil shape and that's 300000 and you'll see the same things for the White train and why eveil
belts go ahead and set up the estimator inputs.
So S-meter inputs a little bit of this funky thing but basically you need to have an input function
that kind of acts like your feed dictionary and batch size indicator all at once.
So we show you how to do that right now.
You're going to say inputs underscore if you are see.
So just the variable name.
Then you're going to call T.F. estimator that inputs and then right now we're going to be inputting
from a null PI array.
So we're going to say no PI inputs a fan but if you also hit tab here you'll notice there's an option
for a pair of those data input.
So what's nice about this T.F. the estimator API.
It can take inputs from both NUMP pie and Pandurs.
Right now we're dealing with some pie in the future.
We'll see it coatl example with a panda state of free.
The next step to passen is basically the x and y.
So we're going to do here is essentially pasan a dictionary here.
So remember appear if we come back we said that this feature column has this key X.
So we're going to pass in the same key X there and then say X underscore train.
So there'll be X data and then we're also going to use y train and then let's go ahead and give it a
batch size so what you can see we're kind of doing all these steps though we there are multiple lines
in one single input function with the estimator API.
We can say batch size 8 or 4 you can kind of play around with that.
And here I'm just going to say a couple of more arguments.
Number of e POCs is equal to none.
And then I'm also going to say shuffle is equal to true.
All right.
So I have my PI input function ready to go and then I'm going to do a really similar thing here.
I'm going to copy and paste this and then I'm going to create two more input functions later on there
we're going to use for evaluation.
So I'm going to basically rename this to train and put phunk and then set that equal to the same thing
here.
Let me zoom in or zoom out one level so we can kind of see a little bit more of all this.
So there's my input function.
There's my original one.
And now I have one almost the exact copy called Train funk except here I'm going to say that the number
epochs.
I want it to be trained on is specifically 1000.
And I also want to shuffle equal to false OK.
There we go.
And the reason I have a shuffle equals false here for this train is because I'm going to be using this
train input function for evaluation against a test input function.
So I'm actually going to copy this whole thing again.
Do shift enter.
Paste it but instead of being trained it's going to be tested and also it's going to be called evolves.
Kind of follow the same naming convention we have earlier.
And instead of X train this will be X evil and instead of Y train that will be y Ebell
OK perfect.
So we have these three input functions.
Our first step is to train the estimator.
So the way we do that is we say estimator that train and then you just pasand the input function that
you just created.
So say input phunk.
Now for this very first one we didn't actually specify the number of epoxy or steps we want it to run.
So we're going to do that here in the train so you can say input func and you can say steps.
So that's how we're going to have here.
We'll say run it for 1000 steps.
So we're going to run that.
Ill save it and then you should eventually see the steps running gives you information.
Mary these are errors essentially just reporting back what the final last step is et cetera slashed
the loss at each of these steps.
So you can see here we start with a huge loss 4:51 And very quickly we begin to die down.
It may come up and down as you continue training can see here kind of oscillates a little bit between
6 and 11 but eventually we get some sort of convergence to a loss here on our training set.
So we're able to train the estimator.
Now it's time to actually get some evaluation metrics and the estimator API also has nice methods or
convenience methods for that.
So I will zoom in on my time here so we can see that.
Let's go to get the metrics on the training data the way I'm going to do that is I will say train underscore
metrics and then off of this estimator object instead of saying like that up here train I'm going to
say evaluates and then I'm going to specify that my input function is now that train input function
and I'll say steps is equal to 1000.
So the reason I want this train input function instead of this input function is because since I'm using
this to evaluate I specifically don't want to shuffle this I want to make sure everything's in the same
order.
That way I can do the evaluation correctly and see how it performs against the true label.
So we're going to run that get those train metrics.
So depending on your computer this may take a little bit of time.
You should end up with some kind of huge output here.
And if this output is bothering you you can always click here on cell and say current output.
Clear your results will still exist but it will clear the output.
So I'll go ahead and run that again and keep the output there and then scroll down a little bit.
I have a pretty fast computer so keep that in mind.
Your results may not be as fast as mine next what we're going to do is the exact same thing will say
eveil metrics.
Essentially our test metrics so say estimator evaluates and then will say input function is equal to
my evil input function.
And then when you say steps as equal to 1000 here.
Let's run that again.
You kind of see this huge output and once that's done running what we can do is compare the results
on the evaluation of our training data in our test data.
We're going to scroll down here in order to do that.
And what we're going to do is we're going to say Prince the train metrics so that evaluation method
we just did or that evaluate method we just did has a nice output which is essentially like a dictionary
Sarno and say training data metrics.
Let's run that.
And so we can see our loss.
The average loss and then Globalstar which was something to find earlier.
Now that I understand my training data metrics I want to compare that to my tests or evaluation set
metrics.
So I will do the exact same thing here except I will print out evil metrics and then say print's evil
And this is a really nice way to check if your model is overfitting to your training data.
A good indicator of your model being overfit to your training data is when you have a really low loss
on your training data but a really high loss on your evil data.
We want these to be basically as close as possible to each other.
That doesn't mean we want them both to be high.
We want them both to be low hopefully but a good sign that you're not overfitting is that your training
data loss is pretty similar to your test data loss.
You should always expect your evaluation cost to perform slightly worse than your training data.
Again this really depends on your data.
Uranium splits how much data you gave the training versus how much gave to test revaluation etc..
Lots of specific factors for your specific situation but in general you kind of want these to be relatively
similar and not way off from each other if you're training data metrics are much much better than your
evaluation or test data metrics that you're probably overfitting to your training data.
OK so we're almost done here except a really common question where we're creating models is the question
well how do I predict new values.
The metrics are nice but let's say actually wanted to play this thing.
How do we get those new values those predicted values well that show you are going to create a new input
function called input Ethen predict and it's going to be T.F. estimator inputs again a PI input function
and I'm going to pass in test or new data here.
So what does that actually mean.
Well let's say I have some new data of X Remember we're doing just a simple linear regression.
So I'm going to say my brand new data to predict.
So given some x value what is its corresponding y label according to your model.
So we're going to say my brand new data is P Lynde's space 0 10 10 points here.
So these are 10 points that my model has never seen before and they're conveniently linearly spaced
again you kind of play around these values here but this essentially brand new data the model has never
really seen these data points before.
In a sense it kind of has depending on how you created data.
But we're going to pretend like it's never seen before.
So we have our input function to predict and we're going to pass that in as X here.
Our brand new data so brand new data and then we're also going to do here is say shuffle is false so
say shuffle is equal to false.
We'll run that.
So now we have an input function to predict.
So we're going to say estimator and instead of saying train or evaluate the final method I want to show
you is the Predict method where you just pass in that input function predicts.
So the difference between this T.F. estimator input that we created versus the previous ones is here
I'm passing brand new data that I want to predict for.
So let's go ahead and run this.
And you'll notice it's a generator object which means if I actually want to see the results I need to
either iterate through this or conveniently I can cast that to a list and then I'll see a list of all
the predictions and here we have it.
It basically returns a list of dictionaries where the key is predictions and we have some sort of array
value as well as the data type that it is.
So let's actually kind of plot these out and see how we did.
So what we could do is say we'll say predictions is equal to an empty list Scalzo be an array and then
I'm going to say for pred in estimator predict actually I'm going to copy and paste from here.
So basically in that list so for prediction created by this generator objects I'm going to say predictions
and I'm going to append x.
Whoops.
Fred predictions.
The reason I'm doing this append operation here is because remember each of these items is a dictionary.
So in calling the predictions key which is going to return that array value it predicted for it and
then I'm going to run that.
And then we should be able to see a nice list of predictions.
So great.
There is my array Let's actually plot these out and see how we did.
So I will say my data are going to sample an equal to 250 here.
And let's go in and do a random scatter plot again like we did last time.
So scatter where x is equal to x data and Y is equal to y so remember those are our samples here.
And let's do a plot based off of our predictions.
So I'm going to say N.P. when space actually I could just pass in our brand new data that we have so
that brand new data plotted out our predictions and then let's make it a red line and you can see we
have kind of the same linear fit we predicted last time.
Now we can even do the points themselves.
So these are the points I predicted according to my model you could see here is essentially falling
that Weikel said it's supposed be that we did earlier.
So that is how you use the S-meter object.
Let's quickly do a review of everything we just did.
And if it's still a little fuzzy to you don't worry we're going to do a classification example that
uses a T.F. estimator API.
And I think that's going to make it a lot clearer.
This was pretty confusing to me personally when I first saw it but once I went through a couple of examples
it became a lot clearer and the workflow became really clear.
So we won't be using the estimator API beyond this section.
Not really.
Said We're going to be using kind of the more thorough way with the placeholders the variables etc..
But I do want you to be aware in case you ever plan to use tensor flow for simpler tasks such as regression
classification.
The S-meter API is really useful here.
So really quick review we have to create the list of feature columns and every item in this list does
a special feature called Call where either you have a numeric column.
Maybe you have a categorical column and we'll show you how to create those later and then you provide
it with a key as well as a shape.
Then you actually create your estimator later on we'll show you how to do more complicated estimators
such as a dense neural network classifier or aggressor.
Then we do a train test split.
You should really be doing this regardless of using T.F. estimator or not.
Then we actually create some input functions.
I create an input function based on my training data.
Then I create two more input functions one for my training data one for my test data and the main difference
there is I'm telling it not to shuffle it that way my evaluations are an order then I train the data
on that first input function based off the training data.
Once that's done I can evaluate my training data metrics.
I can also evaluate my eveil metrics which is basically going to calculate the loss function for me.
So then it reports back the last this is a nice way to check for overfitting if I ever want to predict
off of New data points I can just create a new input function for prediction where I passen the data
values I want to predict for.
And then I can say shuffle is equal to false then I call a scimitar that predict which remember is a
generator object seen in either case as a list or if you want just iterate through it and then append
the new results and then we can plot them out to a histogram whatever you really want to do.
OK.
Put those interesting to you.
Again if you're a little fuzzy on this don't worry the classification examples going to clear up even
further.
I'll see you there.