Welcome everyone to the tensor flow classification example code along lecture in this lecture we're
going to be working in a real data set.
Previously we've been generating data sets.
Now we're actually going to show you how to work for real data set and we're going to be using the T.F.
estimator API discovery a little bit more and we'll also show you how to deal with categorical and continuous
features columns.
A lot of real life data sets aren't just going to have pure continuous numerical features that may have
categorical features.
So we're going to show you how to do all of those.
The TAF S-meter API and then will also show you how you can use the S-meter API to switch models between
like a linear classifier to a dense neural net classifier.
OK let's get started and hop over to Jupiter notebook.
OK the first thing I'm going to do here is actually get our data and I'm going to use panderers to do
that.
So let's say import panels as PD and I will create a data free and called diabetes and is going to read
in this provided see as we file for you which is under the tents full of basic's folder and you can
choose tab to autocomplete that.
And then if we check out the actual diabetes data frame head lips diabetes.
There we go.
I can see that there's various features such as number of times pregnant glucose concentration blood
pressure triceps insulin a body mass index pedigree the age of the person the class where one is whether
or not they have diabetes or one is if they do have diabetes 0 if they do not.
And then there's also this categorical column called group I actually added this column myself manually.
It's basically a meaningless column.
But the reason I added it in there was to show you how to deal with a feature column that's just a categorical
string.
And then we'll also do something a little special with age.
The rest of this are basically just continuous numerical values that we've seen before in the past so
we have various features and we're trying to predict this class.
This is a binary classification problem.
And the first thing you want to do is clean the data.
Remember I said a lot of times we need to normalize our data.
So let's walk through how we would do that for a real data set.
First thing to do is say diabetes not columns and get a list of the columns returned and then I'm going
to say calls to Norm and will create a list of the columns to normalize.
And the reason I have diabetes our columns here is that way I can just copy and paste this for convenience
and then put it in there and I don't want to normalize class because that is my feet or label column
that I'm trying to predict group.
I can't normalize that.
Those are strings and then age.
We're going to convert age to a categorical column as an example.
So I'm also going to remove that as well.
OK.
So those are my Combes to normalize and I'm going to show you how to normalize them with panderers.
We could also use cycle learns pre-processing as we've done in the past.
But I want to show you a little trick with Pancho's that may save you some time in your own data sets.
So we passing the columns to normalize into diabetes and then I'm going to set that equal to diabetes
and then passen columns to normalize and then what I will do is I'm going to apply a custom function
or it custom land expression.
So we'll say off of that list of columns.
Say Dot.
Apply and then I'm going to say lambda X and then anguishes the following will say X minus the minimum
value.
Then I will divide that by the maximum value of X minus the minimum value of x OK and that should normalize
the columns so let's see that in action.
So take the hand column again and now I can see a number of times pregnant glucose concentration BMI
etc. those are now all normalized.
So you can use this quick command.
It's a little more convenient for pandas because it's essentially just a nice one liner and you don't
really have to import anything.
And the mathematics essentially works out the same.
OK.
Now let's go ahead and create our feature columns.
Remember we're using the estimator API.
We need to pass in a list of those feature column objects.
So the first thing to do.
Zoom back in here.
Is Important sensor flows we're going to be using it say importance as T.F. And let's go out and grab
those columns again so diabetes columns and number pregnant glucose concentration et cetera.
And if you're wondering what these columns actually physically represent you can go ahead and check
out the notebook provided there's the full description of the diabetes dataset there.
OK.
So we have various continuous features.
Basically everything except age class and group are the ones we're going to be working with.
And in fact age could be treated as a continuous feature column.
So we'll go ahead and do that for now.
Well we need to do is create feature column and numeric columns off of these.
So the way we can do that is we create a new variable for each column such as number of times pregnant
and we set that equal to T.F. feature column numeric column.
And then I'm going to pass in that key name or that column name so let's go in and grab that and then
pass it in.
So that's what we're going to do for the rest of these continuous feature columns.
And if you want you can just copy and paste these results from the notebook if you have a really large
dataset you probably want to try to figure out some way to assign these using a for loop.
But there we go.
They're just going to copy and paste that from the provided notes and essentially all we did for each
of these continuous columns is T.F. feature column that numeric column and then passed in the actual
name of the column.
All right.
So those are our continuous values.
Now any of the categorical features the non-continuous values.
There's two main ways you can do this.
One is using a vocabulary list and one is using a hash bucket.
Let's go ahead and show you both methods because both are going to be useful depending on the situation.
Third thing going to do is say assign group is equal to that's my variable is going to be using then
I say T.F. feature column and then instead of using numerical column I'm going to begin to type out
categorical column and notice here we have caterwaul column with hash.
But I tend to see vocabulary file and vocabulary list the main ones are going to be using are either
hash bucket or the vocab list.
Let's first show you the vocabulary list so I know that there's only four possible groups A B C and
D.
So what I can do is what I am defining my categorical column.
I will say passen the key which is just group.
So if I come back up here this column is group and I know there's only a b c and d available.
So then I pass an A list of possible categories that's going to be a b c and d.
And that's how you can create a categorical feature column using tensor flow with a vocab list.
Now the important thing to note here is you're not always going to have such a convenient grouping of
categorical columns.
So let's say you have a column that for whatever reason has all the countries in the world in it.
We you don't want to have to write out hundreds or tens of countries depending on how many categories
you have.
Instead what would be nice if you could automatically create that using some sort of hash bucketing
system.
And that's exactly what tensor flow provides for you.
So if you're ever in a situation where you maybe don't know all the groupings themselves or you just
have so many you don't want to type them out.
You can say T.F. feature call them categorical call them and you can use a hash bucket.
And the way this works is pretty similar.
You say group for the key but now instead of providing a list of the possible categories you just define
a hash bucket size.
And this is the maximum amount of groups that you will believe will be in that category column.
So for example I can pasand 10 here and that's going to be fine because there's only four.
So at most there's going to be 10.
And basically the effect of this line is tensor flows making something like this automatically for you
in the background based off how many categorical entries you expect so you can make this as large as
you want depending on how many categories you expect for it.
Now we're going to go ahead and use the vocab list.
Either way we really shouldn't see a difference so a hash tag that our commented out and now I want
to discuss converting a continuous column to a categorical column.
So we have age here right now as a continuous value.
But notice we specifically did not convert it or normalize it.
And that's because I'm going to use it to convert it to a categorical column.
Sometimes you get more information out of your data this way.
This is known as feature engineering.
So I'd say first try to visualize this well say map plot lived a pipe plot as Pulte and then also say
map plot lib.
In line so now let's go ahead and say diabetes grabber age column and plot out a histogram from it so
we can actually do this quite easily by just saying dohis and then let's say 20 bins in the sister room.
All right so this histogram basically shows you the distribution of the ages.
Most of these people are quite young in their 20s and maybe late 20s early 30s and then it kind of goes
down from there.
So maybe instead of treating this as a continuous value I can get these together maybe I can make some
boundaries for each decade so you can see here there's 20 30 30 to 40 etc..
So the way I can do that is again with tensor Flo's feature column methods.
So if I want to ever take a continuous value and bucket it into categories I can say whatever the variable
name there is and then say a feature column and I can say but ghettoised the column in which case I
passen the continuous value feature.
So I already have this numeric column which has a continuous value I'm going to grab whatever variable
I called it.
In this case it's just age and then I'm going to pass it in here and then I'm going to provide one more
argument called boundaries which is a list of the buckets I want.
So I walked from 20 to 30 to 40 to 50 to 60 to 70 let's say to 80.
There we go.
So this is going to create buckets of values between 20 and 30.
Anything less than 20 between 30 and 40 50 60 60 70 etc. and then 80 and above.
So that's how you can convert a continuous numeric into a categorical column based off these booking
systems.
Now this doesn't always help you.
In fact it may make things worse depending on the situation.
So this is where your domain knowledge is going to come into play.
Now let's go ahead and put this all together and wanted to make a list of all my future columns.
And you don't just use tabs to complete this.
Help you out here.
Or you can just copy and paste this from the notes that we have just various ones got insulin.
I believe we have BMI.
We got one called Diabetes pedigree.
We got the assigned group one that we just made sign group let's go to continue here we also have the
age buckets that we made as well.
All right.
So now I have my list of all the feature columns which are these TFT feature columns.
Now it's time to perform a train test split.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So we'll say her my train test splits
we'll have our X data that's going to be equal to diabetes data frame and then I'm going to drop the
class label along the columns axis and if I take a look at x data it's just the features it no longer
has the class.
If you scroll Let's make this head so I don't scroll down here.
So if we skirl although it's that right we no longer see our class.
So this is just the data just the features.
And we're going to say that my labels is now equal to diabetes class.
And now if I take a look at labels it's just literally the labels themselves.
Once in suras OK now it's actually split up I'll say from a Skillern model selection import train test
split and then let's perform that train split will say train to split and I usually just like to copy
and paste this from the note so or from the documentation scroll all the way down here until you see
this nice little example line and then copy and paste this kind of save you some time.
All right so we have X train x test Y train Y test let's pass our features and our labels we can say
test size is equal to 30 percent not a big deal.
And if you want to make sure you get the exact same random splits I do so your random state to 1 1 run.
That and our ready to go.
OK.
We're going to stop this here since this basically concludes part 1 of classification where we fix the
data showed you how to do the feature columns in part 2.
We're actually going to create the input function create the models and then evaluate this I'll see
it there.