Welcome back everyone.
Now it's time to actually take what we did previously in the last lecture for data and apply it to creating
our model.
First thing we need to do is actually create an input function or create a variable called input underscore
funk so that equal to T.F. thought estimator that inputs and instead of using a PI input function we're
going to be using 8 Panda's input function because we have this in the form of Panas data frames.
So we're going to say our x is equal to x train and R R Y is equal to y train.
And then we can do things like set the batch size so it's fitted in batches of 10 at a time and then
we can see that the number of the pox Let's go and just say a thousand and then will say shuffle is
equal to true OK.
Now it's time to create our model will say T.F. estimator and will start off of a linear classifier
later on we'll do a neural network classifier and then we're going to say feature columns is equal to
that feat calls column that we are list that we made earlier and then we also supply the number of classes.
So by default it's 2.
But in case you ever doing more than that you can change that number.
But for analysis binary classification classifications we'll say number classes too.
And once you run that you should see an output basically telling you the configuration of the model.
Now all you do is train that model.
So we'll say model train and we'll say input function is equal to that input function we just created
and it's good and train for 1000 steps run that and you should see eventually some output here.
As your models being trained and the pinning of how fast your computer uses may be a little slower or
a little faster than what you see here.
All right.
So coming back down let's time to evaluate our model so we need an evaluation function will see evil
underscore and put underscore phunk is equal to T.F. estimator dot and put stop Pandurs funk and we'll
do the following.
We'll say x is equal to now say x.
Test don't say Y is equal to Y test we'll do the same batch size.
Set it to turn and we're going to run this once we'll say number of epoxies equal to 1 which is also
the default.
And let's make sure we have Comus here.
Comma comma and then finally we'll say shuffle is equal to false because we want to make sure that we're
evaluating this in the same order.
So they will see results is equal to model evaluates and say evil and put phunk run that.
And then we should be able to see the results
once we evaluate this we should be able to see our actual accuracy in area under the curve.
So that would be something like in Orosi curve which we can do for binary classification you can see
your accuracy baseline Silex we're getting about 74 percent accuracy it's not so bad.
Let's go ahead and practice getting some predictions off of this.
So to get predictions who saying pred and put funk and T.F. estimator input X dots inputs Pandurs input
function.
And in this case you would say x is equal to whatever new data you had in.
So we don't actually have any new data within it create a hold out data set.
We're just going to head and passing the test data again we'll see batch size is equal to 10.
Now I'm not passing any y value because technically if we want to predict something we won't really
know the y value for it otherwise to be no point in predicting it.
That's an evaluation not a prediction.
I will say in the report six to one and then we'll say shuffle is equal to false.
Ok so now we have our Pred.
So let's go out and create some predictions here will say model predict and then we're going to pass
in that prediction function.
So model that predicts pass and Pred input function let that happen.
And remember predictions is going to be a generator.
So we want we can pass it in as a list.
Let's go in and say that as my pride or my predictions and then if I check out my pred I can see here
I essentially have a list of dictionaries where it actually reports back the classes it predicted and
also the probabilities for each class.
You can see here on the first one it was split pretty evenly between the two classes.
But just by a smidge point 0 1 percent he went ahead and classified it as one as having diabetes according
to its own prediction.
All right so that was for a linear classifier we noticed the linear clus for overall got 74 percent
accuracy.
We showed you how to do predictions on new data that it hasn't seen before.
Essentially the same thing is evil except you don't provide it why.
Because that wouldn't make sense for prediction.
Let's go out and show you now how to do it dense neural network classifier.
So say DNN model is equal to T.F. estimator.
And I'm going to say that's neural network classifier and I will say it in units unhidden units basically
defines Well how many neurons you want and how many layers.
So you provide a list of neurons per layer.
So if I want three layers with 10 year on each I say 10 common 10 commet 10.
So that's 10 year olds and it's densely connected meaning every neuron is connected to every other neuron
in the next layer and then we just pass in the feature columns that we defined earlier.
So a feature column is equal to feet calls.
And then when you specify the number of classes which again is just to OK.
So we have our dense neural network classifier.
Unfortunately if we try to do the exact same thing we did before you'll get an error if you say the
model train and try to use the same input function.
So if I use input func and say steps is equal to a thousand you're going to get an error here.
And the reason because of that is you can check out the fooling in the stack overflow page in the notebook.
But basically if we have a feature column and we're trying to use this on a densely connected neural
network then what we did do is pass it into an embedding column.
So it's giving us trouble.
Are these categorical columns so he created so I'll show you how to do that.
Basically what you need to do is you say embedded group call is equal to T.F. feature column.
And then you need to say imbedding column and then passen the previous categorical column which is just
assigned group and then you give it they mention which was the number of groups so that was ABC the
xul say for their.
There we go.
So that's what you need to do if you end up defining your own column using a vocabulary list in the
past into this imbedding column.
And again that's only for those densely neural networks.
Once we have them that we need to reset our feature columns.
So you say feek calls is equal to and a scroll up and grab the last thing we did.
We don't need to rewrite all that.
So come up all the way back here are just copying pieces from the notes.
But here we have our feature columns.
So I'm going to copy that scroll back down and paste it here.
But now I'm going to replace my group feature.
So remember that was a group with the embedded group call.
So copy that and then replace that here.
There we go put that all zoom out a little bit so you can see it and you can always copy and paste this
from the notes as well.
So let's try this again.
I'm going to define my input function as T.F. estimator inputs panel's input function.
Again I'm going to do X train y train.
I'll say it that size 10 number of Eat pocks is going to be a thousand Nells say shuffle is equal to
true.
So have that input function again three days ago in Altes create our model so it's NTFS the matre that
see neural network hidden units go with 10 10 10 and these are values you can play around with.
Obviously the more neurons and more hidden units as we kind of saw in the tents for a playground the
longer it's going to take the train this thing they'll see a feature of school to see calls and then
number classes is equal to two run that.
And let's see if we can train and also say the N-N model school down here.
We can see it in effect zoom in again scroll down we say DNN model that train and the input phunk we're
going to train on is the one we just read the fine input phunk illustrated for a thousand steps.
OK so now looks like everything is running.
We're not getting any errors anymore due to that fix the imbedding column.
All right so it looks like you're finished training.
So let's evaluate it.
We're going to say again evil input funk T.F. estimator inputs hopefully starting to feel a little more
familiar now.
And those input function.
And then we pass and what we want.
So we want X test Y is equal to Y test pass in a batch size
we'll say the number of epoxies just one because it's an evaluation.
And we also want to make sure that shuffle is equal to Fox so that all that line run that will say the
model call evaluates on it.
So we passen evaluate input function.
And this is going to evaluate on the test data.
So it's going to run the model that we just train on our test data and then compare his predictions
to the actual true values here.
So run that evaluation and looks like we get almost the exact same accuracy as we got before.
So it looks like our densely connected neural networks is performing almost the same.
So we got let's see 74 on accuracy 82 under the curve.
To come back up here previously we got we scroll way back up here 74 and 80s is performing a little
better.
Let's see if we go crazy on the number of neurons and number of layers.
If we perform any better granted we may just end up overfitting So it may not be that helpful.
Let's say I believe we only have 10 features that's probably not going to be very helpful to create
more neurons but it's kind of see what happens.
Just for fun little run these again.
And see what happens when you get it.
So I'm going to jump forward in time to finish training.
All right so jumping forward in time.
Looks like I was not really able to squeeze much more actually out of that.
So hovering around 74 75 an area under the curve still 82 83.
So looks like Rupert is reaching the limits of what this data can do.
OK.
Hopefully that was useful to you and hopefully you got the chance to see how you can get a real data
CXXVI and use the T.F. estimator API to work with it.
So as a quick review you take in your data and then you normalize it at least the continuous numeric
columns you plan to use.
And then you go ahead and create your feature columns using feature column that numeric column.
And if you have categorical columns you use feature column that categorical column either with Yvo vocab
list or a Hash bucket.
Then you can go ahead and Bucha ties in the continuous columns you want to make categorical.
Then you create your list of feature columns do a train test split.
Also you can do a train test puts you on hold outset then you're going to go ahead and do is create
your input function depending if you're using Pandurs or not pi pass passing the training data choose
your batch size shuffle et cetera create your linear classifier.
Train it then you can't evaluate it.
And then if you want later on you can predict on your data.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.