Welcome everyone to the solution lecture for the free Russian exercise let's go to the Jupiter notebook
and code along with the solutions.
OK here we are at the notebook.
Let's go ahead and start off.
First thing I want to do is actually get the data.
So I'm going to import pandas as PD and I'm hitting alt enter there it's Create a couple of more cells
and I will read in the data so that housing is equal to PD ritziest we obviously can call the data frame
whatever you want.
And then we say how housing clean.
See the file read that in and we can check out the head of the data frame.
So I see here I have housing median age total rooms total bedrooms.
Population households et cetera.
Now we're going to go ahead and do is do the train test split.
So in order to do that it's come at this out and let's just describe here showing the school information
in case you're interested in that.
But we need to do the train to split.
So I want to grab all the features and then the white label.
So say the y value is equal to that housing data frame.
And I just want the median house value.
Remember that's what I'm trying to predict.
And let's grab the rest of those features.
So we'll say X data is equal to housing drop and then I'm going to drop the median house value column
and remembered to do that along X equal to 1 then we're going to say from Let's zoom in one more level
here so we can see this clearly from S-K learn model selection.
Import train split run that then train to split.
Go ahead and do shift enter there which is a nice little convenient way of scrolling down through the
docstring until you find this line so you can easily just copy and paste it here.
All right so now I have X train x test Y train Y test at test size to be 30 percent and then we want
to make sure this x is x data and this Y is why y.
And if I scroll over to the right I always say random stay as one to one because I always remember that.
But again that doesn't really matter here.
You can set it to whatever you want.
Your results just may be a little different than mine.
Up next we want to scale the feature data.
So we're going to use as Kaylor and pre-processing in order to create minimax scalar for saying it is
actually important.
So from a scalar and pre-processing import minimax scalar that I'm going to say scalar is equal to an
instance of minimax scalar.
And then we want to fit our scalar.
And we're only going to fit it on the training data otherwise it would kind of be cheating because we
want to assume that we have prior knowledge of test sets.
So we fit onto the training data and then whoops we'll say X train.
Is that equal to Peetie data frame.
And I'm going to have the data here be equal to scalar transform extreme.
And I'm doing this all in one line once that you could kind of separate this out to multiple steps than
the columns here.
This puts us on a new line is going to be called to X train columns and then the index here is going
to be equal to x train dot index.
So this is just a way to basically reset X train to be the scaled version of the data because the fight
were to transform this just by itself.
So if I were to grab this line just by itself let me show you what would happen if I run just this line.
I get back a pie array.
But instead what I want is a panel data frame like I had appear of just the features.
So to make sure that happens I'm going to pass this array in as data to PD that data frame and then
to make sure the columns and the index are the same and with say column 0 to X train that columns and
index is equal to x train the index.
And if you wanted to you could call this X train something like scaled X train et cetera but for unmelted
kind of overwrite it with X train and then we're going to do the same thing for X test.
So we're only doing this for the features data frame and then we just copy and paste this here except
that a train.
Going to be test overhears well and then over here as well.
All right.
So we successfully split our data using a train to split and now the feature data is scaled as well.
So once we have that will scroll down and create the feature columns.
So we want to create the necessary feature columns.
So again I can do that easily just by saying housing columns to get a list of the columns themselves
then going to import tensor flow as T.F..
And then I want to create those feature columns.
So I'll just do one of them and then copy the rest from the solutions.
So if you want to get to the age column so that's the housing median age I'll say a variable called
Age is equal to T.F. feature column numeric column.
And then I'll pass in the list there.
So housing median age.
All right so that's one example you want to do that for the rest of them.
So you want it could set this up for a loop that's kind of looping through these columns and then setting
them up through some sort of variable dictionary but instead we're just going to do them all individually
by copying and pasting and then run that.
All right so we have a feature column and they also want to make sure to aggregate these all into some
sort of variable so of say feet calls for the feature columns is equal to age rooms bedrooms pop for
population household income.
All right so I have my list of feature columns where these are tense full of feature columns.
They're all continuous values and just using numeric column for all of them that I want to create an
input function for the estimator object.
Let's go ahead and do that say input func is equal to T.F. estimator inputs and I'm using panderers
as my input impiously used panderers input function and then I set X as equal to x train will say Y
is equal to y train and then I'll choose a batch size of 10 and let's say a number of POCs is equal
to 1000.
And you can play around with these values and we'll say shuffle is equal to true here because this is
our training function that we want to create the estimator model and we're going to use a dense neural
network Tresor you can go out and play around the hidden units.
I'm going to set it to be three layers of six neurons.
So say ATF estimator that's neural network repressor and I will say it in units and then we just pass
in a list here.
So I'm choosing six because the inputs I have are six features essentially.
Again there's no real right or wrong answer you can really play around with these units as much as you
want as we've seen in sensor flow playground.
But right now we'll keep it simple just three layers six units each and then I also need to pass in
the feature columns which we've already defined as fit calls so run that that should then create your
model and then you going to train the model for a thousand steps.
And then later you can come back to it and train it for more.
I'll go ahead and just say model train pass in our input functions or that was that input funk we created
and let's say steps that steps equal to just 20000 for it now since I it's a pretty fast computer so
while that's training we're also going to do is create a prediction.
So let that train let me scroll down.
I'll probably end up hopping forward here as it continues.
All right.
Jump forward in time.
My model is now finished training for 20000 steps on my computer.
That took about 30 seconds and I'm a pretty fast computer.
So we're going to do now it's create a prediction input function that I can use the Predict method with.
So let's go ahead and do that will say predict underscore input underscore phunk is equal to T.F. estimator
inputs and we're still using Pansy's input function that we're going to say x is equal to x test then
we'll say the batch size is equal to what we chose before which is 10.
Here I'm only using this for predict.
So I'm not going to have a Y value you'd use that for evaluation then we'll say number of the POCs since
I only want to run this one just to get one set of predictions I'll say one.
And then I want to make sure shuffle is equal to false because I'm using this for predictions.
I don't want the shuffling to occur.
So predict input function.
So let's get a prediction generator.
Remember the return generator objects will need to cast them to a list so we'll same model and then
we'll call that predict off of.
So we say that predict and then I'm going to passen that predict input function so that we have that
that predict generator and then we'll say predictions is equal to a list or cast that to a list.
There we go.
So now I ran that generator I have these predictions here.
So if I check those out let me insert a cell below so to insert itself below.
If I check our predictions it's essentially this list of dictionary items where we have a prediction
and then some sort of array value indicating the predicted housing price.
So now it's time to calculate the mean squared error.
There's different ways to do this.
You can use manual coding but as you learn metric metrics is really useful.
So I'll show you how to do that.
First off I'm going to make some final predictions here will say final Pretz is an empty list and I'll
say for Fred in the predictions list that I just showed you I'm going to say final Freda's and I'm going
to append this dictionary value.
So essentially just grabbing all this array information instead of having a list that dictionaries will
say Fred for the actions and we could have also done this with Philos. comprehension.
Will say from a scalar metrics import mean squared error.
And that's basically what this link takes you to if you go to click on it I'll take you to the documentation
for that.
But S-K learn has means square error built into it which means if you want root mean squared.
You just take the square root of that.
So if you take a look at it mean squared error takes.
It just takes in the true values and the predictive values.
So let's pass those in.
We know we have Y test wups we know we have y underscore it test.
And we also know we have our final predictions and then we want the square root of that.
So we'll say the power of 0.5.
We run that and we should get around 100000.
So that means or mean squirt air is around hundred thousand dollars.
If you take a look at the median price.
So if we come back here and take a look at some of this the school information of our dataset so let's
say housing.
Describe Let's transpose that and we run that if we take a look here median house value it looks like
the mean is around 200000.
So we're not doing super great for our model if our mean square error is 100000 So we're not really
doing quite a great fit here.
So something you may want to do is trade training for more steps maybe shoot this up to 100000 or try
editing your model more hidden units and we can also do is play around with a linear repressor not a
dense neural network regressors and see if that performs better.
But hopefully through this exercise we're able to understand the basics of the T.F. estimator API.
So the main goal of this exercise was not to actually create the best model ever but it was to understand
the general process using TFT estimator.
OK.
If you have any questions please feel free to post the Q&amp;A forms.
I'll see you at the next lecture.