Hello everyone and welcome to the tensor flow classification exercise and this lecture will have an
overview of the exercise notebook and what you need to do.
And then in the next lecture we'll have a CO-2 long walk through these solutions.
Let's hop over to the Jupiter notebook and explain the tasks here and at the classification exercise
Notebook.
We're going to be working on some California's census data and we'll be trying to use the various features
of an individual to predict what class income they belong in.
So as a classification task we'll try to predict that they make less than $50000 a year or more than
$50000 a year.
So basically two classes there less than or greater than 50000.
So we have various features of these individuals things like their age their educational level.
Now whether or not they're married how many hours per week they work etc..
Country of origin.
And a lot of these young voters are categorical.
And we also have continuous features here.
So we're going to be needing to use those numeric column and categorical column attributes of the feature
column that tensor S-meter API gives you.
So basically we have to do just follow the directions in bold if you ever get stuck.
You can go ahead and jump to the next lecture where we go through the solutions and if just going through
a code long lectures more your style you can just go ahead and skip this exercise go to the next lecture
and come along with me.
So the very first thing we do is read in the data of pandas.
You can check it out and you'll have to note that tensor flow won't be able to understand the actual
labels here.
So we're trying to predict income bracket column but it's actually listed as strings.
So what you need to do is convert this label column to zeros and ones instead of strings.
If your not super familiar of how to do that with Pandurs you can kind of just skip this part and take
a peek at the solutions.
But something to note here is that one of these labels are both of these labels actually have a little
space for the string code.
So here I am highlighting the space so that should help you out.
OK so it's just a little hint.
Again you may want to use Pancho's apply Google that SEO works.
Then once you've done that perform a train test split on the data.
Once you've done that create the feature columns for the estimator so taken of categorical columns versus
continuous values.
Remember that for categorical columns you can use either a vocabulary list or a Hash bucket.
I would definitely recommend using hash buckets because it's unlikely for you to know all the unique
values in a vocab list using a hash bucket.
Much easier than I want you to put all these variables into a single list with the variable name C underscore
calls for feature columns.
Then the next thing you need to do is create an input function so the batch size is up to you.
I use the batch size of 100 but make sure you do shuffle in this input function for training.
Then you create your model T.F. estimator.
Go ahead and create a linear classifier if you want.
You can use a densely connected neural network classifier that remember from the lectures for the categorical
features you need to create those embedded columns.
So since that's a little bit more work we'll go ahead and just use a linear classifier for this particular
problem then you're going to train your model try to train it on at least 5000 steps.
Again depending on your computer's speed you can lower the amount of steps there but your results won't
be as good.
Then continue scrolling down once you've trained the model.
It's time for evaluation.
So I want you to create another input function for prediction.
But remember the prediction input function only needs to supply the X test data and you want to keep
shuffler equal to false.
Then use the model predict method passing your input function they'll produce a generator of predictions
just as we did in the lecture.
Then transform it into a list each item in your list is essentially going to be a dictionary looking
like that.
So if you want to do is grab these class IDs right here.
Those are the predictions of what class it belongs to.
Then once you have that list you can go ahead and import classification report from.
As he learned that metrics and go ahead and google this if you're unsure of how to use it.
But basically once you import this classification report all you have to do is provide the prediction
values of the labels something like this.
And the real White House values which we already did in the train to split above and you'll have this
nice little classification report telling me the precision the recall and the score values as well as
how many points it has and support for each of these classes 0 and 1.
Okay that's it.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forms but definitely check out the solutions
lecture.
We're going to code out and explain every step.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.