Welcome everyone to the solution lecture for the tense flow classification exercise.
Let's go to the Juber notebook in code along the solutions.
All right so let's get started.
Firstly in the data.
So I need to import it also import Pandurs as PD and then I'm going to say census is equal to PD read
C S V and then I'm going to Redan census data that CXXVIII.
Remember you have to pass in the whole file path.
If you're not in the same directory and then we'll say sensus head so we can check out the data so you
can see here I have a lot of categorical categorical data where we have strings as the categories so
we need to work with that later on with tensor Flo's estimator API.
Up next we need to say that the label columns of less than or equal to 50 k are greater than 50 k those
are strings and we need to convert them to zero and ones in order for tent's flow to understand.
So the way I did this is first off if you ever want to figure out what are the actual unique values
inside a column you can just say unique as a method of a column and report back that unique values here.
So we know now that these are the strings we need to convert.
So the way we can do this is using the panels to apply method.
So I create a function that converts these two strings to either zero or 1 and then apply it to the
entire column.
So I'll say label 6.
It takes in a label that is either the string or the string and we'll do the following.
If that label is equal to the string right here and again note the spacing there's a space right there
in that string.
Then I'm going to return a zero else I'll return a 1.
And if you check out the solutions book there's kind of a nice little land expression that does this
all in one line.
But I think this one is really clear on what it's actually doing.
And Chips equals equals.
There we go.
And then I'm going to say sensus income bracket is not equal to sensus income bracket how about a complete
and then I'm going to say apply and I will apply the function so labeled 6.
I know here I'm not calling the function I'm just passing it in there.
Perfect.
So now if I take a look at my data from again census had run that and if I go all the way to the right
you know Notice here that the income brackets are either zeros or ones.
Now I want to perform a train test split on the data.
It's pretty straightforward from S-K learn model selection.
Import train to split run that you want to grab our data.
So our actual features that's going to be sensus and then we're going to drop the income bracket column.
So income bracket and we want to drop that along access is equal to 1.
Then we also want to get our y true or Y labels.
And that's just going to be equal to the income bracket column.
There we go.
And then we call train to split shift enter.
Expand on this.
Scroll down until we find this nice little convenience line copy.
Paste that in and then we just need to do a couple of replacements here.
Change this to be ex-state to change that to be white labels test size is just 30 percent.
And I do want one for my random state.
OK.
So there's a train to split up next you want to create the feature columns.
So I always recommend using the name your data frame and then calling the columns to get a list of the
column names.
This gives you the exact strings in the passen.
First off we're going to create the columns for the categorical values.
I want to show you two examples and then I get a copy and paste the rest from the actual notebook.
But first off I need to import tensor flow as T.F..
OK so let's create the feature columns or do two of them.
So for the gender column I would need to say T.F. feature column is a categorical column.
And since I know there's only two genders female and male I'll say with a vocab list.
So I pasan gender is the name of the column and then I pass in a list of possible options which is just
female and male.
So that's one way to do it the other way is let's say you have the occupation column where I have no
idea how many categories there are and I don't want to provide a full vocab list.
Well I just create an occupation variable here.
It's going to be a feature column.
Again a categorical column.
But instead I'm going to use a hash bucket.
We'll say occupation the name of the column and then I just choose the hash bucket size large enough
that I know I will run into any limitation so I can just put a thousand here because I know there's
no more than 1000 occupation's.
All right.
And you can do the same thing for the various other ones either provide a vocab list or provide the
hash buckets.
Obviously hash book it's a lot easier.
So let me just copy and paste from the solutions book here.
And there we have now all our categorical columns so that the marital status relationship education
or class and then native country.
So I just set the hash bucket size 2000 because I know that's a large enough number.
It's not going to make a thousand categories.
It's just going to make up to 1000 categories.
OK.
Now we have the continuous features.
So let me just do one example here.
We've done this before we say a feature column numeric column and then we'd just say age.
All right.
So then I'm going to copy and paste the rest of these from the solutions.
No but I have these for you so you can copy and paste this as well.
Now we want to put all these variables into a single list.
So we just say feet calls is equal to.
And then we just create our list with these variables so gender occupation marital status etc..
So I'm going to copy and paste this so you don't see me just type a bunch of variable names here.
There we go.
So that is our feature column.
So we just created for the T.F. estimator.
Now it's time for the input function.
So the bet size is up to you.
But I mentioned that I did choose a batch size of 100.
You can kind of play around to see what works best for your model.
So same tensor flow estimator inputs and we're dealing with panel data frames so we'll choose a Pancho's
input function.
And then we're going to say x is equal to x train Y is equal to y train I'll choose batch size equal
to 100 will leave number of the pox as none that is default.
And then we also want to say shuffle is equal to true because the training input function.
Next we want to create our model.
So let's go and do that we'll say model is equal to T.F. estimator.
And we're going to use a linear classifier.
As I mentioned if you want to use a densely neural network classifier are connected in your own that
were classifier then back for these categorical columns you'll need to convert them into embedded categorical
columns.
So you need to pass all of these into that embedding function.
So go ahead and review the lectures and we did that.
But for right now we're using linear classifiers we don't need to do that.
We basically just need to say what the feature columns are which is feek calls.
All right so we have our linear classifier.
Now it's time to trayner data.
So I'll say model train input function we'll say that's equal to the input phunk we created.
And you provide how many training steps you can do.
So it's really up to you.
I'll just do 10000 pretty fast computer and then I'm going to hop forward in time for the evaluation.
All right so hopping forward into the future.
My model is now done training.
It's time to create a prediction function.
So let's do that.
We'll say my prediction function is going to have some major thought inputs that pand those input function.
And because I'm using prediction not evaluation I really only need the features if I was doing evaluation
then I would end up needing something to evaluate against such as white tests.
But in this case I'm just going to say test will say batch size is equal to the length of X test.
And then because we want to use this for prediction we'll say shuffle is equal to false and then I just
use model that predict and I pass that input function is equal to that prediction function.
I just made.
And that's going to give us a generator results so let's say prediction generator is equal to that model
prediction and then let's say predictions themselves is a list or converting that.
So that takes a little bit of time because it's actually generating the results.
So now if I take a look at predictions it's a list of dictionaries where I have class IDs.
So that's what I actually want to grab.
So let's go ahead and do that.
You can do this for loop or with a list comprehension.
So he basically wants pred the class.
Let's do this like this.
We want pred for class underscore IDs.
We want the first item there.
For prayer in prediction.
So this is of a list comprehension.
You can check up these solutions book if you want the actual For loop that does this.
But then we'll just set the sequel to final sets.
There we go.
So there's our list comprehension.
And as I mentioned we have those dictionaries.
But if I take a look at final spreads.
Now I just have a big list of all the values all the labels that predicted.
So once I have that list which is basically what we did here I can use classification report from scalar
metrics so let's do that from S-K learn metrics import the classification report.
And this is a really nice tool that essentially gives you a precision and recall value or a fun score
for binary classification and we use it.
If you just say classification and poor you shift tab here Ill report back the White shirt or excuse
me.
It needs provided the y true values and the way predicted values.
So I know the y true values equal to white test and then I know the predicted values.
Those are the ones that you just create appear which you have as final Pretz.
So there we have it.
And then when I run this it looks a little weird.
That's because it's meant to be printed.
So we need to print this out.
And now we get this nice little format so you can see here I got around 85 percent precision recall
and EF 1 score which is definitely not so bad given the data set.
That's pretty much close to the best you can do using regularisation you may be able to push it a little
further up but that's pretty good.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums but basically ends the section on using
the dancefloor basics for things like regression and classification.
Coming up next in future sections we're going to start tackling problems that really only tensor flow
are only deep learning has the capabilities of solving things like image classification.
All right I'll see you there.