Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to quickly discuss saving and restoring models.
You've created some pretty interesting models of tensor flow.
So it might be nice to be able to save them and then recall them later.
Let's open up a Jupiter notebook and show you how this is done.
All right so here I am underneath the tensor flow basics folder and if you go to that folder and scroll
down you'll see a notebook called saving and loading models.
I'm trying to walk you through this notebook and show you how this is done because otherwise we'll have
to create a whole nother model.
And since we already have one ready we'll go ahead and use it.
So saving and loading models and what this does is it runs through the network example that we've already
created.
So I'm going to go ahead and just run these cells and we kind of go along.
We remember we created some artificial data.
We saw the x data we plotted it out created some variables have our costs function the optimizer and
then we initialize the variables and then it comes time to actually run the model.
But this time we're going to save it and then restore it the easiest way to save a model intenser flow
is using the ETF train that saver object.
If you look at the documentation it shows you some other ways to do it.
But if you actually start looking at Stack Overflow posts everyone suggests to use this method because
it really is the easiest way to go.
So all you have to do to save a model of tensor flow is say some Savir or whatever you want to call
this variable is equal to an instance of the T.F. train that Savir object.
So I'm going to go ahead and run that.
And then during your session where you're going to do is you'll run your session initialiser variables
either go first some epochs or some training steps et cetera you're going to run your training optimization
algorithm you're going to get back any results you want to get back.
And then once you're done with everything where you're going to do is at the very end you're going to
call your saver object that you've already defined and then call the Save method off of it and it takes
in two arguments it's going to take in SPSS or whatever you decided to call your session.
In the course we always call it s.c.s.
So you're going to pass in your session and then what you're going to do is passen the pathway to your
checkpoint file.
And typically this works a lot better if you provide a directory.
So what you need to do is for instance if I want to say save or save I'm going to pasan my session and
then I always recommend to pass some new directory for your model so we can say new model directory
and forward slash when the whatever you want to call your model so we can say my second model that and
then you're going to create a checkpoint.
See Kate Peetie Now if you want to just say my second model checkpoint.
Typically you get errors if you just pass in the checkpoint file itself.
So if you just want the checkpoint file you don't want another folder so to show you what I mean by
another folder.
If I come back here you can see I already have a model's folder created and if I click on that model
I can see that checkpoint data.
But if you don't want to create another folder you just want the checkpoint data here.
We usually have to do is put a dot and then a forward slash.
Now if you get errors you know kind of depends on your operating system then I would suggest actually
create in that directory depending on your operating system.
If you just pass this checkpoint file as I'm doing on this last line you sometimes get errors or it
doesn't actually save it.
So again I recommend either providing a directory or doing a forward slash if you for whatever reason
just really want the checkpoint files in the same directory as this notebook.
So let's go ahead and test this out.
And I put a hash tag here and let's go ahead and try this.
So saying new models my second model.
I'm going to run this now it trained it and if I come back over here to senseful basics now I see my
new models folder and I see a bunch of stuff with the checkpoint data.
So I'm going to actually restore it.
And again if I evaluate my results and the training data that's still working.
So that's good.
So now we're going to show you how to load the model.
So remember I still have my test data.
So what I will do is you start another session and then the very first thing you do.
Unlike last time it was the very last thing you're going to say Sabor thought restore you're going to
pass in your session and then you going to pass in the path to that checkpoint file that you just created.
So basically you can just copy and paste that.
So it was Kennebec appear it was new models.
My second model checkpoint.
Copy that scroll down.
Paste it in and then now you're going to have all the variables from your model so you can continue
trading it on more data if you want to.
Or you can just Fich back results.
Remember model has the variables and B.
So all that information is already saved here.
So I could continue training on more data or I could just run the variables themselves and grab that
information.
So going to fetch back the results this restored slope and restored int..
So let me run that real quick so you can see it's restoring the parameters from the model set.
My second model checkpoint file.
And just to show that it worked.
I'm now going to do the plot with this restored slope and this restored intercept.
And if you run that you should see kind of that same slope line because we're able to successfully restore
it from our model.
OK.
And that's really the basics of saving and loading models.
You'll see us use this later on in a little bit in the convolutional neural networks and a little bit
more in the current year that works throughout the course whenever we need to call our model.
And as far as general workflow for restoring a model and saving a model I personally like to usually
have my training data in it's own session and then I save the model and then I restore the model for
my test data.
We won't do that throughout the course.
A lot of times we'll just run everything in one session just to save time.
As far as tape is concerned.
But my personal preference is to have kind of a training session and then a testing session where I
just restore the trained model.
OK.
Again that's a personal preference.
There's no right or wrong way to go about it.
You could just do everything in one session if you really wanted to.
Thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture.