Welcome everyone to the crash course basics section of the course in the section of the course we're
going to have just a few lectures that provide a very basic overview for some of the libraries we'll
be using throughout this course such as pi pandas that live and pandas built in data visualization as
well as using sikat learn for pre-processing data.
Now keep in mind most of the time we'll be working directly with tensor flow.
We're really just using these libraries for kind of reading in our data manipulating it or cleaning
it just a little bit.
The main focus of this course is tensor flow and hopefully before you've even started this course you
already have experience and worked with these libraries in the past if you feel very comfortable with
these libraries.
Feel free to just skip this section completely.
Again this is really not meant to be a comprehensive overview of these libraries.
If you've never heard of these libraries before you may want to check out my other course Python for
data science or machine learning bootcamp before actually attempting discourse.
Again these are very basic overviews just enough for a quick refresher in case it's been awhile since
you've worked at the falling libraries.
OK.
Let's get started.
I'll see at the next lecture.