Welcome everyone to this quick crash course overview lecture on pi which is a numerical Python library
and we're such it is going to show you the very basics of it and how we're going to use in this course.
Let's open up a Jupiter notebook and get started.
All right so here I am with a new Jupiter notebook and the first thing to do is important up-I as MP
and let's go over a couple of ways so we can create arrays.
So we're already familiar a python list 1 2 3 which is elements in a sequence.
And if I want to convert this into an empire array and I can say end dot and if hit tab here you'll
notice that there's a ton a ton of functions that are built into non-pay the majority of these we will
never use but we may be using array.
So you can cast a really transform a list into an array.
So if you run that you can see now it's an array.
And if you check the type of this object it's no longer just the list but instead it's a PI and D array
meaning and dimensional array.
OK.
So then we could also save this or assign it to a variable and then call back that variable later on.
And again remember it's just shift and try to run a cell.
Now that's the way you can cast a list into an array.
But lots of times we'll be using a lot of built in functions with no PI to create large arrays very
quickly.
So one way to do that is by using the arr. function that's built into non-pay again just clicking tab
there to auto complete and arranged the way it works.
If you do shift tab here will basically tell you it's essentially non-pay his version of Python's normal
range function where you indicate a start a stop and then as an option a step size.
For example I can say start at zero.
Whoops let me make sure I click on that.
Start at zero go up tube and not including 10 and then I'll see 0 through 9 here so you can see that
we have 10 elements in array evenly spaced by one.
Don't be confused by the fact that it doesn't go all the way to 10.
It's because it's going up to but not including that last stopping.
So if you actually wanted this to be 0 310 you would have to put an 11 here and then you would get back
0 through 10 which would be 11 elements.
Now if you actually want to indicate a step size for instance you all the even numbers as a third argument
you can indicate hey go in steps of two.
And then when you run this you can see have zero to four six eight 10 etc..
So that's a range.
Again a start stop and step size.
Very similar to pythons Bilton range function non-employee also has lots of useful tools for quickly
creating specific arrays such as an array of zeros.
So zeroes can either just take in one digit or one integer and will return back a one dimensional array.
You can see here it returned back five zeros or instead you can pass any tuple of dimensions.
Maybe you want a three by five array or matrix A two dimensional array.
And when you're in that you can see here I have three rows and then five columns of zeros.
So that's the way zeros works essentially returns back an n dimensional array pending on what you pass
in the dimensions of that where they're all zeros.
And note that it has a decimal point here in the Kading that these are actually all floating points
versus integers so we had over in a range and a lot of times with the operations we perform with tensor
flow and Python non-place going to be transforming things to floats to make sure that we don't accidentally
lose information.
OK so now let's go ahead and discuss a couple of more ways of creating arrays.
There is also a similar ones function.
Same deal here.
If you pass on a single integer it's going to bring back an array of ones.
No again that their floating point numbers.
And then we can do something like a 3 by 5 and pass that in as a tuple.
Although I believe it doesn't matter either way.
Here we go through by five three ones by five ones and there's ways of creating linearly spaced arrays.
So there's lende space and basically Lance Bass works by you providing a starting point a stopping point
and then the number of elements you want evenly spaced or linearly spaced between the start and the
stop.
For example if I want to start at zero and go to 11 and I wants 10 points there that are evenly spaced
it's going to return back.
This right here if I want 11 points that are evenly spaced then I can see jumping up in steps of 1.1
then two point two three point three etc. if I want 100 points between 0 and 11 that are evenly spaced
then it goes zero all the way to 11.
So the difference here between linearly spaced and arrange arranged takes in a start and stop and then
it you actually define what jump or what steps size you want to take as you go along linearly spaced
or space instead again start stop.
But then you say how many points do you want evenly spaced between that.
So you could ask for just five points evenly spaced between that.
Or you could ask for 5000 points evenly spaced between that and know here if you ask for a super large
array back in Jupiter.
It just indicates a dot dot dot.
So that's one space.
Very useful to know.
Let's go ahead and cover a random number hirees.
A lot of times we're dealing with neural networks you have to initialize things for in them values.
So implies a really nice random library.
You can say that random dots and then hit tab here and there's lots and lots of functions that are included
in this random Library.
We'll be using all of them.
But we'll introduce a few of the common ones.
One of the common ones is Rand ants which as you may have guessed returns back a random integer.
So we do shift tab here.
You basically give it a low number and a high number and then you can also indicate a size so the dimensions
you want.
And note that the low number is inclusive and the high number is exclusive.
So show an example of that.
Let's say just want one random number between 0 and 10 where 0 is inclusive tennis exclusive.
You run that and you get back 6.
If I run this again I get back zero run again.
So every time I run this I'm going to get back a different read that number every time.
And sometimes it gets repeated.
So there we got three zeros in a row.
If we make this larger we won't see as many repeated values because the likelihoods are 1 in 1000 here.
OK.
So just random integers.
That's how it works.
And if you want dimensions there I want three by three.
Two dimensional array or a matrix of random integers.
I can run that and there they are.
So read this again.
Now there's that are random integers.
Now there's other random ones that we're going to be using.
Things like random normal is another common one.
So you can give a location a scale.
It just draws random samples from a normal or Gaussian distribution.
There's lots of round distributions that you can choose so keep that in mind we'll introduce those throughout
the course as we encounter them.
So to finish off our discussion of Nim Pye's ran the module I want to talk about setting a random seed.
And that's going to be important to make sure that the random numbers I generate are the same as the
array and the numbers you generate.
So Nesle go ahead and type N.P. that random seed.
And then you can see the generator of the ran the numbers.
And typically I use the value 101 may change it up.
But what's important here is now if I say any random thought ran It's a let's say 0 1000.
Give me 10 random numbers run this I get back starting from 95.
A much more in numbers than in 40.
However no.
If I were to run again I constantly get back the same ran the numbers and that's because I've set this
random seed.
The important thing to note here is that this random seed is currently in the same cell as this random
integer command.
And that's important because if I were to copy and paste this into another cell I won't get back the
same random integers because that's the second time I run this.
So if I want to make sure that I constantly get back the same or intimidators I want to make sure that
I'm resetting that seat every time.
So again make sure that that seed is in the same cell as whatever operation is generating random numbers
to make sure that you're actually taking into account that seed.
Because if I keep running it outside of this then even though I set that seed it's going to keep generating
as I ask for them.
I have to reset the seed in order to get back that same sequence of random numbers.
OK that's basically all we need to know about creating an umpire or raise either one dimensional or
two dimensional.
Later on we'll learn about tensors which are essentially three dimensional and dimensional arrays.
We're going to do now is quickly cover a few useful operations.
So if I have an array here that's going to generate run we'll see a random rant.
It's 0.
One hundred ten.
And let's go ahead and grab that see just to make sure that we get the same numbers here.
So I ask for the survey.
You should have the same numbers I do.
If you want to find the max value of an array you can just say Max.
Call it like that if you want to find the minimum.
You can just call minimum.
There's lots of other functions and methods you can call here if hit tab you can see a bunch of them
here who definitely won't be using all of these.
A lot of this is happening in the background with tensor flow.
But you can do things like also grab the average what's also really nice is that if you want to grab
the index location of the max value so the max value here is ninety five bullets say this is a huge
array.
And I want to know whereas the actual index location of that max value I can use our emacs and that
returns back zero which is the index location of that max value.
And there's the same operation for Argemone or it's going to return the index position of the minimum
value and very quickly too.
And there is discussion of Empire operations.
I want to discuss the reshape method often IRA.
So if I take a look at my array right now it's one dimensional and just 10 elements but I can actually
reshape this using the reshape command.
And here I can reshape it into whatever shape I want as long as the 10 elements out evenly.
For example I can reshape this into a 2 by 5 array.
And here I have the two rows with five columns and we'll be using reshape to reshape tensors a lot.
So again reshape.
Very useful.
It just reshapes an array.
Finally let's go ahead and discuss indexing.
So I'm going to create a matrix.
We'll say in Empire range 0 to 100.
And then I'm going to call reshape off of this to be a 10 by 10.
And this sort of stacks methods on a higher rate is really common.
So now I have a nice numb piracy Ray 0 through 99 rubber goes up to about including 100 and it's 10
by 10.
So it includes a there.
So the way I can grab stuff if I just want to grab a single element let's say I wanted to grab the value
of the safe first row second column what I could do is say mats or whatever the name of your time to
the missional array is.
And then you passen the row you want starting at index 0 and then you can pasand the column you want.
So in this case I want column 1 and this should return the value 1.
So let's go in practice.
Go ahead and choose a random number here going to choose 43.
So let's try to index up 43.
That's 0 1 2 3 4.
So it's in the fourth row and then column wise 43 is 0 1 2 3.
So let's go ahead and put in 3 here.
Run this and then we have 43.
So again it's just the index location by RHO comma in the location by column.
So that is how you can get a single element out of a to them array.
You can also use slicing to grab chunks of the story and it works just like regular Python slicing.
So let's go ahead and say Matt let's say I want all the rows in the first column.
So that is I want all these rows 0 10 20 30 but just for the first column.
So essentially I just want 0 10 20 30 40 etc..
What I would do is I would use colon to indicate everything as far as Rose is concerned.
And then I can pass in zero to indicate that I only want that first column index 0 run that.
Now I can see you have an array here 0 10 20 30 etc..
I can also do kind of the opposite effect.
So grab all the columns in a particular row.
So if I just wanted to essentially return back a single row I could say five comma colon returns back
that entire row a little weird because you kind of think about it backwards.
The fact they are selecting all columns for one row returns back the whole row.
But that's the way it works.
Again it's fro comma column and you can use colon to indicate everything.
Then you can also do slices.
Let's take a look at our matrix again 0 through 99 and then we're going to say Matt here and let's go
ahead and grab just this first trunk.
0 1 2 10 11 12 20 21 22.
What I'm going to do here then is first slice off my rows so the rows I want is zero 10 20.
So that is starting at index 0 up to but not including three.
So that's 0 1 2 to get I'm up going up to bet on including that third index.
Or really that fourth row index three.
And then we're going to do essentially the same thing for 0 1 2.
So I'm sorry column 0 then slicing all the way and not including that index three there.
And that should return back 0 1 to 10 11 12 20 21 22.
So this is confusing to you go ahead and practice a little bit so see if you can select kind of random
chunks from this array and go ahead and index them.
The most confusing part I believe for beginners is the fact that it goes up to an not including that
last slice index.
Finally let's go ahead and discuss masking.
So masking is a super useful attribute of pi.
So I want to show it off.
Basically if you have a matrix here you can perform a Boolean operation on it.
For example I could ask Hey where is this matrix A greater than 50 and it'll return back a matrix of
boolean values and see the start as false and then once it becomes great and the fifth day they all
start returning true.
If I actually wanted to only select those values I don't want just this to the matrix of boolean values
but instead I want the actual values we can end up doing is the following.
We can say something like My filter is equal to this and then I'll grab my matrix again and pasan filter
and then it returns back all the values that have to be greater than 50.
And there they are typically you don't see this done in two steps.
So instead what you end up seeing is something like Matt.
And then inside of that Matt greater than 50.
And this is known as Boullion masking or just masking in general it's super useful.
And we'll be seeing it a little bit throughout this course.
OK.
That's really all there is to it.
You can go ahead and review the notebook in case you want any of the code I ran here.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture or we'll quickly do a crash course for pandas which
is built directly off of them by.