Well everyone welcome to this quick overview of pandas.
We're actually going to be using pi a lot more than pandas so we're going to show you here how you can
use pandas to read in a sci fi file which will be our main use for pandas and then how to access things
from the data frame which Pandurs creates.
Let's hop over to Jupiter notebook.
OK here I am in the Juber notebook and Lynsay import Pandurs as PD shift enter to run that and we're
going to be mainly using panels to read in files so you can use PD read underscore and hit tab here.
You'll notice that Pindar's can read from a variety of formats are mainly just going to be using C as
V files.
So then what you do here is you passen as a string the entire file path to the CSP file or if the CC
file is located in the same directory as this particular notebook which is the case for the zip file
that comes with this course.
And if you ever wondering what directory you're in.
Just type in P.W. the shift enter and I'll report back what directory you're in.
So again all you need to do is passen the location of the CFE file.
So I have the CC file located in this character right here so I'll have to do is type it in this file
called salaries CXVII.
Keep in mind every CACP file has the extension that cxxviii sometimes it's just salary's in the name
of the file.
So you can always use tab autocomplete to help you there.
So those here a hit tab.
It will auto complete if the files actually there.
If you're not getting the auto complete that's probably a good sign or indicator that the file is not
actually in the same directory that your notebooks in.
So we do as we set this equal to a variable and then the variable is a data frame.
So I just put in DFA there and a data frame essentially kind of looks like an Excel spreadsheet.
You have column names and you have an index and then you have data points.
And we're going to be using this for our various features in machine learning datasets.
If you ever want to grab an entire column of information we end up doing it you will type in the name
of your data frame square brackets and then pass in the name of the column.
So for instance if I wanted the salary column I can run this and it returns back the salary column with
the index location of it.
If you want multiple columns back you end up doing is you can just type in a list of column names.
For example I want salary and name.
And then I get both of them back.
Notice the difference here and passing in a list which is why I get those two sets of brackets.
Remember I mentioned that panderers is directly built off of pi.
So just like Num. pie has lots of the same features.
For example if we say salary we can do things such as Max run that in order to turn back the max salary
if you want to see a bunch of information.
Statistically speaking about your data frame you can use the described method and it will take in the
numerical columns and describe them.
Count means standard deviation minimum portal's etc..
Then finally what else also want to mention is just like them we can do boolean filters.
So for example if I ask K where is the salary greater then let's see let's say 60000.
So if I say back here in the cell where is a salary greater than 60000 run that I see.
False.
True true.
So taking a look at my original data frame looks like Sally and Alyssa have salaries that are greater
than 60000 if actually want the entries themselves and not just the boolean values.
What I ended up doing is I can say my filter here run that and then pass in that filter.
So my filter run that heresie Sally and Oliseh.
Now again usually you don't do this in two steps.
Instead we end up doing just copy and paste this here and you see something like this which looks a
little weird at first but this is kind of a very common thing in Pandurs.
That's really all we need to know.
Again pandas can do a lot more to this.
And I covered that in my Python for data science in machine learning boot camp but really won't encounter
Python or excuse me pand those that much because we're sensory is going to be using it to read and to
see as we file an offer that you can then say something like as Matrix you know return back a non-primary.
That's what we're going to be doing a lot.
Going to see as we file and then pass it off as a non PI matrix and then we're going to it work if not
pay.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.