Welcome everyone to this lecture on a quick overview of data visualization will teach you how to use
Map plot lib for data is as well as Panoz built in data visualization.
Let's open up a new chapter notebook and get started.
All right we'll start off with a couple of imports here by pandas and then we'll also say import map
plot whipped up pipe plot as peel tea and the next thing we're going to do when working of Jupiter notebooks
in order to see the visualizations in line of the notebooks when you have this percent sign map plot
live space in line and that's known as a magic command.
And this magic command only works in Jupiter notebooks if you're not using a Jupiter notebook that means
that after you have all your plot code you need to get to type then appeal t show open and closed print
CS in order to actually see the plot.
OK we don't need to do that since we're in the Jupiter note book.
So let's actually show you do a really simple plot with Matt spotlit and most of the plots in this course
are going to be really straightforward we're either going to use that plotted to show an image or we'll
kind of show some sort of curvature song going to create an empire.
Let's say zero to 10.
So if I take a look at X it's just 0 9 there and then we're going to say why is equal to x squared.
And then in order to plot something like X versus Y you just say peel t plots and then x y enter.
And that creates this nice little to the line plot.
Now as a third argument what you can do is you can passen a string code for a marker and if you pass
an asterix there kind of puts some little stars if you pasan a color code such as for instance red it
will make that line red.
There is a lot more detail to this and it's not just a bunch of string codes to memorize if you shift
tab here.
There's kind of a list of arguments and if you expand on this it will tell you various things here.
So our Plus has read Plus's etc. and helps keep scrolling down.
Ill tell you the various characters description of the lifestyles as well as the colors that you can
add to it.
We really don't focus that much data visualization as course we just use really simple plots.
So really all you need to know is X versus Y and then some sort of string code that will allow us to
kind of differentiate this.
OK so kind of as a last example here we can do like a red dash line.
We have something like that something you may find yourself needing to do is to kind of edit the x axis
and y axis in order to do that in the same cell as replot command.
We need to do is say PLDT and you can passen X limits and then passing the limits.
So notice here that it kind of has some extra space after 0 if you want it's clear that you can kind
of hardcoded in set the limit at 0 and then maybe only want to go to 4.
So you pass that in and you can see now we have zero to for instance the y axis is still defined by
the original auto set Y axis.
What we can do here say peel t y Lim and make that go from let's say 0 to 10 and there we can see the
various points here.
And it's essentially just putting out the points and then putting a dashed line between them which is
why you zoom in it gets a little more jaggy.
And in case you ever want to put titles or X labels on your plot you can use Piazzi title to title your
plot.
So you just pass a string there and shows a title on top.
And I'm a little zoomed in here which is why it looks blurry or a little blurry so if I zoom out it
kind of starts getting a little clearer that we can say Piazzi to the X label to have some sort of X
label.
So to put an X there and then we can see now I have an X label.
And as you may have guessed I just kind of copy and paste this put a white label here make that label
I also get a white label.
Keep in mind all of these commands need to go in the same cell.
Otherwise matplotlib isn't really smart enough to know what plot you're referring to just with these
Piazzi commands.
In other plot there were going to be doing a lot especially when we work with images of convolutional
neural networks is in the show plot recension the kind of show and image on a to the array.
So I'm going to create a matrix will say derange 0 to 100.
And then I'm going to reshape this 10 by 10.
So if I look at my matrix is essentially just a bunch of values that keep getting higher and higher.
So if I wanted to plot this out as kind of a to the missional color scheme what I would expect is some
sort of color gradient that row by row it keeps getting brighter and brighter.
And also column by column it keeps getting brighter and brighter or darker and darker depending on how
you think about it in order to do that.
We need to say peel t show and this can take in a two dimensional array here and then define the color
by the actual value.
So if we just pass in our matrix here I can see what we expected which is a lighter and lighter color
mapping.
And you can actually declare what kind of color map you want using See map.
You can pass on a string code here.
You can check out the documentation for the various string codes but cool warm is another one here.
And if you accidentally spell something wrong and you scroll all the way down here eventually says hey
this color map wasn't recognized here are the possible values.
And there's tons of possible values here.
And you can check out the documentation see what each of these colors look like.
We can kind of grab one here and this one may or may not look that great with this data.
But here we have kind of a red yellow green so you can see stars red yellow to green.
So that's in show and just kind of showed again one more time.
Let's now create a random value here so say Ran's ants.
This goes to a thousand and then lets the size be 10 by 10.
So that's my matrix now it's just a bunch of random numbers.
So if I say peel T.
Show here.
On the Matrix now I can see kind of a bunch of random squares there.
And if you want a color bar all you have to do is say peel t the color bar offer this open close parentheses
and then you can see color bar in the case.
The range of the values themselves.
So that is map plot lib as far as plottings concern.
Pancho's actually has its own built in visualization capabilities that run on top of that plot lym kind
of more like a nicer API call from Appin the state of frame.
We don't use it a whole lot but just in case you're interested in it we can say Deia physical to PD
read CSFB we're gonna use that salary's file from last time as well.
And then if we check out that sellers file let's say we wanted to do a scatterplot of salary versus
age.
Then I can just say if plot's and then it's basically expecting an X A Y and then a kind of plot.
So I can do a line plot or I can do something like a scatter plot which makes more sense for three points.
So I'll say X and then as a string you just pass in the column name will say why is H.
And then finally we'll say the kind is a scatter
run.
And now we can see we have a scatterplot right off of our panel.
There's lots of different plot types that panned supports.
You can check the documentation we really won't be using that many of them but if you check out the
plot dot and then hit tab you'll notice the various kind of plots that panned the supports.
And these are all built off directly of Matt plotless which is why the styling looks so similar.
OK that's really all you need to know.
Will essentially just be using him show a lot for images and then we'll be using things like dot plot
for simple graphs.
OK thanks everyone.
See the next lecture.