Welcome everyone.
This quick overview on psychist learn and we really won't be talking about sikat learn machine learning
models because we're going to be using tent's flow instead.
Well we're going to be talking about in this lecture is using sikat learn for pre-processing and specifically
two things and that is scaling our data and also splitting our data into train test sets.
Let's go ahead and jump to DUPERE notebook and see the convenience functions that sikat learned provides
for us.
OK.
Go ahead and generate some data.
I will import umpire as an p and then we're mainly going to be using preprocessing of sikat learn so
say from S-K learn pre-processing import.
And we'll be importing the minimax scaler.
Let's go ahead and create some data we'll just say.
And we ran them ran in.
And we'll say random data.
Zero to 100.
And we'll have it be 10 rows by two columns.
So if I take a look at my data I see here that I have the 10 rows two columns kind of think of this
as either features in a dataset or labels in a dataset etc..
So if I actually want to run this data into a neural network usually what I should be doing is scaling
that data in order to do that.
I can use the minimax scalar.
So the way we do this is we create an instance of that minimax scalar.
So I'll say scaler underscore model.
Really whatever you want to call it minimax scaler close print sees.
And now I check out the type of that scalar model.
It is a instance of a min max scalar.
And then what we do is offer this scalar model.
We're going to fit it to our data and fitting it to her data.
Basically allows the model to learn what the minimum value and what the maximum value is for each column.
This warning right here you don't need to worry about it too much.
It's just reporting back that it's converting the integers into floating point numbers which makes sense
because we expect these wants her scale to be floating point numbers.
Then once we do that we can go ahead and grab her model and then transform the data and then once you
transform data you'll notice what happens is that the minimum value becomes zero and the maximum value
becomes one and that goes across each column.
So we kind of scroll up here we can see here that in my case with this random data I had a max value
for the first column at 92 and the minimum value was three.
So if we divide each value in this column by the max 92 we end up getting these results.
And that that is what the min max scaler does.
There's other ways of normalizing your data.
But for most of our cases since we're dealing with pretty basic data sets the min max scaler will be
enough.
Now technically I could have done this in one command instead of saying fit the data and then transform
the data the scalar model also has a fit transform.
And if you run that on the data it performs both those steps at once depending on what situation you're
in where you're usually going to do is you're going to fit to your training data and then transform
your training data and then transform your test data.
And the reason for that is because you don't really want to cheat by fitting to your test data as well
as your trained data because you don't want to assume that you're going to know what your test data
is going to look like.
So typically you fit to your training data and then you transform to your test data and your training
data.
But the model itself this scaling model has only been fitted to your training data.
All right let's go ahead and kind of show an example of a train test split so import Pandurs for this
and would create a data frame so we can imagine we just read in some see as we file so we can say PD
that data frames create a data frame and I'm going to say the data is equal to p that ran them ran Diante
I'll say zero.
101.
And then 50 by four.
In effect let's actually just grab that entire thing and put that in and you sell and will have that
be my data.
So if we take a look at my data it's just these integers here it's four columns by 50 rows.
So scrolling down here that's going to be the data pasan.
And you could put the whole command in one line but this makes it a little cleaner here.
And then let's go ahead and if I just pass this in and I take a look at the data and if you want to
call this DFA that it's a little clear.
So I'll say DFAC could repeat the data from there.
And if I take a look at the f.
So now that I'm viewing my data frame I can see here that pair of those has auto named these columns
to be 0 1 2 3.
What it can do to make sure is columns have names is I can provide a list of names.
So let's imagine this as a data set.
So all have three features F1 F2 F3 and then some sort of label.
So I can already tell this is a supervised learning problem.
I have three features and I'm trying to predict this label.
So now if I take a look at my data frame now the columns are named so three features and then the label
column.
Now let's imagine the Zura entire dataset.
And I want to split it into a training set.
And the testing set the way can do that is through the following method.
If I scroll down here I can say my X that is my features is equal to data.
And then I pass on a list of the columns only the feature columns that is F1 F2 F3.
So what's the mixture.
I personally fear there we go.
So now if I take a look at X it's only the feature columns and I'm going to do a similar process for
y for the labels will just say Y is equal to the F label.
Run that then take a look at why it's just that label column.
OK so now that I have my features my actual data and then the label that I'm trying to predict I can
do a train test split seal say from S-K learn the model selection import train test split run that and
then what I like to do is call train to split through shift tab here and then you can expand this to
see the actual documentation.
And if you scroll all the way down there's a nice little example you can kind of copy and paste from.
And it's this one right here X train accessed y train and y to us copy that whole commands and then
we can actually overwrite it here and put this all on one line.
When we zoom out a little bit so we can see the whole thing.
So it is trained to split actually do.
Well you pass in your feature columns and then you press in your label.
And then it's going to ask you what the test size is going to be.
So it's asking you what percentage of the data you want to go to the test set.
A really common value here is 30 percent or 33 percent should be your test 70 percent should be your
training.
And again this is a very situation specific number so there is no right or wrong answer here.
Sometimes a 50/50 split makes sense.
And then they ran them state is basically for repeatability.
Just like we had some PI random set seed.
We can do a seed here as well.
That way you can always make sure that you get the same random splits so you can say you want to 1:42
cetera.
It's up to you.
And then you get back these four variable results you get back in X train in excess a white train and
a white test.
So if I run this and I check out the shapes of these guys leps X train check out the shape.
Notice I have 35 rows by three.
So that means this is the actual x train.
So that is the feature data for the training set.
And if I take a look at X test.
Well let's go ahead and take a look at the shape here.
Then I have 15 by three.
Notice that it's smaller because this is the feature for the test set.
So the basic idea here would be once I actually have my neural network model working intenser flow and
I want to do some sort of training process for supervised learning I would feed in the training sets
for X train and y train and the model would try to basically build some sort of understanding of how
the X training features are able to predict the why training labels once they have that then I can evaluate
my model by feeding it the X test data and then it will try to predict what those labels should be in
order to do the full evaluation.
I can then compare those predictive values to the true test values and that's the reason for a train
to split.
And we're going to see this later on the course.
OK.
That's really all we need to know about sikat learn.
And as a quick note sikat learn is actually its own machine learning library for Python it's one of
most popular out there but it doesn't support the deep neural networks that tensor flow can do so which
is why we're not really going to be using it in this course if you're interested in some of those other
sikat learn machine learning model methods.
You can check out that Python for data science and machine learning boot camp course.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture.