Welcome everyone to the crash course review exercises.
So if you went ahead and went through those Crash Course Lectures we have a little note book as a quick
review of a couple of questions for you to answer so you can find that no book under crash course basics
crash course review exercises.
And there's also a solution note book that we're going to go through in the very next lecture.
Let's quickly have a quick overview of the review exercises notebook.
All right.
Here I am at the crash course review exercises notebook.
The basic idea here is that you'll have some sort of instructions in bold and then a cell below for
you to execute them in for example the very first one just ask you to import the libraries that we've
been working with.
So you could say something like.
Import some PI and P and as a quick little tip.
If you do shift enter that will execute a cell.
If you want to insert a cell below this one you can do alt enter and it will also execute the cell but
then insert a cell below.
So that's really nice that we can do.
All tenter all tents are all tenter so you can insert cells below.
In case you need more cells or more space than what you want to do is non-firing them see that it asks
you to create a matrix.
Then later on after you create that matrix it asks you to do some sort of visualization of that matrix.
They also ask you to do things like add a title add a color bar and then there's a little bonus aspect
to this.
It asks you to how can you change the aspect of this show plot.
So there's a parameter called aspect there to play around with.
And notice there's a little link here that kind of gives you a hint.
Then you go ahead and use Panas data frame to read in that player Ray as a data frame.
We actually should have to do that earlier in the lectures.
Then you'll create a scatterplot using panderers then you will scale the data to have a minimum of zero
maximum value of 1 using Cyke learn the preprocessing you went through.
Then once you've done that you'll go ahead and create a data frame and then perform a train test pilot.
OK.
Basically right in line of everything we just covered.
Those are all the basic tools that we're going to be using throughout the rest of the course when we
actually discuss neural networks and sensor flow.
Thinks everyone in the next lecture will go over the solutions.