Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to go through the solutions to the crash course.
Let's get started.
OK so here I am at the crash course review exercises notebook and if you want you could put these all
in the same cell.
But basically you just have to do all the imports import pandas PD import map plot lived up plots as
PLCC.
And then we're also going to be using sikat learn we'll say from S-K learn pre-processing in poor minimax
scaler and you could import that later.
Not a huge deal.
And we're also going to be using train to split from model selection import train to split.
Next thing I wanted to do was to set up Paice random seed to 101.
So it's going to do that say any random seed is 101.
Run that.
Let me zoom in one more level here so you can clearly see this so any random seed that we want to create
a matrix of 100 rows so I'll say math is equal to the random random I.A. because I want a random integers
that can go from 1 to 100.
So we're going to say 1 to 1 comma 101 because I wanted them to be a hundred and then I could say a
hundred and five.
Not a huge deal if you interpreted this to be a 100 here instead of 8 101.
Not really the purpose of the exercise just for you to remember how to create a matrix of integers.
So again not a huge deal if you put that as 100.
OK.
So kind of back down here.
Then we wanted to create art to the visualization the way we did that is we say peel t him show you
passing in your matrix and then we say peel t color bar in order to see a color bar and then if we want
to title it we just say PBT title and say my plot.
Now if you just run this notice that I didn't get anything out and that's because I haven't set map
in inline.
So let's go ahead and do this.
And you could do this above as well.
So I'll say Matt puts it in line.
Now when I run this I can see my plot.
Notice here though the dimensions feel off and that's because I haven't specified the aspect ratio I
want for show.
So if you go ahead and click on this link it'll take you to a stack overflow post.
That essentially describes how to resize any show and later on it just says hey use aspect here.
So we're going to go ahead and play around with that aspect.
Once you play around the aspect I ended up choosing a really small aspect ratio to kind of stretch it
out.
So that's the aspect ratio.
No right or wrong answer here.
Just wanted you to kind of play around with that.
OK.
So next we wanted to use PD that data frame to read in the array as a data frame.
That's quite easy we just say F is equal to PD data frame and then pass the cent as our data.
So I can say data is equal to Matt.
And then whoops if I check out my diff there it is 0 1 2 3 4.
Ok then moving along.
I want to scroll down here now create a scatterplot using Pandurs of the zero column versus the one
column and 0 0 and then 1.
So to do that all I have to say death plot I'll say x is equal to zero y is equal to 1.
And then I will specify kind as equal to scatter and then I have that scatterplot.
Next up I wanted to scale the data to have a minimum of zero and a maximum value of 1 Using say Hitler.
So I just create my scalar objects I'll say min max scaler and then you can have the results the scale
data and just say scaler in this case we'll do a transform that will always be the case for a train
to split but that wasn't really specified here.
We just show the skill result.
I can see here the minimum values are zeros and the maximum values are ones scrolling down.
We get to using your previously created data frame use D-Nev. columns to rename the pan those columns
to be these columns right here.
Then perform a train to split with sikat learn.
So if you click on that link it kind of explains what I'm trying to say here.
But you can grab this attribute off the data frame columns and set it to be equal to this list.
So I'm going to copy and paste this
in now if I check out my data frame I can see I've been able to rename the columns and if you only want
to see the head of your data frame that is the first and number of rows you can say DFA head passen
the first couple of number of rows you want to see and will return back 10 rows for you zero tonight.
And if you don't pass anything there automatically just returns the top five.
OK.
So I want to do the train test split which means I need to select my feature columns.
So one way to do that is say F and then pass and a list of columns I want.
So in this case it's all the feature columns.
Copy that.
And then I'm going to paste that in run that looks like I have one too many brackets there.
There we go.
And then for the label column just going to the F label run that as well.
And then finally and the train split.
So we actually already imported that.
So when I say train to split and then I was going to copy and paste.
I almost always do this just because the actual terms is a lot to type out manually.
So all these four things that are returned that I usually just copy them here and then paste them in
and then I change whatever I need to change.
In this case I have capital X and lowercase y.
So that makes sense.
Test size.
Not sure if I actually specify this doesn't really matter.
Random state again doesn't really matter as long as you're able to figure out they could do a train
test this way and then you can kind of view your results and you can see here that it works if both
non-payers and Pan those data frames.
OK that's it.
If you have any questions feel free to post to the Kewney forums.
But really what I can be using these libraries a whole lot these basics here is essentially all we need
to know to move onto a tensor flow.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.