Hello everyone and welcome to the section on recurrent neural networks.
We've used neural networks to solve classification and regression problems and we've also learned how
to use convolutional neural networks to solve image classification problems but we still haven't seen
how neural networks can deal with sequence information such as a time series.
So for this we need to learn how to use recurrent neural networks.
There's lots of interesting stuff are going to learn about the sex for the course.
We'll start off with a basic overview of our current year old that work theory that we're going to manually
implement a very basic recurrent neural network they will learn about some specific subtopics such as
vanishing gradients and specialized units such as a long short term memory unit.
Then we'll show you how to do a time series analysis with a current year that works trying to predict
a time series shifted one step into the future.
Then you'll have your own time series exercise along phase solutions lecture and then we'll also discuss
worts of VEC algorithm for word embedding.
All right.
There's lots to talk about so let's get started.
I'll see at the next lecture.