Hello everyone and welcome to the recurrent neural networks theory lecture here in this lecture which
is going to give you a brief overview of the theory behind a recurrent neural net.
So first off we're going to mainly be working with recurrent neural networks to solve problems that
deal with sequence information in a couple of examples of sequence information.
Are things like generally time series data.
So that could be something like a stock price changing throughout time or even things like the sales
of a store changing throughout time.
Then there's also sentences.
So even just natural language has a sequence to it.
So there's going to be words in a sentence in a particular order.
So as you move along the words should be in a particular order.
So that can also be thought of as a sequence.
Then there's music and audio information.
So that's sound and in particular at time ordering.
So that can also be thought of a sequence and even things like contradictories so where a car is going
to go or things like if you throw a ball up in the air or the trajectory of its path throughout the
air it can also be thought of as a sequence.
So we can imagine a sequence as just a vector of information for the index location basically points
out its points in time.
And then the actual values are the training values.
So if we imagine a sequence that's 1 2 3 4 5 6 the question that you could ask anybody is are you able
to predict a similar sequence shifted one tiny step into the future.
And for most people it's actually pretty easy.
You feel that there's a pattern here of increasing by 1 as you move along one time step.
So if I asked you hey what's the sequence that's similar to this except shifted over one time that you
would hopefully be able to figure out.
Well I'll just say two three four five six seven.
So we're going to try to later on training network to predict a time series shifted over one time step
into the future and you can imagine that will be really beneficial if we're trying to predict sales
for the next day.
So the way we can do this is by using a recurrent neural network so let's review how the normal neuron
works in a feed forward network.
Remember that a normal neuron just takes in some input and it can be multiple inputs so it can aggregate
them and then once it aggregates those inputs it passes it through some sort of activation function.
Here we're just using the symbol for a rectified linear unit that it can be things like a sigmoid function
or a 10:08 function et cetera.
And then from that we have an output.
So that's one normal neuron works a recurrent neuron is a little different.
What it's going to do is send the output back to itself.
So the output goes back into input of the same neuron.
So we can actually unroll this throughout time.
So if we roll this throughout time it ends up looking something like this.
So we can see time here kind of represent it on the x axis and we have this particular recurrent neuron
where it's input at T minus one gives an output at T-minus 1 and then that gets passed into the neuron
in its state input at time t and then that has an output at time t.
And then we can take that output and pass an input for the same neuron at time T plus 1 and then so
on and so on.
So this is called unrolling that recurrent neuron.
Something that's important to note here is that the neuron is actually receiving both inputs from a
previous timestep as well as inputs from the current time step.
So you can see each of these neurons has two sets of inputs there.
These cells that are a function of input from previous time steps are also known as memory cells in
recurrent neural networks are also flexible in their inputs and outputs for both sequences and single
vector values so show a couple of examples that in just a little bit.
But I want to know it's also very easy to create a layer of recurrent neurons.
Previously we just thought one recurrent neuron then we unrolled it through time but we could do the
same thing for an entire layer.
So if we want an entire layer of recurrent your aunts then it would look something like this where we
have input X and then it goes through those recurrent neurons.
Here we have three of them.
Then we see the output y and then we take the output and then just pass it back in to all the neurons
in that layer.
And we could do the same idea and unroll this entire layer throughout time so that we get an input to
equal zero and output it to equal zero and then pass that along with the output and input at time plus
1.
And same idea except now we're doing it with an entire layer.
Now since the output of these recurrent neurons at a time that T is technically a function of all the
inputs from previous times that you could then begin to think that has some form of memory because we're
technically passing in historical information into that recurrent neuron or that layer of recurrent
neurons.
So part of this neural network that preserves some sort of stay across these types steps is called a
memory cell and later on we're going to see much more complex examples of memory cells.
But for now we have this basic recurrent neural near on that it just sends its output back into its
input.
Recurring year old networks are also very flexible in their inputs and outputs.
So let's walk through a few examples of different combinations of inputs and outputs we can use for
recurrent neural networks so we can actually perform a sequence input to a sequence output and an example
of that would be passing in a set of Time series information such as a year's worth of daily sales data
and then wanting back a sequence of that same sales data shifted over a certain time period into the
future.
And that's basically the initial example we first thought of that 1 2 3 4 5.
And then you asked back for 2 3 4 5 6 TSOs a sequence however shifted over one step into the future
another set of examples.
Inputs and outputs would be to pass a sequence and put the request back a vector output.
So a common example of using recurrent your own networks for this sort of input output is sentiment
scores.
So you can feed in a sequence of words maybe a paragraph of a movie review and then request back a vector
indicating whether it was a positive sentiment such as they really liked the movie.
So that's usually indicated by one versus they really dislike the movie which is indicated by usually
negative 1 or 0.
So that would be an example of a sequence input so that paragraph of words to just a single vector value
and you essentially have a bunch of training data where you have a bunch of paragraphs and then some
sort of sentiment score attached them and you train your recurrent neural network on that data to have
a sequence input to a vector output.
So on the opposite side you could also feed in a vector input so a single input at just a first time
that and basically passen zeros for the rest of your time steps and then let the output be a sequence.
So that's a vector to sequence network.
So what you could do here is maybe pasan a single image and then request back a sequence of words describing
the image that would be a caption.
And if you've ever seen any research on line of images and auto generating captions you've seen examples
of that where they show a picture of maybe a person on the beach and the neural network actually returns
back a sentence.
Man Standing on a beach or something of that nature obviously is a really complex networks take a lot
of training time and a lot of data but it's definitely possible.
So what we're going to do now is explore how we can build a simple recurrent in your own that work model
with tensor flow manually then we're going to see how we can use tensor Flo's built in recurrent your
own network API classes.
So we're going to build a network manually still using tensor flow but a little more manually than usual.
And then later on we'll see that Tanstaafl actually has a really nice API for recurrent neural networks
that gives a nice level of abstraction to all of this.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.