Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture we're going to magically create a very simple recurrent near
all that work with tensor flow and then later on we'll see in a future lecture how to use tensor flows
a little bit higher level API for a current neural networks.
So we're going to mainly create a three year on a recurrent neural network layer with tensor flow.
And the main idea to really focus on here is not the actual manual creation of the recurrent neural
network because that's not really scalable for larger problems.
Instead I want you to focus on the input format of the data.
So let's quickly review what we are actually going to create.
We're going to construct the following recurrent neural network layer.
We've actually seen this before in the past but basically we're going to do is have an input X that
goes into three neurons in the layer that produces an output y and then that y output gets fed back
into that same layer.
So you can imagine we're going to need two sets of weights here.
One called W X for that original input and then another set of weights called W-why for that second
output.
So if we want to unroll this through time it's going to look something like this.
Basically will 0 and then sequel's one or zero plus one.
So again we're going to start by running the recurrent neural network just for two batches of data sequel's
zero and sequel's one where each recurrent neuron has two sets of weights.
So W X for the input weights on that original input X and then W-why for the weights on the output of
original x.
Now before we dive into that Jupiter note book I want to walk through an example the formatting of the
input data.
So in this case we're going to show an example using words but the Jubran no books just going to use
numerical data in this case.
I want to show you before it's because it's a lot easier to understand what gives you a much more intuitive
feeling about what the batches actually represent.
So let's say we have two samples of data.
In this case we have two sequences so two sentences the first sequence you have is the brown fox is
quick.
The second sequence we have is the Redfox jumped high and you can see for each of these two samples
we have five times that it's sequel 0 2 1 2 3 and 4.
So the way we actually feed in batches is let's say we have five batches we'll call the entire set of
all the batches words and data set.
And the first batch has a batch size of two so that there's two samples in the batch and you feed in
based off the time stamp.
Not based off the sample itself.
So the very first batch you feed in is everything at teakwood 0 for however many samples you want.
In this case we only have two samples so we pass in the the then the next batch is going to be at sequel's
1.
Brown bread next batch is Fox Fox next batch.
Is jumped the next batch is quick high.
And hopefully are able to relate this understanding to how we've seen the recurrent neural network and
role.
Remember we have those inputs at sequel's one equals one plus one etc. so the swan steepens to people
Street cetera keep going on.
So again a number of batches shown here.
We have five batches that size is based off of two samples and the number of time steps was five total
time steps.
So we're going be dealing with numeric data in a really simple example.
So let's open up a super notebook and code along it OK so first going to start off of a couple of imports
will say non-pay SNP import sensor flow.
Make sure Isbel import import tensor flow as T.F. then import lib pipe plot as P.L. t in case we need
to actually visualize anything although we may not.
And then Matt plotless in line.
OK so we're going to start off with the constants that we're going to create.
So the constants we first start off with the number of inputs for each example.
So the examples we're going to be showing the number of inputs is going to be two.
And then we also want the number of neurons.
So we'll have just three neurons in that first layer.
Remember we're just going to create a simple layer that only has two time steps worth of information
placed into it.
So now we need placeholders
so unlike before where we just had a simple X placeholder.
We're going to need in our manual recreation a placeholder for each time stamp.
So say x 0 for the data at X time stamped 0.
So that will be a placeholder we'll say that data type is a float 32 and then the actual shape is going
to be done by the number of inputs.
And in this case we just have two inputs.
So we're just going to show two samples then we need another one for time at time 1 so say placeholder
placeholder.
It's also going to flip 32 and same size.
So none by a number of inputs OK.
Now again this is just for man or recreation.
But we actually perform a real recurrent neural network on a real data set.
This won't scale.
Otherwise we'd have to do this for every single time stamp which would be ridiculous now that we have
placeholders.
Let's go ahead and create our variables and it's going to be the same deal here where we have two sets
of variables.
As far as the weights are concerned.
So for the weights we'll say to variable and we'll have random normal and the shape is going to be the
number of inputs by the number of neurons so these are the weights that are attached to that initial
x that's fed in.
So these weights are attached to the specs zero.
We're going to need when we actually get the output of x 0.
Another set of weights attached to it.
We're going to call that w Why.
Because we're going to say the output of that original X is Y.
So it's going to be variable and we'll say it's also random normal
and the shape is going to be not number of inputs now but number of neurons because we have weights
for each neuron because we have the output now and then the number of neurons of the second axis and
then we can have one set of biased terms so we'll say a variable and we'll just initialize these as
zeros.
Again we're not really calculating anything real here if this really simple example we're just dealing
with the concept of recurrent neural networks.
Then we're going to have graphs.
So for our graphs basically the set of operations we're again going to have to do think twice.
So we have our initial output from that first ex-pastor which is going to be hyperbolic tangents as
our activation function here and we'll do a matrix multiplication of X not times w x and then we'll
add the bias term.
So we're essentially kind of repeating back when we performed our really simple neural networks were
doing all these steps or doing them twice.
Now we're using a different activation function here from the very beginning of course using sigmoid.
Now we're using hyperbolic Tandja.
So then on that second output we're going to end up happening and we say why one it's going to be we
passed the activation function to the matrix multiplication of why not times W-why then we're going
to need to add on T.F. matrix multiplication of x1 times w 1 W X I should say plus B.
Ok so what's actually going on here.
Well remember this is our initial output which is just going to be the input X multiply by those initial
those first Waite's we'll call them w x plus the bias term.
And then we pass it through an activation function.
Then at the next timestep we end up taking that output and multiply it by our second set of weights
w a y.
And then once we have that we're going to end up adding that current input.
So memory the current input is x 1 multiplied by those initial sets of weights then plus a biased term.
So again just basically coding out that unrolled recurrent neural network layer then we need to initialises
variables so such a from here is just smooth sailing.
We'll say it is equal to T.F. global variables initialiser and we're going to create our data.
So this is just totally made up data.
It's not going to be really significant here.
So I'm going to basically try to make it as clear as possible how are feeding in these batches.
So we're going to have zero and we're going to say the following will say 0 1 and those of them mentioned
here to three four or five.
So this is all the data at time stamp is equal to zero.
So say this is time stamp 0 and let's create another batch for a time stamp.
One the numbers here kind of meaningless.
So let's say at time stamp 1 everything has gone up by a hundred.
So say array and we're going to essentially copy and paste this and then we're going to add 100 to all
these.
So the next time stamp for all these samples they went up by 100.
Again whether or not that's realistic it doesn't really matter.
1 0 4 1 0 5.
OK so then we can run our session.
So we'll say the following with T.F. that session as s.c.s us I'm going to run in it to actually initialize
the variables and then I'll end up having 2 outputs.
I'll have my output values of why not.
Or why 0.
And then my output values at y one.
So why when output values and then we're going to just run y zero y one or my feed dictionary.
Is it going to be equal to with X not being equal to that X not Bache and then zoom out one level here
x1 x1 Bache OK.
Run that and then relatively quickly you should get the outputs.
Now the outputs here are going to be kind of meaningless but you should get something that looks relatively
like this towards the end you should get a bunch of ones on that second value.
Now whether the negative ones are ones that won't match up exactly what I have here due to the fact
that we initialize things randomly but this is the basic idea for manually recreating a recurrent neural
network that's able to operate on just two time steps.
Now definitely a lot of problems here because this won't scale to larger time serious problems.
If I add something that has 100 times steps that would mean I have to write 100 W's manually 100 output
wise manually and then feed in these manually as well a hundred times.
So that's not really possible a reasonable tensor flow has an API for the neural networks that allows
us to take care of all that under the hood.
But I want you to be aware of what's actually going on when you unroll a recurrent neural network layer
and hopefully actually coding it out man really helped your understanding of that.
OK that's it for this lecture.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'll see at the next lecture.