Welcome back everyone.
Before we actually dive into using tensor Flo's nice API functionality to build recurrent your own that
works for time series analysis.
I want to discuss a few key challenges for analyzing larger time series data sets with recurrent neural
networks and one of those key problems is the vanishing gradients issue.
Back propagation recall goes backwards from the output layer to the input layer and it propagates back
that error gradient for deeper networks.
Issues can arise from back propagation sometimes called vanishing or exploding gradients.
So as you go back to these lower level layers or these front layers closer to the input gradients often
get smaller and eventually causing whites to never change at these lower levels.
The opposite problem can also occur for activation functions who used to rivet that take on larger values.
So that's an exploding gradient problem.
So that can also cause issues.
However it's not as common as the Vanish Ingredion problem so discuss why this problem occurs especially
how it relates to activation functions and how we can fix it.
Then the next lecture will discuss these issues specifically to recurrent neural networks and how we
can use specialized neuron units such as Ellis T.M. and gear you to fix these problems.
But for now let's look at activation functions as the source of this problem and see different activation
functions that can help solve it.
So why do these vanish ingredients actually happen in relation to the activation function choice.
Well if we take a look at some of the typical activation functions the traditional ones that we've been
looking at such as sigmoid activation we have this sort of curvature that goes from 0 to 1.
Remember that the Cygwin activation is just 1 over 1 plus E to the negative x or negative input.
And then there's also a traditional activation function such as the hyperbolic tangent that we've seen
before which essentially has the same shape except it goes from negative one to one and sort of from
zero to 1.
So we have these traditional activation functions and recall that back propagation computes the grievance
by the chain rule.
Now if you have an input going into the sigmoid function or this hyperbolic tangent function and it's
quite a large input then your gradient or your slope coming out of this activation function ends up
being very close to zero.
And it's the same deal if you have really large negative numbers.
So this chain rule of back propagation computed the gradients has the effect of multiplying n of these
small numbers to compute gradients of these lower or front layers in an analyser network.
And basically what that means is the gradients is going to decrease exponentially with N as you get
more and more layers while the front layers train very slowly because you're multiplying these small
numbers over and over again which is just going to lead to smaller smaller numbers.
So one way to solve this is attempting to use different activation functions.
So we've already heard of that activation function that says the rectified linear unit and that's what
it looks like.
Every call here that the rectified linear unit is then not going to saturate positive values.
So unlike the sigmoid function you can see here that even if we have large positive values we don't
end up saturating them with any gradient that's coming close to zero.
Now an issue with this rectified linear unit is that for negative numbers it's always going to output
zero or they're.
So there's another activation function called a leaky rectified linear unit which then has sort of a
negative slope for negative numbers in the input.
There's also other activation functions such as an exponential linear unit which also attempts to solve
some of the problems that lead to vanishing gradients.
So hopefully you get this idea that we can use different activation functions to try to solve this problem
and other solution is to perform batch normalization where your model normalize each batch using the
batched mean and the standard deviation so apart from rational realization Researchers have also used
what they call a gradient clipping where gradients are cut off before reaching a predetermined limit.
So for example you would cut off gradients to always be between negative 1 and 1 so recurrent neural
networks for time series analysis present their own gradient challenges.
So we're going to explore special neuron units specially designed for recurrent neural that works especially
for time series analysis with them to help fix these issues.
So you'll see that the next lecture where we discuss these specialized neuron units.