Welcome everyone to this lecture we're going to be discussing Ellis T.M. and G.R. units or long short
term memory neurons and gated recurrent units.
Many of the solutions we just previously presented for vanishing gradients can also apply to recurrent
neural networks that is using different activation functions applying Bachan formalizations etc..
However because of the length of sequence input such as a really long time series input these could
slow down training a possible solution would just be to shorten the actual sequence you use for prediction.
But then that makes the model worse at predicting longer trends.
So we don't really want to have to sacrifice shortening our inputs in other issue recurrent neural networks
face is that after a while the networks are going to begin to forget those first inputs so we basically
have some sort of memory loss as information is lost at each step going through the recurrent neural
network.
So we really need some sort of long term memory solution for our networks.
This is where the long short term memory cell was created to help address some of these recurrent neural
network issues.
And it was introduced in 1997.
So we're going to go through how an LACMA cell works but quickly recall that a typical recurrent neuron
basically has this sort of structure where we have some input at T-minus one that we have the output
at T minus one and that output is also fed back in a long input at t.
So as a quick note these outputs are often called hidden.
So we can have instead of 2st output at T minus one we can say H T minus one.
And then that also gets fit in the input t that gets passed through some sort of activation function
like the hyperbolic tangent then that gives the output h of t etc..
So when you see HFT just kind of think of that as a typical output of a recurrent neuron cell.
All right so here we can see the entire model of a long short term memory cell.
And I know it can look really complicated if you see it in this format but it's actually not so bad.
When you break it down in parts.
So let's go ahead and first take a look at what's being inputted and what's being outputted here.
We still have those original inputs from a normal recurrent neuron.
Those h of T minus 1 and X of T.
But note here we have this third input and we'll call that the cell state.
So right now we're receiving the cell state at T-minus 1 and then the outputs we again output H A T
and then we also have the cell state.
So that's the current cell state c of T.
So what we're going to end up doing is we're going to take an H of T minus 1 and X of T as well as the
previous cell state.
C of T minus 1 and will output h of T as well as the current cell state.
C of T.
So we're going to do this step by step so the very first step is called the forgets Gates layer.
And this is going to be the first step or we decide what information are we going to forgets or throw
away from the cell state.
So what we end up doing here is the passen h of T minus 1 an X of t and we pass that in after performing
a linear transformation with some weights and biased terms into a sigmoid function.
I remember because this is essentially a sigmoid layer.
It's always going to output a number between 0 and 1 and a 1 is going to represent to keep it and a
zero is going to represent to forget about it or get rid of it.
So if you think back to maybe a language model where we're trying to predict the very next word based
on previous ones a cell state might include the gender of the present subject so that you end up picking
the correct pronoun.
So we end up seeing a new subject.
You want to forget about the gender of the old subject.
So that may be used use for a forget gait later when working with natural language as a sequence.
Now the very next step is to decide what new information are you going to store in the cell state.
So we already decided what we're going to forget.
Now we need to decide what are we actually going to store in the cell state.
Remember that c of T.
So the first part is a sigmoid layer.
And the second part is a hyperbolic tangent layer.
So let's go ahead and tackle that first part that sigmoid layer so that sigmoid layer is called the
input gate layer.
So we'll say that's equal to I have to look for input gate layer.
And again we take an H of T minus 1 and X of t do a linear transformation on it with W of II plus B
of-I we pass that into a sigmoid function and again now we have a bunch of values between 0 and once.
Then the second part of this is the hyperbolic tangent layer.
And that's again going take h of T minus 1 and ex-city do that linear transformation and then pass it
through a hyperbolic tangent.
So that ends up creating a vector of what we call new candidate values.
So that's that c of T with a little tilde above it.
So these are candidate values that could be added to the state and then the next step we're going to
combine these two to create an update to the cell state.
So if we think back to an example of a language model we essentially want to add the gender of the new
subject to the cell state and replace the old one that we've already decided we're forgetting.
So now it's time to update the old cell state to remember the old cell state is c of T minus one and
we eventually want to update that to the new cell say c of T so we can pass that on to the T plus one
state of the cell.
So in the previous steps we already decided what we're going to forget.
And we also already decided what we're going to store.
So now we need to do is just perform or execute these actions.
So what we end up doing is we multiply the old state c of T minus one by f of T.
So we end up forgetting the things that we essentially decided we're going to forget based off that
first sigmoid layer then we're going to add I have t that input gate layer times those candidate values
c of T with tilde on top.
So these are the new Kennedy values and now they're being scaled by how much we decided to update each
state value.
So if we think back to a case of a language model this is where we would actually drop the information
about that old subjects gender and add in new information based off what we decided in the previous
steps.
Now our final decision is going to be what do we output for H of T.
So this output is going to be based off your cells.
That is just a filter diversion.
So it's actually pretty straightforward now we just using H A T minus 1 an X of T.
We passed that after a linear transformation into the sigmoid layer and that's going to decide what
parts of the cell state were going to be outputting.
Then we put the cells stay through the hyperbolic tangent.
So that's going to push the values to be between negative 1 and 1.
And we're going to then multiply it by the output of that sigmoid again so that we only output the parts
we decided to.
So that's what's occurring here in this red line.
Again we're taking H A T minus 1 an X A T doing a linear transformation on it passing it through the
sigmoid And then once we have that output.
So we're going to say that's o of T output of T.
We're then going to multiply by the hyperbolic tangent of the sea of t or that current cell state.
And that gives us h of T.
So that's how an elist cell works.
Now there's different variants on an elist himself.
So there's a variance called the peep hole variance.
So this is actually quite popular.
And the reason for that is because it adds peepholes to all the gates.
So basically it allows these f of t of t and O of t to be able to see the previous cell state.
Or C of T minus 1.
So you can see here now instead of being a function of just h of T minus 1 and X of T.
We're also passing in a C of T minus one.
And then for the output we're also passing in a C T directly.
So that's called LS T.M. with peepholes.
Another variation of the LS tiam cell is called the gated recurrent unit or G or you and this was actually
introduced quite recently around 2014 and what it ends up doing is it actually simplifies things a bit
by combining the forget and input gates into a single what they call update Gates.
And it also merges the cells stay and hidden state.
And it makes a few other changes so this resulting model is actually simpler than standard elist him
models.
And because of that it's been growing increasingly popular over the last few years that it's been around.
So there's actually lots of other slight variations off of this and they're being introduced all the
time.
There was another one called depth gated recurrent neural networks and that was introduced in 2015.
And I mean who knows maybe in a few years we'll see another variation that further improves on this
model.
But the main idea is to understand how elist teams work and that allows you to quickly learn how these
variations work off of it.
Now fortunately we won't actually have to implement all of that logic ourselves tensor flow comes a
really nice year on models built in a nice API.
So it makes it really easy to swap in say in LSD hemself for a GI or use cell.
Essentially it's just a call to tensor flow which is why people use tensor flow in the first place.
So because of this we're going to do now is explore using this tensor flow recurrent neural network
API for time series prediction and generating new time series data.
So we've gone through kind of the more difficult parts of understanding vanishing gradients LACMA cells
gaitered recurrent units.
Now it's time to actually code this out and take it full advantage of tensor Flo's API.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.