Welcome back everyone to this series of lectures.
We're going to be building out a recurrent neural network with tent's flows.
API now that we understand the various possible improvements for recurrent neural networks we're going
to use tensor Flo's built in T.F. thought and functionality to solve time series and sequence problems.
So let's recall our original sequence thought exercise we are given a sequence one two three four five
six.
And now the question arises Can we predict this sequence shifted one time step forward and hopefully
you would end up predicting two three four five six seven.
And if this one two three four five six was part of a larger data set as a treating batch you wouldn't
hopefully be able to confirm that 7 was that correct sequence shift at one time step forward.
But what about this time series.
This is a harder problem for someone to actually solve.
And this is the exact problem we're going to try to give our recurrent neural network.
If you were to actually visualize this time series data you would hopefully just realize that it's a
sign of x.
So we're going to be feeding in a time series that looks like that top time series from 0 all the way
to negative 0.2 eights and then we want our actual model to spit back out a time series shifted over
one timestep.
So then we no longer have that initial 0.
But it's that towards the end it went ahead and predicted 0.6 5.
But keep in mind it's actually trying to generate the entire time series.
So it's not just grabbing the previous values and sticking them in.
It's going to attempt to generate the entire time series shift that over 1.
So you may get small errors throughout that entire time series so we're going to start by creating a
recurrent year all that work that attempts to predict the time series shifted over one unit into the
future then we'll attempt to generate new sequences with a seed series.
So going to first create a simple class to generate sign of x and also grab random batches of sign of
x.
So we'll have some time series data class and it's going to be able to initiate or generate sign effects
as we see here.
But it's also going to be able to then feed in batches of training sets.
So here we can see this training batch.
This is part of sign of x.
So if we were to view it overlapping sign of t it would look something like this.
So basically the batches that we're going to feed into our model are just going to be batches or groupings
of this sign of the algorithm.
So those orange stars represent a single training instance.
So then when we actually train the model and attempt to predict a new time series shifted one step ahead
it's going to look like this.
So the train model you're going to give it a training instance.
So those are those blue points there.
And then you have a target which are the black points.
So that's the target shifted over one time step and then hopefully that model is going to attempt to
predict what that time series is going to look like shifted over one time step and you can see here
that we are off on some points not perfectly centered especially the very first point is pretty way
off but you can see that last point is almost right on top of its target.
So obviously you can still tune this and try to get better predictions but this is the main idea that
we're trying to do.
We give it a time series and have it generate a time series shifted over one time step into the future
afterwards.
We're going to be using the same model to generate much longer time series given a seed series.
So if we take a look at the previous use of the model we gave it a training instance essentially a sequence
in this time series and then asked it to predict a time series shifted over by one timestep.
Now we're going to do later on is give it again a seed series except this time we're going to ask it
to predict way past just one time step forward.
In fact we'll ask it to generate many many times step forward.
So you can see here that red represents the seed series given in this case we just fed it straight zeros
and then it attempts to generate a sign you saw it a wave and you could see it's pretty cool.
That is generating this just based off of what it knows from learning about the sign of x function.
And here you can see it's a bit of a sloppy sinusoidal wave and it only goes from negatives or 0.6 to
0.4 and that's because you're feeding it straight zeros as it seed series.
However if you were to actually feed it sign of x in the very beginning so we feed it that red portion
you can see that it predicts a something much closer to sign of x.
All right let's get started in the next lecture will open up a Jupiter note book and start by creating
the time series data class.