Welcome everyone.
Now it's time to actually create the recurrent neural network with tensor flow.
I'll start off with a couple of imports.
Will first important up-I as N.P. then will import sensor flow as T.F. then import that plot lib pipe
plot as PBT pipe plot and then some using Joop or notebook will say at play live in line.
OK now the next step is to actually create a class that will to both initialize the data and also send
batches of the data back.
Right now the next step is to create a class and this class is going to both be able to create the data
and generate batches to send back.
So will do the following.
Will say class time series data and this is just a normal class and it's going to have an in it method
which takes itself and we're going to start it off with the number of points we want to create and then
it's going to have an x min and an X max so let's go ahead and create a couple of attributes here.
Please say X-Men is equal to the X-Men provided same for X max
then all we're gonna do is the same thing for the number of points number of points and then we're also
going to define an attribute called resolution which is just how fine of a resolution are we actually
creating and we can easily calculate that by either the self-taught X Max or the actual x Maxxis provided.
So to kind of save some typing we'll just say X Max minus X-Men divided by the number of points then
will create X data and x data is going to be linearly spaced points using pi from x men to X Max and
we want the number of points provided and then we'll say self-taught.
Why true is equal to the sign self-taught ex-state of.
OK so do we actually have here.
Well so far we have this time series class that takes in the number of points wanted and the x men and
X max and it ends up doing is it creates a bunch of attributes to store some information.
First off those three provided them also.
The resolution then the x data.
So that's a number of linearly spaced points from X-Men.
Tx max and then also white true or white True's just defined as passing in this x data through the number
pi sine function that I'm also going to add in a convenience method called ret.
True for return true and this takes in any series of x values and it's going to return and sign X series
and that's going to be useful for comparing data that we don't have.
So for example if I wanted to know what the true value of any sign of the number 3 was I could then
call this method return true and it will return back and the sign of whatever series I happened to pass
in.
So this is more of just convenience.
Well right now the next method we need to create is going to be actually to generate batches of the
data.
So I'll say the next batch is going to be taking in self and then it's also going to take in the batch
size wanted and then the number of steps and I'm also going to add in this parameter which will see
later what it's for.
But it's called The Return batched time series and I'm going to set it by default equal to false and
as I mentioned we'll see that later on.
So let me comment out the steps that we need to do.
First off we need to grab a random starting point for a well I should say for each batch of data once
I have that I need to convert to be on the actual time series then I'm going to create a batch time
series on the X-axis and then I will create the y data for the time series X axis from previous that
then I'm just going to be formatting it for the recurrent neural network.
OK so let's actually do all this.
So I want to grab a random starting point.
So I was going to say random start as equal to any random Rand and I get a pass in the batch size and
one sort of Moran is just random values in a given shape.
So we'll see later on how we're actually gonna work with that.
So I need to convert this to actually be on the time series because right now this is just some random
number.
I don't know whether or not it's on the time series.
So I'll create another value called Time series start.
And that's going to be equal to random star and I'm going to multiply that by the following.
We're going to multiply that by the x Max minus leps the X-Men minus the number of steps times soft
resolution.
And that's going to basically convert this random star to be somewhere on the actual time series that
we defined earlier.
Because notice here I'm just taking the maximum value then subtracting the minimum value.
So now I have my points that are actually on that time series and then I'm going to subtract the number
of steps multiplied by the resolution.
And that's going to convert this random star to be somewhere in that time series.
Then I need to create a batch time series on the X-axis.
So that's actually a lot easier.
I just say Bache time series.
And then what I'm going to do is say equal to that starting point we just created and then I'm going
to add and points to it we'll say arr. 0 0 2 the number of steps asked for and we'll say plus 1 and
then we're going to multiply that by self-taught resolution so that this has the same resolution as
the points here.
OK then I need to create y data for this.
So this is actually an easier
sign batch time series.
OK.
So let's quickly review what we just did.
First off we essentially create a random starting point.
However we don't know whether or not this random starting point is on the actual time series data because
the time series data was first the final in the initialize this with an X Men in X max and a number
of points.
So we then convert this random start to be on the time series and we do that by multiplying that random
start with the result of the maximum value minus the minimum value minus the number of steps times the
resolution.
And that gives you a starting point on the time series then we need to actually create the x axis batch
of time series information.
So that ends up being that starting point we just decided plus 0 up 2 steps plus 1.
I remember steps is defined right here and then we multiply that by the resolution.
So it's going to be basically this resolution times this arrangement and then we have t start plus these
points and that's our Bachche time series then to convert that to y data.
It's actually quite easy it's just taking the sign of it so that it matches up with our actual function.
Now for formatting for the recurrent neural network it is a little trickier for you to say the following.
I'll say if return Bache TS going to return something.
I was going to comment that out right now because we'll get to that in just a second.
Else I'm going to return and this is what I'm going to do.
I'm going to return why batch
everything along the rows and then along the columns everything up to minus one here and then I'm going
to reshape this to be negative 1 steps 1.
So that's going to be the first item in this tuple that I return back and then I'm going to have y batch
everything along the rows and then one colon that are going to say reshape them is going to be negative
one staps one.
Let me zoom out real quick.
So recall that formatting or data was really important when we were working with the manual or creation
of a recurrent neural network.
And that's essentially what this reshape is doing here.
And that is the batches here.
So we have one batch that's going to represent the time series and this batch which represents the time
series shifted over by one step into the future.
That way we can then train on this data.
So I'm going to then copy this and I will return the same thing here except then I'll have a third item
which is called Bache underscore.
So that's if I actually also want the x axis information which is what this essential boolean value
is for.
OK.
So let's go ahead and quickly review what we did and then we're going to plot this out just so we can
visualize what we actually did.
But basically I had this class called time series data and when you call it you're going to provide
it the number of points you want and the X minimum value you want them on and the X max of all you want
them on.
So it's good to return let's say 50 points between 0 and 1 it's going to set up all its attributes.
Calculate the resolution of what you just asked for and then create the X data and then create the true
data which in our case we're just using the sine function as our white true.
Then we have a convenience method here that for any x series it returns the sign of it.
Then we have our next batch method.
This one is a little more complicated but when you break it down into steps it's not so bad.
We create some random starting point.
We need to make sure that random starting point is on the time series.
So we did this conversion using the X Max X-Men and resolution values.
Then once we have that time series starting point we're going to add on the number of steps asked four
times the resolution so that now has that information so that that's time series then we're going to
create the y values associated with that batch TS which is just passing batched TS into sign here.
Then I have two options if I want to return the Y batch information along with the actual x axis values
that it belongs to are axis values depending on you think about it.
Then I have the time series the time series shifted over by one step and then batched yes.
Otherwise if I just want these two batches then I just return these two tuples.
So again basically here we have this time series and then this time series shifted over by one timestep.
OK so now that we have that let's go ahead and create some data so we can actually visualize what's
happening here.
So we'll say TSA data is equal to time series data.
And let's say I want 250 points between 0 and 10.
So then I'm going to say Piazzi plots plot this time series data and out of this time series data object.
If I hit tab here notice I have all these nice attributes.
So I'm going to plot the X data versus Y true.
And there we have it.
We have our X data versus Y true which is just sign of x.
So that's all we did so far by creating this time series data.
So let's say I want each of my random batches to have 30 steps in it.
So I'll say a number of times that is equal to 30.
So a number of steps in batch.
And we're also going to use this for prediction steps into the future later on.
So I'm going to say why one white two Ts is equal to ts data and then called the next batch.
And I want if we come up here.
What we're going to do.
I'm going to ask for just batch size to be one.
And then I'm also going to ask for steps to be equal to the number of times that we're here.
So I want 30 steps.
I just want one batch and then I'm also going to ask for the Bache time series.
Basically that X data for our plot.
So going to say give me one batch of 30 samples and true.
I do want this time series data that way I can plot it later on since we're not going to use it.
We're going to have the option to just not pass in that parameter that I'm going to say VLT plot.
And well let's look at time series right now if we look at ts.
It's in this array right here where it's a nested array.
So if you take a look at the shape it's one by 31.
So I need to flatten this in order to actually plot it.
So if I flatten it out now I get this as a single one D-Rays if I take a look at the shape.
Now it's just 31 points.
So that's what map plot live needs.
So we're going to be using that.
So I'll say Piazzi the plot and then I'm also going to get white too and white is the same deal and
to flatten it and then I want an asterix here to be the actual points.
Now I'm going to get an error here if I just run this.
And the reason is because hey it's going to say Did I mention don't match up.
So it says one of these is 31.
And one of these is 30 and that makes sense because remember why one in y2 here.
As far as these training batches are concerned they're shifted over one step from each other so they're
each missing a whole step from the 31 possible points.
So what we're going to do then is for it to yes we're just going to say indexing starting from 1 all
the way to the end and then when we plot it we see we have these points right here.
Now because this is randomly chosen You're not going to get the same points I do.
So if I run this again so ask for another batch.
You'll notice I get a different part of that sinusoidal wave.
So keep that in mind every time you run this you're going to be getting different parts of the sign
as your batch.
If you're getting the same part every time then something is wrong.
You're not actually choosing random values here.
So that's a good indicator of something's wrong.
If you keep running these cells you should be constantly getting different segments of the sinewave.
OK so now let's play this out.
On top of our original sinewave so I'll say Piazzi plots TS data X data versus TS data y true and we'll
say we'll get the label to be sign up to you OK.
So remember that's just this plot right here.
And if I say at the very end the legend that I end up seeing sign of T.
So now let's go ahead and plot these random points that we just made.
So that little batch.
So I'll say the following will say Piazzi plot.
And I'm going to take T.S. flatten that I can just copy this right here.
He is fighting to flatten and then the Strix So let's grab that and then we're going to say label is
equal to single training instance
run that and you can see here there's a single training instance.
And if this legend is kind of blocking your view you can use a little peel tea.
Well at the very end of the cell you can use Piazzi Titely run that and that shift shifted over and
nothing's blocking anymore.
All right.
So if you were to keep running this you should constantly be getting new points.
So now look where this curve is.
So if I run this again I now see I grabbed.
This is my batch.
So what we're going to be doing is randomly grabbing two batches and they're shifted over from one another
which is why when we came back up here we ended up saying steps plus one here.
So that way when I asked for 31 each of these batches has 30 themselves.
OK.
So that's it for the data.
Well we're now going to show you is the training instance and what we're actually trying to predict.
So remember we are trying to predict a time series shifted over by one timestep.
So let me visualize that real quick.
So we're going to say training data.
What this actually looks like.
So let me create a training instance will say and PLN space five to well say five plus Test Data resolution
and we'll have this be.
Well have this resolution be multiplied by the number of times that's wanted plus 1.
And then the second parameter here in space is going to be the number of times that's a number of times
that's plus 1.
So what does this training instance actually look like.
It's just a bunch of values here.
So then what we're going to do is say PLCC and we'll say title
training instance.
So this is the actual data we're going to be feeding in our model and we're training it and I'm going
to plot out the training instance called negative 1 and then test data.
I'm going to ask to return the true values.
So that's why we have that convenience method there.
Train instance colon negative 1.
And then what we're going to say here is we'll have these b b zero or B.
Oh excuse me.
So it's going to be a little black thoughts and we're going to say marker size.
This is just for visualization purposes now.
Make these marks eyes 15 and the alpha is going to be 0.5 and let's give this a label of instance.
OK so that's our training instances go ahead and plot it out.
OK.
So that's actually blue not black Sorry black is OK.
So here's our training instance.
So we just created a training instance so again we just linearly spaced from five to five plus the data
resolution here.
So 5 up to 6.2 So 30 times steps forward from five.
Then we have Kilty training instance and we're plotting out this training instance.
All right.
So then we're going to want to predict one time step ahead of this so we're going to predict an entire
series shifted over by one step.
So I'm going to essentially mimic that by doing the following.
We'll say train instance one colon now and then we'll say TSA data return true of train instance one
colon and then very similar thing here will say oh for a black thought will make this market size a
little smaller.
You can change the colors if you want.
And those say labels equal to target.
OK so what is actually happening here.
Let me pass in the legend so we can see it.
Kilty Legin.
So I have my instance and I have my target.
So the blue is what is going to be the training here.
And then the black is the actual target.
So essentially the model is asked given these blue points can you generate these black points and you
should imagine that it's relatively easy to generate the points that should be exactly the same as the
points that you were fed.
The harder one is this point right here because technically you weren't given any data at that particular
x.
Now as you train the model you'll see that later on is actually not super simple to get the points that
you were actually given technically the correct answer to because of the way the recurrent neurons actually
work but this is the general idea given these blue points as a series can you generate these black points
in the series.
So shifted over one time step and that is the whole purpose of our model.
So coming up in the next lecture we're going to end up creating their model and running some more current
neural networks and then running the session.
Okay thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.