Welcome back everyone.
We're right where we left off last time.
Previously in this Jupiter note book we had already created our data and this is a class that's able
to give us batches of a new social wave and you go ahead and provide the minimum value of the maximum
value and the number of points you want.
In between those two an hour we're going to do is actually create the model and the first thing to do
is just have a cell reset the default graph.
This technically shouldn't be necessary in this particular note but because I haven't actually created
that graph yet.
But in my personal experience I was encountering some bugs because I was using a graphical processing
unit AGP that is and I had to keep resetting of the default graph every time I ran my session.
So getting any issues.
Just go ahead and use the provided notebook and then say kernel restart and run it all and it should
work for you.
So I'm going to keep that in mind as I continue on coding this out.
So up next I'm going to create just some constants.
So first off we'll say the number of inputs is equal to 1 because we basically just have one feature
in this time series.
Given some value x what is the value y.
So we have a number of inputs 1 and then we can also ask how many neurons we want in our layer.
So this is definitely something you can play around with.
We'll just go ahead and say we want 100 neurons in our la and then I'm going to just ask for one output
the predicted time series so we'll say the number of outputs wanted is just one.
And then we're going to define a learning rate variable.
Again this is something in play around with.
We'll start off with 0.00 0 1.
So pretty slow learning right there.
And then the number of training iterations we want to go through again and other value you can play
around with.
So I'll say a number of train iterations.
Make sure it's an underscore is equal to 2000.
So we'll have run through 2000 steps and then our actual batch size we're just going to fit in one match
at a time.
OK so now let's get back to kind of our classic format.
So we need some placeholders.
So the placeholders we need are x.
So it's going to be T.F. placeholder and that's going to be floating point 32 and then we're going to
pasan none because it's going to be defined by the batch size than the number of time steps by the number
of inputs.
And that's why it's just going to be this almost the same thing.
Placeholder to float 32.
And again none because that's the best size for that dimension number of times steps that's going to
be the same except this time y is going to be number outputs along that dimension.
The third dimension there.
So now we have placeholders X and Y.
All right.
Now the next step is to actually create the recurrent neural network cell layer.
You have a lot of options here.
You have things like basic RNA and cells basic LACMA cells multiply RNA and cells multiply Ellis tamps
cells.
But we're going to deal three very basic art and cell and see how those results are.
So we'll say our cell.
So let me actually just comment this first.
It will say we are not right right now creating the recurrent neural network so layer and zoom in one
more level here so it's clear.
So are created the cell layer and I'm going to say cell is equal to T.F. contrib.
Thoughts are.
And and and then off of this you should see tons of options so you have a stem cell Arnon cell etc.
The gated recurrent unit's cell.
So you have tons and tons of options.
A lot of these we didn't talk about but the one we did talk about is just a basic recurrent neural network
cell.
So for this guy to give it the number of units you want and the activation function.
So you don't need to actually specify reuseable Gisli that is the default none but the number of units
we want in this basic current year network cell will have that be the number of neurons.
It's essentially a layer of recurrent neural network cells and then we're going to say the activation
function will use Well go ahead and use T.F. and then we'll use a rectified linear activation unit.
Now there's an issue of just using this basic recurrent year that work cell because the way we set this
up remember that we're really just predicting one output here.
We just want one time series output.
If you take a look at the number of neurons we're using it's 100.
So we don't want to 100 outputs.
So the way we can actually project this just to be one is using output projection wrapper.
So I'm gonna end up wrapping this whole thing.
So then I will say cell is equal to T.F. contrib.
R n n.
And I'm going to call output projection wrapper and then that's going to take in that previous cell
and then it's going to ask for an output size and the output size you want is just a number of outputs
which in our case is just one time series output.
OK so we'll go ahead and run that.
And in fact just to make sure I don't get any confusion with this I'll go ahead and wrap this whole
thing.
Whoops.
So let's take this whole guy cut it and just inject it in here.
That way don't have two variables there.
And then set this equal to the following.
So let me make this simple but lines it's a little clear.
It's actually happening here.
So all I'm doing is taking that first basic recurrent neural that works well has 100 neurons that layer
activation function as a rectified linear unit and then and then wrap it to the output projection wrapper.
So I just get one output.
All right.
And then later on you can replace this with elist himself and see the differences etc..
Or he can do multiday RNA and cells and play around with that.
Now the next step is to actually get the outputs and the states of these basic RNA and cells.
So the way we can do this is using a convenience function that's NCF to an end and it's the dynamic
are.
And so it just creates a recurrent neural network specified by the actual cell that we just created
appear that cell.
And what you can do is it's essentially going to automatically output both the outputs and the states
of these cells.
So it performs a dynamic unrolling of the inputs that basically just means it's using a while loop operation
to run over the cell the appropriate number of times.
So we're going to go ahead and say TFT and end that dynamic and then we're going to pass in that cell
we just created and the next thing we're going to pasan are the actual x data points here.
So that's the placeholder.
And then finally we need to specify the type it is or say the type is equal to to float 32 OK and then
that's going to return outputs.
OK so that's the dynamic Arnon call.
And then finally we need a last function in an optimizer.
We're almost ready to start our session so we're going to go ahead and use mean square error as our
last function.
So for mean square error it's pretty straightforward.
We just are going to say T.F. reduce mean T.F. square of our outputs minus the true value which in this
case if we come back up here it's a placeholder y so all we're doing is taking the mean square error.
So square mean mean square.
Next we need to create the optimizer.
So we'll say optimizer is T.F. train and we'll use an atom optimizer for this and we'll set the learning
rates equal to the learning what we described above and offer this we're going to say train is equal
to optimizer that minimize the loss.
This is we them before finally we want to create in it so we can initialize the variables say global
boops global variables initializer and now it's time to run a session.
So since I am using AGP for this because it's going to run a little faster for me there is a slight
bug that sometimes occurs where all the GPS memory gets taken and you'll get a little crash.
So I'm going to copy and paste one line here from the notes.
If you're using C.P you don't need to use this but it's you.
Scuse me T.F. GPU options and it's basically just telling it how much of my cheap memory I'm allowed
to use.
So I'll go ahead and do this up to 85 percent my GP whose memory is allowed again for using c.p.
You don't need to run this.
They'll just take you a little longer if you're using GPS you you may not get this error and you may
not need to provide this.
It just happened to be on my specific Nvidia card.
I was getting error and hopefully to actually fix this bug because I don't believe it was actually any
fault of the tensor code.
It was just some bug deeper intenser float 1.3 here and then finally I'm going to create a saver function
or really an instance of T.F. train saver and that's going to allow me to be able to save my model.
So now we can save our models and use them again later we'll say with T.F. session and I'm going to
give the parameter we haven't actually provided parameters before but this pre-merge just for the GPU
you can go in and skip it if you're not using sheepy you will say T.F. config Kroto and say GPU options.
Is it cool to GPU options then we'll say as session go into say run and it's then I'll do the following.
I'll say for every iteration in a range the number of training iterations I will do the following.
I will get X batch and y batch and that's going to be my test data set and then I'm going to call next
batch off for that can it pass in that batch size that it defined earlier along with the number of times
steps then I'm going to actually run the trainer and I'll provide a feed dictionary.
Let me scroll down a little bit here.
I'll provide a feed dictionary of values where X is just the x batch and Y is just the Y that each Hopefully
now this feels pretty familiar.
And then let's go ahead and calculate our accuracy every 100 steps and report back.
Or I mean squared error we'll say if iteration mod 100 is equal to zero.
Just as we've done before we'll calculate mean squared error.
So say loss evil and I'll write a feed dictionary here.
Is equal to x.
Wups next batch why y batch isn't calculating loss on this training set not on some separate testing
set.
And then we'll say iteration and let's go ahead and say just in quotes will say we'll put a tab there.
So that's just tapping.
They'll say mean square error.
And they will say MSE OK so I still print function there.
And then finally once this is all done I'm going to save my model so I call saver that save.
And then I provide the session and then I provide a file path where I want the model to be saved so
when I say dot slash aren't in time series model and then I'll say Code along.
So I would recommend you add some sort of unique identifier here because I did save a model and it provided
for you with the zip file.
So don't overwrite that model.
Otherwise you have to download the zip again.
So let me run this and hopefully have no errors.
And there we go.
So now I can see every 100 steps so mine is running pretty fast because I'm using GPS to use maybe running
a little slower.
But what I'm going to do now is fast forward in time until these 2000 steps are then running OK.
I just jumped forward in time that took a total of about 10 to 15 seconds for me.
So now we're going to do is attempt to predict the time series or one step into the future.
So how do we do that.
Well we're going to run another session.
We'll say with T.F. session as SPSS and Lotusphere And again this is just kind of a quirk of tent's
flows maybe GPs bugs.
I didn't actually have to provide the GPU configuration here.
I don't know why that is.
Basically it was just a bug for this particular session here.
Technically you shouldn't have to ever provide these options and have it crash.
But that was just the case for me.
Hopefully that's a bug that's fixed by now.
OK then I'm going to say Savir restore.
And I'm going to restore that model I just saved.
So let me copy and paste the file path here and again you can basically put whatever file path you want.
I would again suggest that you don't overwrite the model that's saved with the actual zip file.
So then I'm going to do the following.
I'll say ex-New is equal to any peace sign I get to say NPR-A of the tree and we created earlier in
the lecture Colon's negative one.
And then I'm going to reshape this to make sure it actually matches the shape of the training it expects
that's going to be negative one number of times.
That's number of inputs.
Zoom out one level here.
And then we're going to say why prediction is equal to session run outputs.
And then we're going to say feed dictionary is equal to x and then we'll say ex-New OK you run that
should run really fast because you're essentially just doing one quick prediction here and now it's
time to plot it out and see how he performs.
So say Piazzi title is testing the model.
So I'm first going to do the actual training instance all say training instance.
And then after that we'll say target to predict that's essentially the correct test of values which
are easy enough.
That's just Pete that sign of the training data.
And then the models actual prediction.
So let's go ahead and do this now.
So first thing I say till Kielty plot or grab the training instance.
Colin too negative one than say peace sign of same thing train instance colon negative one and we'll
go ahead and have this be a blue marker so I'll say be 0 for blue marker and she's the same size as
before.
And again you can go ahead and choose any markers any colors you want here then to create an alpha 0.5.
It's a little more see through.
And more importantly let's give this label training instance.
Now the target to predict.
And I say Piazzi plot again training instance.
So now this is going to be time series shifted one into the future.
So I'll say one colon and then we'll see any sign train instance one colon here and then this is going
to be black will say marker size is equal to 10 and then we'll say label is target
and then finally our markets or models predictions will appeal to.
Train instance one colon then we're going to say why prediction zero colon zero.
And then let's say let's have this be read thought so say our thoughts are period they're marker signs
we'll have this be turns a little smaller and the label is going to be predictions.
And let's go ahead and label the x axis x axis labels just going to be time we'll say Piazzi legend
and that is called Pill teeth tightly.
All right.
So let's here we did.
So we're testing our model we can see in the beginning we're actually not very good at predicting.
But as we get further and further along the time series we're actually lining up with our target.
So again the blue points here those are the points we trained on.
And then I would fit in the values here for X and I said go ahead and predict one time series into the
future for me and the correct values are these and black that it should have been hitting.
You can see that they basically overlap perfectly with blue as they should.
And then these red points are what our model actually predicted.
So we're being a little bit off in the very beginning.
And then as we continue along we're getting closer and closer there.
Let's go ahead and see if swapping out the cell type will improve performance instead of a basic Arnett's
cell.
We'll use that gated recurrent unit that we talked about earlier.
And since we're using that unit we can also decrease the learning rate a little bit.
So we'll say 0.00 one and let's see how that does.
Again you can play around to learning rate number of iterations even further.
You can reduce the learning rate more give more iterations etc. but now I'm going to say kernel restart
and run all and then while that's running I'm going to go ahead and jump forward in time and see how
that model performed.
All right so now that that's finished training we can see that overall our predictions are essentially
a little higher than our actual target value.
But you can see that those earlier inputs are now no longer being lost.
So we're actually the behavior of this entire time series is a lot smoother.
Even though the values seem to be shifted up a little higher than they should be off the target we're
getting decent behavior towards the beginning of that time series as would be expected using those gaited
recurrent units.
OK.
So I definitely encourage you to come back up here and play around a lot with different cell types as
well as your learning rate and number of iterations.
See if making a slower or faster learning really helps.
You can even play around the number of neurons.
Cetera.
All right.
Thanks everyone and we'll see you at the next lecture.
We're actually going to generate completely new sequences not just one time step ahead.
I'll see you there.