Welcome back everyone.
In this third part of our Arnon with tensor Flo's lecture series we're going to be practicing generating
a new sequence So previously we created a time series sequence that shifted just one time step over.
Now let's go ahead and generate a completely brand new sequence.
So we're going do the following.
We'll say with T.F. session as SPSS we're going to say Savir all restore the model I say.
So session and then go ahead and find it.
So this one I believe is called R and in time series model code along and is going to pass that and
right there and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to first seed it with just a bunch of zeros and
let's see what happens.
So I'll say zero sequence seed.
Let's zoom in on level here.
Scroll down a little bit.
So zero sequence seed that's going to be equal to zero point zero.
For i in range I will say a number of time steps.
So 30 right there.
And then I'm going to do the following.
I'll say for iteration in the range of the length of TS data X data Minus the number of times that it's
going to perform the following will say X Bachche is equal to an array of zero sequence Seeta and only
go from a negative number of time steps all the way to the end and then going to reshape this to be
in the proper format for r r n n which is going to be one number of time loops one underscore number
of times steps comma 1 and then we need our Y prediction or should I say white generated and that's
going to be to session run and we'll run the outputs where the feed dictionary is just equal to x the
X that we just created there.
And then finally it will say zero.
Sequence seed.
And I'm going to pen those y prediction values 0 negative 1 0.
So I need to index that using pi indexing so I'm in zoom out here.
So again all we're doing is we're going to create this zero sequence scene.
So that's just going to be 30 zeros or however many number of times that we have.
And then for iteration in the range of the length of time series X data Minus the number of times steps
what are going to do is generate an X batch.
So that's going to be passing in the zero sequence array going backwards a negative number of time steps
then go all the way to the end that I you to reshape this for the recurrent neural network.
So anyone come the number of times that's one.
Then I have my prediction.
So I'm just running the outputs passing in that feed dictionary of the next batch I just created up
here.
And then finally I need to append those new values to Mizer a sequence seed.
So at the very end I should have 30 zeros and then the generated values so let's go ahead and run that
and plot it out.
We'll say PBT plot data X data versus zero sequence seed.
And we'll go ahead and have this be a blue line and then also going to plot theist data X data and this
is only going to be for the number of time steps.
So a number of times steps that are going to plot zero sequence seed number of time steps and then finally
will have this be a red line hopes are what make this a little thicker.
Just so we can see it.
So line with is equal to three and it's going to give this an X label of time loops and we'll have wild
label be just white.
So this first one right here that's putting in the entire time series and the second one is going to
be a red line in the case.
The first seed value OK is when we take a look at our results here.
We're definitely providing something that looks sinusoidal but it ends up generating from let's say
negative 0.5 to 1.
So it's not exactly generating a pure sine wave but it's definitely learned that sort of behavior.
So let's go ahead and seat it with something that is the true first sign value.
And let's see how it does with that.
So we'll end up doing is the following.
I'm going to copy this right here.
And paste that and then we'll say time series come along and we're going to see this with the actual
values.
So instead of a zero sequence seat what I'm going to do here is say training instance is going to be
equal to a list of TS data y true values.
And we're just going to take 30 points there.
So then instead of the length of test data the X data minus the number of times steps when I get in
that doing just say the length of the train instance that I just created that X Bache instead of being
zero sequence seed is going to be that training instance instance.
There we go.
And then that needs to have the same dimensions so that reshape is fine as well.
So this line stays the same.
And then instead of appending it to zero sequence c I'm going to append that to the tree instance.
There we go.
So now we're going to run that.
All right so let's plot this out and then scroll back up here and I'm going to copy this and replace
what's necessary.
So instead of saying X data with zero sequence seed.
Now since I actually have a real training instance I could just say TSC data versus Y true.
And then when I got to end up doing is saying the X data X data is fine but replaced this zero sequence
seed with the training instance OK.
That's going to have a saying that mentions.
And let's run this and we can see here.
Now we're predicting pretty much inexact sinusoidal wave.
Now these results won't be perfectly equal to sign of X but they're going to be pretty darn close because
our seed was much better.
Now keep in mind sometimes you'll get weird exponential values especially for the first one.
You may get something that just looks flat and then suddenly explodes.
If that happens to you then usually a good fix for it is just running everything again because sometimes
the graphs session wasn't saved properly and either reset the default graph.
So in that case if you ever get that urge just come over here to colonel and say restart and run all
and make sure you use the provided notebook.
It's really easy to get a typo in here or mess up a line or just mix up the graphs.
So again always use the provided notebook because there's lots of ways to just make small typos and
mess this up.
All right so I hope you enjoyed this lecture series.
I think this last part is really one of the most interesting aspects of our current neural networks
the ability to just completely generate new sequences based off what it's seen before.
And what's really cool is the pinning on the seat value you make it something unique and different.
So you can imagine that if we were trying to generate something like music or we had words we could
give it certain seeds and it would generate a unique instance that we've actually never seen before.
So this is the cool way you could use recurrent neural that works to maybe journey new pieces of music
or something similar to that.
All right.
Hope you enjoyed that.
Coming up next it's going to be an exercise that allows you to walk through this for a time series.
Thanks.
And I'll see you at the next lecture.