Welcome everyone to the solutions lecture for the time series exercise.
Let's hop over to the exercise notebook and start coding along the solutions.
OK here I am at the notebook.
First thing to do is import some pie and then we're also going to need to import Pandurs to work with
that CXXVI file and then we'll do some visualization later on.
Let's say I live as tea and then map plot lib in line OK.
So we're going to use pandas to read and to see as we file.
So I going to say milk is equal to p the read C S V.
And then we'll say monthly milk production.
So just as an untapped autocomplete there and then I'm also going to say that the index column is equal
to month.
So check out the head of the data frame it should look something like that.
And then we're going to do next is set the index.
So we'll do the following basically just copy and paste that line.
So milk index.
Copy that run that and then I'm also going to plot out the time series data.
So that's actually really easy only if you say milk dot plot and it should create this milk production
plot automatically for you.
And this happens automatically because of the index being a date time index.
So Pan those again really convenient to use there.
Now it's time for the train to split.
So remember we want to actually have the last 12 months be the tail end of our test set.
So we're going to do is if we say milk that info you'll notice I have a hundred and sixty eight rows.
So what I'm going to do is say my training set is equal to milk dot head.
And then I'm going to say essentially 168 minus 12 Well that's equal to 156.
So I'll put in 156 here and then I want the test set to be the talents all say milk tail last 12 months
and that's a really easy way.
You could also use I Alosi or I look with some slicing to do the same tasks but head and tail just makes
it really easy.
So in other ever trainset those first months or first years and the tail is just the last year we want
to scale the data.
So what we're going to do here now say from as Kaylor pre-processing import min max scaler are going
to create an instance of the scaler will say minimax scaler and then I will say train scaled and then
I'm going to do perform a transform only all the training set and then I'm going to say test scaled
and I'll say scaler transform and this is all the test set.
So now we've been able to successfully scale our data.
Remember we only want to fit it to the training set if we fit it to the entire set then we're assuming
we'll know about future behavior when scaling.
So we only want to do the fit transform on the training and then just transform on the test.
Up next is this batch function.
So let's go ahead and create it.
It's actually not so bad.
It's really similar to what we did during the lectures.
We create some random starting point.
So I'm going to say N.P. ran them and I'm going to choose some random integer between 0 and the length
of the training data that's being passed then.
So that's this training data appear.
So I will say training data and then I'm also going to subtract the number of steps.
So that's essentially what these instructions are trying to tell you.
So use this.
We ran them that ran that to set a random starting point index for the batch.
Remember that each batch needs to have the same number of steps in it.
So that means you should limit the starting point to zero.
Or excuse me the starting point to length of data minus steps which is going to be length for training
data mining steps.
Okay.
So there is our starting point.
Step two is to create a y data for this all say why batch is equal to and pray you trick taking that
training data and then say go from Branch start all the way to Rand start plus the number of steps plus
1 and then we just need to reshape this to be shapes of one wups steps plus one.
So again basically what the comment that steps we're telling you to do.
Then finally we just need to return the batches so I get return y batch.
All those rows and then will say one step backwards there reshape negative one steps one and then will
also return.
Why batch and essentially all the rows except one of say one to the verion here and then we'll reshape
that to be negative 1 steps 1 OK.
So now we have our next batch function.
It's time to actually set up the recurrent neural network model.
So the first thing you need to do is say import sensor flow as T.F. and then up next we have the constants.
So let's go ahead and fill these all out.
So essentially just use the ones that provided or play around with them totally OK as well.
The number of inputs.
Well that's just going to be one feature which essentially is the time series so that stays is one than
the number of time steps.
So the number of steps in each batch will go in limit that to just 12.
Since we're dealing with monthly data so a number of time steps it's going to be 12 and then the number
of neurons will go ahead and just say 100 just like we did last time during the lectures.
Again a value can easily play around with a number of outputs.
Are you going to create one sequence all number of up it's going to be one.
Then we have a learning rates.
Then we go ahead and choose a bit of a faster learning rate.
So like 0.03 And then number of training iterations we'll say let me scroll down here just a little
bit number of training iterations going to set that equal to 4000.
Again another valley you can play with and then the batch size will go ahead and just feed in one at
a time.
So now we can create placeholders for x and y.
So I'll say X is T.F. placeholder and it's going to be float 32 and then the shape will say none because
that's defined by the bat size.
And then we have the number of time steps so 12.
And then by the number of inputs and that's going to be almost the same thing for why except instead
of number of inputs that's going to be number of outputs
There we go.
So now we have X and Y are placeholders there.
It's time to create the recurrent neural network where you have a lot of stuff you can play around with
here.
So I'll just do the basic one will say T.F. contrib Arnon n ill say output projection mapper because
that's going to allow us to make up their go up prediction mapper or output projection rapper excuse
me because that's going to allow us to basically just get one output back and then I'm going to wrap
the T.F. contrib Arnon and we'll use a basic LACMA cell
where the number of units is going to be equal to the number of neurons.
That's just the 100 the activation that's going to be equal to T.F. and rectified linier act rectified
linear unit and then we have the output size that's going to be set up that size is equal to the number
of outputs.
In this case just one.
So let's run that.
Looks like I got my column mixed up.
So output size that goes into the upper projection wrapper.
There we go.
OK.
So we have our output projection wrapper that's outputting this just to be 1 output and that's wrapping
this basic elist.
So with a 100 year odds so that we don't get 100 outputs Instead we just have the output protection
wrapper sending just one output.
Next we want to pass in the cells variable into T.F. and in dynamic Arnon.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we get back outputs and states just like we did in lecture with CTF and then we have a dynamic Arnon
we have a cell X that placeholder.
And we also specify the data type so data type is going to be as always Tier 3 to next we have the last
function and the optimizer.
So this is essentially same as the lectures will say to reduce mean staff reduce mean and then TFA squares
is the means quarter the product that outputs minus Y.
That true placeholder.
And then let's go ahead and create our optimizer will use the atom optimizer and we'll set its learning
right to be the learning rate with the above.
And then we want to set train equal to optimizer and we want the optimizer to end up minimizing or say
minimize loss that we need to initialize the global variables so we'll see it is equal to T.F. global
variables initialiser.
And then finally I want to create an instance of T.F. transceiver so I can see if my model will say
saver is equal to T.F. train sabor.
OK now it's time to actually run the session so we're going to run a session that trains in the batches
created by our next batch function.
And it's also going to add in that last evaluation just like we did during the lecture.
Going to add in a quick line here for my GPS options just in case.
So say T.F. GPU options and you don't need to do this if you're not using the actual GPU version of
Tancer flow.
So I need to save per process.
GP You memory underscore fraction and will use 90 percent.
My GP is memory.
OK so that I'm going to passen that config.
So let me just go ahead and copy and paste it.
Then again you don't need to do this.
So there we go GP units ready to go.
And now for the code.
So I'm going to say a session run and it's and then I'll do the following.
I'll say for iteration in a range and then I'm going to say some train iterations
XT batch y batch and then I'm going to call my next batch function on my scale data.
So remember I have my trained skilled data and then my batch size that I defined earlier it's going
to pass that in as well as the number of times steps I passed in earlier.
So those are the concepts I find all the way up here.
So scrolling back down now how are batches going to run our train variable.
And we need our feed dictionary.
So that's going to be x x batch y y batch that I'll say if my iteration Model 100 is equal to zero then
I mean squared air is equal to last evil and we'll have a feed dictionary here where X isn't going to
equal to or passen X batch and Y person white batch The other thing we could do isn't passing just on
our test data.
But right now just keep it the same way we had in the lecture that are going to say iteration is all
the same as we did in the lecture.
I mean square error comma.
MSE OK then that's going to save this and pass the Senate's code along just so I don't overwrite anything.
I would recommend you do the same.
So we'll run that and hopefully be in the training.
OK.
So this is going to then train for 4000 times.
That's something to hop for on time until this is done training.
All right so my model has now finished running and it's gone to a pretty low MSCE.
And as a quick note I previously made a little typo here on Savir so I had a rerun that to rerun the
entire session during the training.
But now there's trying for 4000 steps.
It's time to predict the future.
So we're going to show the test set.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Remember a test set just looks like this.
So a test set is the month that time stamp column and then the milk production.
And we want to actually add in our generated data.
So we're going to scroll down here.
So we want to attempt to predict those 12 months of data.
So we're going to create generative session.
So let's go ahead and do that we'll see with T.F. session as s.c.s I'm going to restore the model I
just created.
So let's copy and paste that string.
So it's stored as time series model code along.
So don't come back down here and place that in so we're going to restore that model and then I'm going
to set a training seemed to be equal to list and it's going to be my scaled training data.
Except it's not going to include the last 12 months.
So I'm going to see it with the entire training set.
So remember in the lectures we seeded it first of zeros and then a little bit of a sinusoidal wave.
Now I'm going to see it an entire training set and see what it says for the test set that last 12 months
of data.
So I'll say for iteration in range 12 because I want 12 months I'll say my next batch is equal to an
umpire rating of my train speed.
And we're going to go from number of time steps remember this just 12.
So from 12 from the very end all the way to the end.
And then I need to reshape this to be one by number of times that's by.
And then we're going to have our white widespread and that's going to be session run then we're going
to go outputs and we'll create a feed dictionary where we have X and then that X batch and then finally
we're going to append to our training seed y predicted values.
So we need to index actually grab them up.
So let's go in and run this.
And now we should have a train seat.
So we're going to show a result of the prediction.
So if I train speed you should get some predictions that look more or less like this.
So let's see how he did.
All right.
The next step is to grab the portion of the results that are actually that generated values.
So if we take a look at train speed that's going to be everything past 12.
So here are my first 12.
I want to grab these results right here and then apply inverse transform because remember right now
these are not the correct units they are still scaled to units.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We'll see the result is equal to scaler and then I'm going to call inverse transform we'll say NPR-A
train speed from 12 all the way onwards and then I need to reshape this to be 12 1 and then I want to
create a new column on the test called generated.
So let's go ahead and make that happen also.
Test set
generated it's going to be able to results.
So going to run that you make it a warning here.
Feel free to ignore it.
It's just basically telling you that you may be setting a copy then we're going to view the test set
data.
So let's go in and see that test set.
And now it should look something like this.
So you can see here we are definitely overestimating.
So we'll have to explore that when we actually plot this out.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We'll say test set the plots and let's see how far off we're.
All right.
So the good news is we're definitely approaching that behavior but unfortunately we're overestimating
the milk production.
To what actually happened.
So what we can do is try to maybe use a different neuron type and see if we can have more information
there.
So let's go in and go back and try to fix that.
So I'm going to scroll back up here to where we actually chose the recurrent neural network type.
All right so what I'm going to try doing is changing the cell type to a gated recurrent unit and then
I'm going to expand the number of iterations but then because of that I'll give it a slower learning
rate.
So let's go ahead and try that out.
And I'm going to hop forward in time and see what the results are.
All right.
So looks like that resulted in a much closer fitting to the actual test data.
A few things to keep in mind is that our original model is still only being trained to predict the time
series one step ahead.
And it's kind of a lot to ask it to generate 12 full steps ahead which is why you'll never end up getting
perfect results.
Given the way we're trained the model.
So somebody could end up doing in the future is trying to if the original model train it with an error
of not just one step ahead but a full 12 steps ahead.
Now in issue with this particular training set is that it's a little too small and it's going to let
me your options as far as the amount of data you have if you're going to end up testing and generating
a full 12 steps ahead.
But if you do take that approach you should see even better results.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.