Hello everyone this lecture is going to serve as a quick note on the word to VAK lectures.
So there's going to be an optional series of lectures describing how you could implement the words of
ECK model which is a model that those embeddings in a vector space for individual words with tensor
flow.
Now if you actually want to practically implement word to VEC I would personally not recommend you use
tensor flow.
In fact lots of people have already done a lot of work to create nice API libraries that quickly and
easily create word to Veck models doing what we do in the series of lectures that you're about to see.
Basically it does all the hard work over again and you're gonna end up reinventing the wheel.
So if you actually want to do a practical implementation of sorts of EQ on your own datasets I highly
recommend you check out the gensym library instead.
If you're further interested in words HVAC and I'll mention it again later on during the lectures.
So keep in mind that this series of lectures is basically going to be a full manual implementation of
using tenderfoots create the words of model.
But if you actually want to do it in real life I would recommend that you avoid tensor flow and use
gensym instead.
In fact let's hop over to the gensym Web site so I can give you just a quick tour of it.
We don't cover this course because it's technically not related to sensor flow but I do want you to
be aware of it as a practical solution for applying or its effect to your own problems.
OK so here I am at the gensym Web site.
If you just google search Python plus gensym you'll end up finding it.
And basically this is topic modeling and natural language processing but it uses a really nice simple
to use API so you can click here on tutorials and it basically has full tutorials and everything you
need to do.
If you want to go from strings to vectors you can click on this here and it basically shows you how
you can end up representing strings as vectors.
Otherwise known as word to VEC so shows you how to do it and you'll notice here that the code is really
quite short.
So it's a lot simpler to use than the full implementation will see with tensor flow later on in this
course.
So I recommend if you want to use words of Eq.
Check out gensym.
It also has a lot more additional functionality and methods you can call once you've already trained
your model.
If you need instructions on how to install it you click here on install and it basically tells you you
can just use Pipp install or an easy install.
Or you can just download it directly.
And then there's also support.
There's API so you have full references here.
So again I really recommend if you're going to dive deep into Word.
Or even just natural language processing in general.
You definitely give gensym a try.
OK so that's my little plug here.
Again for practical implementation of word to use this library don't use tensor flow.
But since this is a curse on tensor flow and words of x is a pretty famous example of using deep learning
will go ahead and show you how it's done in the next series of lectures.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.