Welcome everyone to this lecture where we're going to be discussing warts HVAC which is a really awesome
algorithm or model that ends up embedding words into a vector of space.
So we understand how to work with time series data.
So we're going to take a look at another common series data source which is just words.
So we can think of words in a sentence as a sequence.
So for example a sentence can be thought of as a sequence like.
Hi how are you now in classic natural language processing.
Words are typically replaced by numbers and it indicates some sort of frequency relationship to their
documents.
And in doing this approach we end up losing information about the relationship between the words themselves
so we can think of natural language processing as having two approaches either a counter based approach
or a predictive based approach.
So basically count based methods compute the statistics of how often some words co-occur with its neighbor
words in a large teks corpus and then they end up mapping these counts autistics down to a small dense
vector for each word essentially replacing the words with numbers.
Now predictive models directly try to predict the word from its neighbors in terms of learned small
dense embedding of vectors.
And these are then considered the parameters of the model.
So where its effect is going to take a predictive based approach where neighboring words are predicted
based on the vector space.
Instead of doing a classical count based approach where we essentially lose that sort of information
so we can explore on your own that works.
Most Famous use cases for this predictive based approach for natural language processing which is the
word to VEC model created by Thomas Micallef.
And again the goal of words of model is to learn the word embeddings by modeling each word as a vector
in some dimensional space and later on we'll see that we actually have the capability to define how
large of a dimensional space we want.
So when we actually code this out we're going to find each word as a vector in a hundred and fifty them
emotional space.
So the question arises What is the actual motivation behind using word embeddings instead of just this
approach that we discussed earlier.
Well if we think about the representation of data across various data sources such as audio images or
text we think about audio and images.
These happened to be really rich high dimensional data sets that are also very dense in their information
so you can have things like an audio spectrogram or image pixels.
And these are really dense data sets.
However when you take a approach like a count based approach to text data you end up getting a very
sparse data set.
So for tasks like object or speech recognition we actually already know that all the information required
to successfully perform the task is encoded in the data.
And we actually know this because humans themselves can perform tasks from the raw data.
You can read a sentence and understand the meaning behind it.
However natural language processing systems that traditionally treat words as discrete symbols will
end up not being able to understand this information.
So what I mean by that is a word such as cat is going to be represented as some number like the word
5:37 and a word as such as dog is going to be represented as some other number like ID 6:59 or something
of that nature.
So you end up getting these arbitrary encodings that don't actually provide any useful information to
the system regarding the relationships that may exist between those individual words or symbols.
So you don't get to realize that dogs and cats are similar because they're both animals they're both
popular as pets they both have four legs etc..
You lose that information about the relationship between these words.
Instead you just get information about the relationship of the frequency of these words showing up in
a document so word to Veck trying to solve this problem by creating a vector based model that represents
or in other words embeds the words into a continuous vector space with the words represented as vectors
we can then actually do really cool things like perform vector mathematics on words which is kind of
a crazy idea when you really think about it.
So what that actually means is because each of these words is a vector you can do things like check
how similar two vectors are to each other using something like cosigned similarity which means you can
check how close and how similar two words are to each other.
And then what's really cool is you can actually add and subtract vectors together.
Meaning that once you actually embed these words as vectors you could technically add and subtract words
to get different results.
So at the start of training what happens is each embedding is random but through back propagation in
the model we end up adjusting the value of each word vector in the given number of dimensions.
So you slowly begin to adjust these vectors for these words.
And more than mentions does mean more training time.
But it also means more information per word.
So what ends up happening is each dimension sometimes represents some sort of idea so similar words
will end up being closer together as they're vectors are slowly brought closer together.
And what's even more impressive as I mentioned the model is going to end up producing accessories that
represent concepts or ideas so they may be mentioned that represents gender or another dimension for
verbs singular vs plural etc..
So what does this actually result in.
Well you can end up plotting out the vectors and performing mathematics on them.
So maybe you'll end up realizing that you can have two words such as man and King and realized that
along a particular of them mention they have their gender counterparts such as woman and queen.
So a lot of times there's a famous example where someone says a king Minus Man plus woman and the vector
that's output is queen.
So you can see that the model is actually learning the relationship and even the meaning behind some
of these words.
And then there's other dimensions such as understanding a verb tense so walking to walked or swimming
to swam and then you end up getting a relationships between just even geographical location.
So the model and the understanding that Madrid is related to Spain Rome is related to Italy etc. just
based off the neighboring words which kind of makes sense because as you read some large corpus attacks
you're more likely to find Berlin very close.
The word Germany and you're more likely to find the word Tokyo very close to the word Japan.
So those vectors end up having a relationship.
Now it's actually discuss how words HVAC actually creates these word embeddings and how it learns these
from raw text.
So words of Veck actually comes in two flavors if you will and that is the continuous bag of words model
and the skip Graham model and algorithmically speaking the models are really similar except in the way
that they end up predicting target words.
So let's actually first take a look at this bottom continuous bag of words approach.
So the bag of words approach basically takes in a source context.
Words such as the dog choose the and then attempts to find its prediction target which is just a single
word.
So that target word maybe something like bone.
So you feed in the dog chews the.
And it ends up trying to find the best target fit as just an individual word.
And in that case it could be something like bone the skip gram model that one on the top does the exact
inverse to it predicts source contex words from the target words.
So you end up feeding it bone and it tries to predict the context around it such as the dog chews the
SO for the most part.
This turns out to be useful for larger data sets and the continuous bag of words approach tends to be
better for smaller data sets and that's usually because statistically speaking the bag of words is going
to smooth over a lot of the distributional information and it does that by treating an entire context
as one observation.
So again bag of words tends to be a little better for smaller data sets.
OK so let's go ahead and basically talk about how it actually trains the model and it does this by something
called Noise contrastive training.
So the way this works if we think about the bag of words approach is that given the dog choose the blank
we're looking for the word that's going to be the real target word.
So we'll call that W T.
And we know the real target word is bone.
And then we also have a bunch of noise words throw our document such as book car house on guitar.
So we're looking for the word that's most likely to fit there as the target so for me to visualize this
it would look something like this.
So again we're to Vic doesn't actually need a full probabilistic model.
Instead what we end up doing is we use a binary classification objective such as a logistic regression
to discriminate the real target words.
That is WFC from imaginary noise words we'll call those K in the same context.
So this is basically a simple visualization where we have our projection layer.
The cat sits on the blank.
So Matt in this case so that's the target word.
And we're going to have some sort of noise classifier.
So it's a binary classification where we compare that target word versus the rest of these noise words
and then we pass that in through some hidden layers and eventually we get some sort of embeddings.
So our training process is going to be noise contrastive training.
We're basically contrasting the noise versus the actual target word.
So the target word is predicted by maximizing this equation right here.
And don't worry too much about memorizing every little detail here.
Instead try to understand the basic idea so let's look at that first term of the equation.
So that first term is the binary logistic regression probability under the model of seeing the word
w or W of T in the context H for some dataset capital D and it's cockily in terms of the learn them
betting vectors theta.
So in practice we approximate the expectation by drawing a contrast of words from the noise distribution.
So here we're only drawing K words.
We're not drawing the entire corpus text data.
Instead we're just drawing a certain amount of words for the noise distribution.
So this works really well for us because computationally it's really efficient because now we're just
computing the last function.
And it scales only to the number of noise words that we select.
That is that case number not all the words in the vocabulary which would be let's say capital V or something
of that nature.
So that makes it a lot faster to train because we're only drawing keywords as are noise words instead
of drawing and comparing to the entire vocabulary.
So that's what makes effect computationally efficient for the task it's actually doing.
Now again the larger the amount of keywords you end up drawing the longer your training time is going
to take.
But that should then make it more accurate to predict the target word versus a wide variety of noise
words.
However you'll see you can get really reasonable results for smaller values of k.
So again the goal is to assign high probability to correct words and low probability to noise words.
Then once you've ran through this model process you'll have vectors for each word.
And what's really cool is you can visualize the relationships through some sort of dimension reduction
and a really popular one especially for Wurtz HVAC is t distributed the classic neighbor imbedding.
So in our practice we're going to have each vector be represented by a hundred and fifty dimensions
and then we're going to use this process to reduce it down to two.
So then we just have these words represented by two missional vectors which means we can then plot them
out because we have two coordinates per word.
So that ends up giving you something that looks like this.
So this is actually the final plot we'll be creating and hopefully we'll end up realizing that points
that are close to each other tend to have some similarity.
All right let's get started in the next lecture.
We'll code out the words havock model.