Welcome everyone to the CO-2 long lecture for the words of ex-model we're going to be using the tensor
for documentation example which has a tutorial implementation of war effect.
It's a really great example for the documentation.
So we'll just be using that directly.
So that means we're going to be referring to the provided notebook often for blocks of code that we're
going to end up copying and pasting to this code along.
So make sure you have that notebook or the documentation example of ready to go.
So as a quick note if we're to VAK is a model that really interests you further and you want to explore
it.
I would actually recommend that you don't use tensor flow as your main source of this but instead check
out the gensym library.
It's linked as a resource for this lecture.
It has a much simpler to use API for word to Veck and additional functionality.
I've used it myself in the past and it's a lot easier to use than tensor flow.
Discourse is an senseful that will be showing you the tensor flow version but definitely check out the
gensym library if you intend to use words.
Further on.
It has a lot more functionality and honestly it's a lot simpler to use.
All right let's get started.
In the Jupiter notebook.
OK here I am of the Jupiter notebook.
The first thing you need to do is our imports.
Many imports that we actually have to do.
So I'm just going to copy and paste them from the notebook.
You can see you're using collection's math our operating system so we can grab the files zip files so
we can unzip them as well as things like pie.
And of course sensor flow.
So we go ahead and run all those imports again just copy and paste that from the notebook and then up
next will actually get the data.
So there's a function that we're going to be creating that will be able to fetch the data for you from
the your l.
It's going to check if it exists or not and if it doesn't exist it will download it for you.
So let's go and just create that.
So we're going to say our data directory is equal to and match this exactly.
Otherwise you'll end up downloading the data all over again.
It's already downloaded for you.
With the zip file so I'll say words effect underscore data words.
And then in case you ever want to download the state of yourself you can use this function to do it.
So I'm going to copy and paste this your L from the notebook just to make sure I don't mess it up.
But it's basically right here.
So we're going to use this text a zip file that comes from this Web site so you can download it directly
in the function we're going to end up copying and pasting here is going to allow you to either download
the data.
If it doesn't exist or just open up the data in case you already have it download it.
So if you come back here to recurrent networks you'll notice that we already have the words effect data
for you.
If you go in there words words zip zip file We're going to be using.
So I'll go ahead and copy and paste the fecche words data function and then basically walk through what
it's doing here.
So when you call this fetch where it's data you end up passing in the URL and the words data directory.
So what ends up doing it's going to make that directory if that does not exist.
The circuitry already exist for us as we just saw under the current US networks folder then it's going
to set a path to the zip file.
So it's going to take that directory and append words that zip to it or join it.
And then if the zip file isn't there it then downloads it.
So this particular line won't work for you if you have some sort of restriction on your internet.
So if you're on a work computer and you get some failure at this line it's probably because you have
a firewall blocking you.
So you'll need to get admin privileges privileges or turn off that firewall.
So again keep that in mind you will need full admin privileges to download this zip file or you can
just go to the Internet and download it manually from this you are.
Then once the zip files there well we end up doing is we just read in that data and then we end up decoding
it and splitting it.
So this returns a list of all the words in the data source so say words is equal to and I mean to call
fecche words data.
Open and close parentheses.
And I'm just using open unclose princes because I will be using the default values of data and data
directory.
So this should not download anything it's just going to fetch the data for me.
Now that data is quite large.
So this may take a little time for you but once we actually run that we'll see the length of the words
is quite large.
So we have about 17 million words here.
So really big.
Let's go out and get a slice of the words just so we can see them say something like get totally random
slice here some 40 words so we can see feelings and the auditory system of a person with autism often
cannot sense fluctuations etc. and you can see here this is what the words look like.
So we're gonna end up doing is say print out kind of a sentence of these words.
Now these sentences aren't exactly directly pulled from a text source.
The zip file is specialized in a way to work a little better for words HVAC which is why it's kind of
a sampling.
So that's why we're using this link here.
So even though these technically are sentences they've been adjusted a little bit so that they work
a little better with words of that.
So we'll say and is equal to just a space years.
Print it all out in one line so we can see here what an example sentence may look like.
So it says feelings and the auditory system of a person with autism often cannot sense the fluctuations
what seems to not to sick people like a high pitched sing song or flat robot like voice is common in
autistic children.
Some autistic children and it continues on.
You notice here that we've actually removed punctuation.
So it kind of feels like a run on us because there are no periods here.
And those are some of the adjustments for words effect so obviously doesn't make sense punctuation since
we want kind of stream of words.
So now we're going to build a word count.
And it's really easy.
The collections library we imported all say from collections import counter.
And as you may have guessed counter we'll just count stuff.
So I want to show you a quick example of what it looks like.
If I make a list of words like one two and two and run that and then I say counter of my list it just
returns back a dictionary with the actual word.
And then how many times it showed up.
So one showed up one time to shoot up two times.
So you can also then request a method called most common and it would return back.
However many most common words you asked so this returns back the number one most common word which
in this case is two.
And if you wanted the two most common words that you pass into and in this case that's all we have.
OK so let's go ahead and create the word data and vocabulary.
So we'll do another function here and this one we can actually code along with.
Let me zoom in one more level here.
We're going to say create the counts and we'll sorry General vocab size is going to be fifty thousand
words.
So even though we have many more words than that in our actual data set some of these are definitely
repeat words so you can see here we have like persons going to be repeated the word was going to be
repeated many times etc..
So we'll have our model just take into account a total of 50000 unique words and we're going to say
that vocab is equal to an empty list here plus counter of words.
And then we're going to say the most common based off cup size.
It's actually change this sort of being vocable will that vocab size sorry for this confusion they're
sort of defining vocabulary size as 50000.
So basically we are saying is Hey grab the most common 50000 words and that's going to be my vocabulary.
So then I'm going to turn that into an umpire.
Which is why I have that kind of list there.
So we'll say vocab is equal to the array.
Then I'll use miscomprehension to say word for word.
Word for word comma underscores a little bit of typing a tuple in packing their vocab.
So what I'm actually doing here with this tuple unpacking.
Remember that what I asked for the most common I get back a list of tuples where the first item in the
tuple is the word itself and the second item is the count.
And I don't really care about the count I just care about the most common words.
So what I'm doing here is using list comprehension for this vocab.
All I'm saying is hey for the word in this tuple unpacking I'm only grabbing the word.
And typically if you're going to throw something away in an underscore or not use it you just use.
Scuse me when you throw something away in a list comprehension or a tuple on packing.
You just use an underscore.
So since I don't really care about this number I'm just going to put it in as an underscore.
So that's common in Python if you're going to not use something just underscore their next.
I'm going to create my dictionary and that's going to be word and I will say code for code.
Word and enumerates vocab.
And this is essentially a dictionary comprehension.
So we'll see the result of that in just a little bit but then I will create my data.
And this is going to be an umpire Ray and we're going to have a list comprehension here.
So lots of comprehensions and Orsen essay gets word zero for word in words.
And then finally we're going to return the data and the vocab.
So let's run this and see what is actually being returned here.
So again a vocab size is 50000.
So I'll say the following data and my vocabulary are equal to create counts.
So I'll run that again this may take a little bit of time.
So I get to hop 4 in time until this is done.
Or it actually just finished for me.
So let's take a look at the shape of data.
So the shape of data.
Notice it's as many words as there were.
And if we take a look at vocabulary and the shape it's 50000.
So what does that actually mean.
Well it means if I were to grab the value add words in that 100 then my data will tell me what number
vocab word it is.
So interpretations is 4189 out of my entire vocabulary so I can see here that the various words in my
data have some sort of index position in my vocabulary.
All right.
So it's going to be useful later on when we generate batches OK the next step is to create a function
that actually generates batches for us.
Now we're going to copy this directly from the documentation so it's a bit complicated but basically
what this is going to end up doing is at the end it's going to return a batch as well as the labels
associated with it.
So we provide a batch size and then number of skips and skip window which we're going to talk about
later on.
They're just going to be some parameters we can set.
And then this whole code is going to generate the batches and you can check out the documentation if
you want some more information about line by line what this is doing.
But for our case we can just think of it as in the batches.
And as I mentioned previously this is one of the reasons why you don't really want to use tensor flow
if you're going to be using or HVAC because gensym kind of takes care of all this.
For you the background.
OK.
So we have a function that's going to be able to generate the batches.
Now we just need to create some constants and then we can start building the placeholders for our recession.
So let's create some constants here will say constants.
So we create a size of the actual batch schoolFeed in batches of let's say 128 at a time.
And then we also need to say in imbedding size.
So the imbedding size is basically going to be how many dimensions will the embedding vector have.
The more they mention the more information but the more they mentions also the longer it takes a train.
So a common size if you check out literature on this is 150.
Again you can always expand this and you can always decrease it to fit.
Training is taking too long.
Then we're going to define a skip window and the skip window is going to be how many words to consider.
To the left and to the right.
So the bigger this value again the longer the training.
So we'll keep it as small as possible just one and then we have the number of skips.
So this is how many times to reuse an input to generate a label and we'll go ahead and keep that value
low as well say 2.
OK.
So then we need to pick a random validation set to sample nearest neighbors.
So what we actually mean by that.
Well I'll say valid size is equal to 16.
So this is a random set of words to evaluate similarity on and then we're only going to pick samples
from the head of that distribution.
So we'll say a valid window is equal to 100 and we'll say valid examples is equal to the random choice
valid window.
Valot size or say replace is equal to false.
OK.
So here what we're actually doing is we're limiting the validation samples.
The words that have a low numeric ID which by the way we constructed these are also the most frequent
words.
So then let's go ahead and get a number of negative examples sample so see num sample is equal to 64
and then we're going to choose our learning rate for our model.
So a learning rate is equal to zero points or one.
If you start using smaller learning rates it's really him to take a super long time and then we I believe
we already defined our vocabulary size.
But let's do it again just in case.
We'll see.
OK.
Size is equal to 50000.
OK so now let's go ahead and create our tensor flow placeholders and constants.
So the first thing to do is reset my default graph because I mean using the same notebook here and then
we want our input data.
So we're going to create our training inputs to be T.F. placeholder and they're actually just integers
this time and the shape here is just going to be none because the find by the Bache pups shape equals
There we go next.
It's going to be the training labels so we'll have that to T.F. da
placeholder.
That's also going to be a 32 bit integer and the shape here that's going to be the size by one.
And then finally we have valid data set and we're going to synthetical to T.F..
Constance valid examples for the data type is again just T.F. integer 32.
All right so now we're going to create some variables and then we'll create our last function.
So remember last function is the end loss.
So let's create those variables will create our initial embeddings.
So remember we need to have each of these words have some sort of random embedding first.
So it's going to be T.F. random and we'll pick this up from a uniform distribution and we need to be
by vocabulary size.
So for each of the words and then by the embedding size so 150 It's make sure imbedding size.
There we go.
And then the other dimensions to be are those things are going to pass in are from negative 1 to 1.
So we're going to randomly start off the vector embeddings.
So we have 50000 words by a hundred fifty definitions for each word.
And we just randomly choose values from negative 1 to 1.
So that's going to initialize them and then we're going to say that the embeddings themselves are equal
to T.F. variable.
And it's in bits
and then we're going to say embed is equal to T.F. and end and there's actually an embedding lookup
function that's built into tensor flow.
So this just looks up ideas in a list of imbedding tensors.
Essentially what we created earlier.
So we'll do the following.
We'll say the embeddings we just made and then passing in the train that puts all right.
So all we have left is to create the last function the optimizer and then run our session
OK.
All we have left is to create our last function our optimizer run the session and then visualize our
results.
So let's go ahead and do that in the very next lecture.
I'll see you there.