Welcome back everyone to where we left off last time the next thing we want to do is get our and see
e loss ready to go.
So we're going to create two variables are NC weights and see biases so we'll see errancy weights or
ATF variable and then we're going to just start these off from a truncated normal distribution so they
truncated normal and then we'll passen for the dimensions vocabulary size by the number of dimensions
for the embeddings which in our case we define as 150.
And then we'll go ahead and say the standard deviation is equal to 1.0 divided by the square root of
the imbedding size.
We'll go ahead and put that in.
So those are weights and then we'll go ahead and create our bias term So says.
And this is also going to be a variable and for these We'll just initiate them as heroes.
And the dimensions are going to be by the vocabulary size.
All right.
Now we want to compute the average and the last for the Bache so following along with the documentation
example we'll say T.F. that reduce mean.
And then we get called T.F. and then dot and C E loss.
And this is a function that basically just nicely takes in a lot of the parameters we are just describing.
So a lot of variables that we just made we're going to pass them in.
So if you do shift tabs you can see the various orders that ask for weights the biases the labels the
inputs etc..
So say ency weights and see bias's will pass and the training labels the embed parameter we created
earlier than the number sampled variable.
And then finally the vocabulary size OK once we have that lost it's time for the optimizer will say
optimizer is equal to T.F. train and we use an atom optimizer.
You can also use gradient descent optimizer and we'll make the learning rate a little faster just because
it takes a really long time to train.
That may affect our results so just keep that in mind.
Usually you have to run this for something like 100000 steps or more to get anything meaningful depending
on how large your data is.
Then we'll say optimizer that minimize and say loss.
Up next we want to be able to compute the cosigners similarity between many bad examples in all the
embeddings.
So I the copy and paste here directly from the documentation example the code that allows us to do that
and it basically ends up creating some sort of normalized embeddings and then it uses this T.F. and
imbedding lookup functionality in order to continue on with that.
So we'll run that.
And then finally we're going to set data index as 0.
So the reason I'm doing that is because this is a global variable that's called by the batch generators
generators we come up here it asks for the data index.
So we'll go ahead and set that as a zero.
And then finally we'll say in it is equal to T.F. global variables initialiser and then we'll go ahead
and begin our session.
Now I'm going to run the Soneji pew.
So I need to put in this cheaper options code so I don't get any errors or basically So my GP isn't
crashed by taking up 100 percent of the GPU and then we'll start our first session.
So let me type out this line from the notes.
First off we're going to run that in it and we'll set our average loss to start off as 0 and then we'll
do the following.
We'll say first that an range number of steps.
Scroll down here.
We'll have the batch inputs and batch labels equal to that generate batch function or we pass in the
batch size we declared earlier the number skips and then the skip window then we'll go hand the finer
feed dictionary so we can easily call it later on.
So this is just going to be for the placeholders of train inputs we pass in those batch inputs that
we just made.
And then for the trained labels for that placeholder we're going to pass in the labels
OK.
Finally we need to say session run and we're going to grab the trainer and the loss and then we're going
to give it the feed dictionary that we just created and then this is going to return a tuple So let's
go ahead and pack it.
I won't bother with the first item I want the second item which is the last value first I was going
to be the results of that trainer but I'm really just looking for the loss here because I'm going to
use that to add it on to the average loss.
So say average loss that's I say plus equal to loss value.
And then finally let's have some sort of evaluation metric continuing.
So say if step maade 1000 so we'll say every 1000 steps that's equal to zero.
What I'm going to do is say if step is greater than zero.
Then take the average loss and set it equal to average loss divided by a thousand.
Because what I'm going to do is take the average loss as an estimate over the last 1000 batches.
So then I will say once that's done print
average loss at Stapp they'll pass and the stop recurrently at they say is and then we'll finally say
average loss OK once that's done we'll just reset the average loss again to be zero.
And then we can say final embeddings is equal to the normalized beddings evaluated.
All right so now we just want to decide what number of steps we want to run this for.
So there is a higher rate that's within your current year that work where I ran this for 200 thousand
steps and we'll go ahead and just make this run for let's say 5000 steps so our results are probably
gonna be pretty meaningless.
But that way we don't wait here forever.
So we'll say number of steps is equal to 5000 so will run this mixture would have the errors average
loss and a little bit we should see 1000.
Make sure it's running
all right there it is.
So what I'm going to do now is Skip forward in time until it's then training for 5000 steps.
Again this is definitely going to take a while especially if you're on a CPQ.
So that's why we have that an umpire Ray that's already been trained for you so you can load it up if
you want to.
OK.
And then hop forward in time OK it's done running for those 5000 steps.
We're going to do now is try to visualize it by using the distributed stochastic neighbor embedding
which basically allows us to transform these final embeddings.
Take a look at the final embeddings the shape of them.
It's going to be 50000 by 150.
So it's 50000 vocabulary words defined by vectors in 150 dimensions.
So we want to reduce that to just be on to them and shows that we can plot it so we can do this using
the Essenes all say S-K learn manifold import T S and E.
So the way I like to just intuitively explain this.
It's a pretty complicated algorithm but basically what it does is you can imagine that if you had a
bunch of points on a crumpled up piece of paper you could then unfold that piece of paper to make it
flat and to that missional see transform it to this three the wad into this to the flat plane.
So this is essentially what this algorithm is trying to do except it's going to do that for 150 that
mentions all wadded up and then bring it back down to two.
So this by itself does take a while.
So just keep that in mind.
So we're going to create an instance of this and there's various parameters you can use various parameters
you can play around of here.
Perplexity is one of them a mixture.
That's correct.
So perplexity will set that equal to 30.
The number of components we want at the end is just going to be equal to two.
So we just want to them mentions and we're going to initialize with PCa principal component analysis
and say the number of iterations you can go through are 5000 so run that and then we only are going
to plot let's say just 500 of our words.
So if say plot only 500 words and then we're saying that the low dimension embeddings are going to be
equal to that model and we're going to say fit.
Transform the final embeddings and we're only going to go for those first five hundred.
So say plot only comma colon so only grabbed the first five hundred words.
OK so now that's fitting transforming basically reducing those 150 them mentions into two that mentions
through the relatively complicated process of T distributed sarcastic neighbor imbedding and this line
should take you a while.
Took me just a couple of seconds here.
Maybe 15 10 seconds.
So now we're going to do is plot this out and see how it goes.
So the other thing we need to do is grab the labels so I can plot those as well.
Well see labels is vocabulary I for I in arr. 500.
So plot only.
So now if I take a look at my load then mention imbedding it looks something like this.
So if I take a look at the shape of it it's going to be 500 words with two dimensional vectors representation.
So let's go ahead and plot that up in order to do that.
I'm going to copy and paste a plot function.
So first off is say import that plot lived the pipe plot as PLDT and we'll say map plot lib in line
and then I copy this plot functionality directly from the notes.
Basically just makes really nice scatterplot with the labels.
So it kind of the hard part was annotating it for the labels.
So now let's go ahead and plot and see what it looks like.
We'll save the plot with labels and load them.
So instead of embed
run that and add a little bit we should see the plot.
OK so now we can see the two that missional representation of the words.
So we only ran for 5000 steps so we may not see a whole lot of similarity between words that are together
but hopefully you can end up loading the actual NUMP tirade that has the higher training.
So what you can do is load that up through the following manner.
You'll scroll down here and say final embeddings equal to the DOT load and I call the train embeddings
200 case steps so you can go ahead and load that.
And now that we overwrote final embeddings with this one that's already been pre-trained for you of
200 K is just an empire.
So if you take a look at final embeddings now it's the same thing as before.
Fifty thousand words by a hundred fifty dimensions except this one was just trained for 200 steps or
200000 steps excuse me.
So then you can explore the process here and repeat the labeling and the plotting.
So you would have to come back up here and rerun these lines that basically fit transform and fit transform
is baffling and take a while.
So you run this again load them and they mention embeds shape that again and again you don't really
need to redefine the plot or run that again and then you can plot with labels.
All right.
So to hop forward in time to this label's done.
All right so just finished for me.
And now you should see the embeddings for the 200 K steps trained.
And again remember that we actually are only showing if you look at this the 500 words.
So out of those 500 words we may not be able to choose things that are close enough together.
So what you can do is expand this number of 500.
However the larger you choose that means the longer it's going to take for this any to fit transform.
So if you want you could choose a really large value like 5000 less than 10 percent of our vocabulary.
But running this line the fit transform isn't going to take a much longer time.